<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Portrait of De Sade</title>
        <author>
            <persName>
                <forename>Walter</forename>
                <surname>Lennig</surname>
            </persName>
        </author>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Encoded in TEI All by</resp>
            <name xml:id="MD">Miki Derdun</name>
        </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <editionStmt>
        <edition n="0.5">Non-public release for research purposes. Basic annotation with minimal enrichment.</edition>
    </editionStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <p />
    </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
        <p>From the Internet Archive edition.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
<encodingDesc>
<projectDesc>
    <p>This version of The Childlike Life of the Black Tarantula uses TEI All to encode Acker's texts and sources. The primary research aim at this stage is to understand Acker's textual reuse habits and interrogate their uses in the formation of narrative identities on the level of varying personas.</p>
</projectDesc>
</encodingDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
    <body>
        <div type="text">
            <div type="chapter" n="1">
                <head type="chapter">THE PANDEMONIUM OF SEX</head>
                <p>THE MARQUIS DE SADE was a great writer. Perhaps more than with any other writer it is necessary to be acquainted with de Sade’s life and fate before turning to his work, which was determined by the circumstances of his life, and cannot be properly under stood apart from them. De Sade’s involvement—and he was “in volved” in the fullest sense—was the simplest and most direct form of commitment, for it concerned himself exclusively. Be cause his era considered that a man of his kind could not be tolerated within human society, he fought unswervingly for the right to be what he was. In all his works he tried to prove that even an extremely immoral person, as all the world held him to be, could under a different code become the representative of a moral system based not on any hypothetical laws, but on the true nature of man. He protested at being declared guilty, on the ground that his abnormal instinctive life was a whim of nature, immutable and obviously incurable. With this he touched on a legal dilemma far in advance of his time which remains unre solved today: whether the law can be based on a morality which is itself not firmly founded and still less can be proved. This is a problem first and foremost of sexual morality. Since, according to Freud, the unconscious is the source of most irregularities, it is no longer scientifically possible to speak of a “conscious” vice, though the law still vehemently refuses to acknowledge this fact. De Sade should not be connected directly with Freud; they have little to do with one another, and are the products of totally different epochs. It would never have occurred to de Sade that sexual deviations could be cured. On the contrary, he based his theories on the unchangeable predisposition of human nature, and accepted the conventional categories of good and evil only pro vided that man’'s natural impulses and desires were first defined as evil, because they were so undeniably opposed to what was designated as good under the existing moral code. To that extent his self-acknowledged evil was only a personal one; yet at the same time it was a demand for life, freedom, and justice, because it could be seen as the human expression of a capricious nature wholly devoted to self-realization. To a large extent, de Sade derived this form of justification on the basis of a natural law from the materialistic natural phi losophy of La Mettrie, a now forgotten philosopher of the Enlight enment, who had had to flee from his persecutors to Prussia, where he received an adequate stipend from Frederick II until his death there in 1751. Rousseau, too, exerted considerable influence on de Sade's thought. Rousseau had combined his rustic enthusiasm for “natural man” with a condemnation of both civilization and history, which in his view had not made man better or more noble, but had only corrupted him. This concept of “natural man” accorded with de Sade’s wholly sinister passions; he might be said to have undertaken to develop Rousseau’s idea to its logical conclusion in other words to transform it into its most concrete imaginative expression, which could be appropriately achieved only within Jean-Jacques Rousseau. the form of his romans noirs. Natural man possesses "natural rights, the foremost of which is the right to freedom. Rousseau himself later fully recognized the insoluble antithesis between this natural freedom and its inevitable renunciation in practice through subordination to the general will. But de Sade had many oppor tunities to witness the bloody excesses of the popular will, so at all events one cannot deny the experience on which his theory rests when he interprets these excesses as true orgies of unbridled naturalness.” In contrast to Rousseau, de Sade does not depend on the criterion of feeling, but rather on philosophical reason. He deals most radically with the sentimentalization of Nature, the great illusion of his own and the subsequent centuries. Above all he feels that natural man is in fact not free, for he obeys his im pulses without reservation and allows his actions to be determined only by the distinction between pleasure and the absence of pleasure. This, in brief, was how de Sade chose to interpret the popular maxim "back to Nature”; he created his own infernal world with a distorted moral code: there, despite bestiality, events progressed with total logicality. Following the unchanging law of “cruel mother Nature, his characters do not suppress a single desire or appetite, no matter how destructive. De Sade would obviously not have used the word "suppress,” but it tends to force itself on every modern reader. Although de Sade does not hesitate to call the characters of his novels evil and criminal, and even expressly prides himself on having made his heroes particularly hateful, he seldom forgets an allusion to the fact that social inequality cor responds at least to some extent to the natural inequality of all human beings: power is the prerequisite for the freedom of evil —the desire for cruelty also requires the defenseless weak. The Marquis' resentment is so total that it elevates his argu ments from being mere damnations of nature and the social structure of his time. He could not avoid a constant inner con tradiction, but he suffered ultimately as much from himself as from his era. His mania was to a certain extent also a merit; by treating virtue and vice dialectically, he demonstrated the artificial nature of any comparison between the sexual and the moral norm. The sexual fiends dressed in rococo costume in Justine, Juliette, or The One Hundred Twenty Days of Sodom, could almost be called laborers in the field of vice; even their most cruel and evil raging in the name of “cruel mother Nature” does not for a second eclipse their lively and logically trained intellectuality. They are untiringly ingenious in exhausting every conceivable possibility of sexual perversion. In the field of pure classification, de Sade left his successors in sexual science nothing more to do other than to evolve the antiseptic terminology which today makes it pos sible to talk about most sexual matters as if it were all merely a question of appendicitis. Even as a philosopher de Sade remained above all "un homme de lettres”—an expression which encompasses more than a mere writer and really refers to a specifically French mode of existence. Like almost all men of letters of the eighteenth century, he is a philosopher: destructive, but at the same time full of faith in the future. He brings the tidings of the flesh as an emancipation from an anti-natural code of morality, above all in the combination of lust and cruelty to which his name has been attached ever since. He himself formulated this superbly: “There is nothing greater or more beautiful than sex, and no salvation without it. Since then, only Sigmund Freud, more than a century later, has dared to describe the sexual drive as the chief and central moti vating force of all human phenomena. But he did this within a system of impartial scientific methods and in academic termi nology, and in this neutralized form it could become a topic for universal discussion, even if in very simplified terms. (What antagonism it aroused then, and to a certain extent even today, is well known.) But there is another decisive difference between the two men: Freud was a specialist with an irreproachable private life, whereas de Sade was no scholar and—though largely due to slander and mass calumny—was considered during his lifetime to be the most dissolute libertine of his era. For this reason it was easy to classify all his works as pornography or even worse. But it remains de Sade’s claim to fame, as we are now pre pared to acknowledge, that he was the first person to describe the wild, demoniac aspects of sex. He exposed depths which were thought forgotten and indicated associations which no one before him had dared to admit. The utter shamelessness with which he pursued this work can equally be interpreted as the love for truth; he spared nothing, neither diminishing nor concealing in the slightest. Man under the influence of his natural instincts is a wild, cruel beast. Between desire and its sacrifice there rules a truly demoniac dialectic; pain, suffering and humiliation para doxically provide the satisfaction of a natural force. The distinction drawn later between sadism and masochism was quite super fluous: de Sade already knew that the phenomena were basically the same, but with opposite symptoms. He considered himself, in fact, to be at times both sadist and masochist, and could justifiably state that such a bipolarity in any one being reduces practically everything to lust and the desire for fulfillment: the crime as well as the punishment have to be suffered—and even the execu tioner then becomes the ultimate benefactor of lust. All this, and much more, must be taken into consideration if de Sade is to be judged according to his true merits. Although various translations of some of his works have appeared in recent years, this does not necessarily mean that there exists any sincere, mature interest in the Marquis’ writings. When we speak today of the total sexualization of man and life, we obviously refer to Freud and not to de Sade—and not without justification, for the popularization of Freud has had immeasurably greater results than the scholarly interest in de Sade. The infernal Marquis had something other in mind than the current world-wide tendency to view sex as something perfectly normal and harmless; a process of "naturalization, which incidentally is not much more than the continuation of an old hypocrisy by opposite means. One of the Marquis' most distinguishing characteristics is his total lack of hypocrisy. He neither embellishes nor defames, but presents sex quite plainly as a demoniac force. This was not only his answer to Rousseau but, owing to the radical fashion in which he put forward his ideas, almost a refutation as well. Though de Sade himself never explicitly stated the conclusion to be drawn, it forces itself irresistibly on the reader: all culture and civilization is won in the unflinching battle against Nature; all civilizing institutions serve man's security and are the achievements of re nunciation and collective self-control. Modern anthropology is now to some degree able to appreciate man’s immensely laborious path from the primitive state up to civilization. As Arnold Gehlen puts it: “The essence of civilization is the protection of man against his own nature. The shock which still reverberates from de Sade’s works today is in no way due to any historical associations. It is mythic in nature. It aims at the animal in us and at the extraordinary role played by the intellect when it becomes subordinated to this ani mal. Even if it is madness, there is not only method in it, but the beauty of a maelstrom. But the Marquis was by no means mad; he was just reasonable in a terrifying fashion. Hatred was his muse, yet paradoxically his ancestry was still haunted by a distant glim mer of that unique light of love forever attached to the name of Petrarch. For it was one of the Marquis’ ancestors, Count Hugues de Sade, who in the early fourteenth century had married the now immortal Laura who was the inspiration of Petrarch’s sonnets of pained longing and desire. To some this may seem shocking. At any event it is fantastic that two such total opposites should be connected by fate in this way. De Sade apparently saw no contradiction in the fact that he of all people should have such an ancestress as Laura; in fact he cherished her memory all his life and even reported from the prison of Vincennes that she had appeared to him in a dream and comforted him. This sounds almost sentimental coming from a man who would gladly have extinguished the sun to prevent it from shining on humanity. As might be expected, love plays a scant and not exactly glorious role in de Sade’s works. He refers to it occasionally as an "accursed practice for combining the physical and the psychical”—but such phrases were in common usage in the rococo period, so the odd comments of de Sade's characters on the subject of love were in no way more extreme than those of Sebastien Chamfort. His characters demonstrate or parody—the Rousseauian “return to Nature.” There seems to be no doubt in their minds that love, and even Petrarch's highly spiritualized type of emotion, is not derived from man's true nature. In this respect at least we can agree with him. As is common knowledge, the nineteenth century—the era of the bourgeoisie—produced more romantic novels than ever be fore, not including the poetry and plays which dealt with permissible or at least tolerated love. Free or forbidden love was inevitably destined to sink, with varying degrees of tragedy, under the pressure of bourgeois morality. Now that the long agony of bourgeois Europe is a thing of the past, there is scarcely a trace Reputed portrait of Laura de Novis. Rome, Palazzo dei Conservatori. of this tragedy which does not have to disguise itself carefully to avoid being dismissed as “Kitsch.” With startling consistency this sense of the tragic has disappeared to the extent that frankness about sexual problems has increased. The great emotions, danger ous passion, and whole pathos of love all vanished with the antagonisms which had formerly stifled them. The civilized sensi bility which had superseded the naked instinct in the course of a long historical awakening of conscience was replaced in a rapid and relentless dismantling process by the re-establishment of sex, whereby in scientific hygienic terms every secret was exposed and every mystery explained. The so-called mass society which re sulted can now only smile at the complex labyrinth of prohibitions imposed by the Victorian epoch. Even the outrage of D. H. Lawrence, if taken into account at all any more, is difficult for us to comprehend. It thus seems permissible to conjecture that Donatien Alphonse François de Sade, who presented his monsters and debauchees in the true costume of his hated epoch, would be somewhat embarrassed and disconcerted were he able to see the state of the world one hundred and fifty years after his death. He was, admittedly, separated by over four centuries from his ancestress Laura, but this seems to us a short gap compared to the almost inconceivable, astronomical distance between the fourteenth century and our own age. At this point it should be mentioned that in France, Italy, Russia, and England, interest in de Sade over the past hundred and fifty years has been restricted to a very small group of artists, writers, and critics, who detected in him the dark genius and discoverer of a mythic world of deadly desires which men refuse to acknowledge at their peril—the hubris of modern civilization. For a century and a half de Sade’s major works remained ta booed and prohibited. They continued, nevertheless, to be printed, though mostly inaccurately and with many bad illustrations. The sequence and quality of these mainly anonymous editions are known today to only a handful of French collectors and specialists. It has been possible to produce reliable new editions only when the original manuscript has miraculously been preserved. Some of his important works will still be withheld from open sale in the foreseeable future, and will be obtainable only by subscription within privileged circles, or in special collector’s edi tions. De Sade attracted interest in Germany only after the two World Wars; perhaps he alone can supply German intellectuals with the information they seek concerning collective sadism as practiced in the torture chambers and slave camps of the SS State. For “Citizen de Sade” had recognized this phenomenon during the Reign of Terror when he saw the curious crowds eagerly pressed round the guillotine. It is a terrifying fact that in each of us there lurks a modicum of de Sade, a morsel of his tendency, an uncontrollable possibility —something archetypal, the mere thought of which is unbearable. But the unbearableness of a thought is no argument against its truth. In any case, there are some truths that are convincing only when decked in the garb of provocation. And has European civili zation ever seen a more powerful provocateur than the Marquis de Sade? </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="2">
                <head type="chapter">THE MARQUIS' YOUTH</head>
                <p>WHEN because of his works an author is persecuted as a monster for a hundred and fifty years, one would expect a summary ac count of his life to resemble the biography of a monster. But the life of the Marquis de Sade is less monstrous than one would imagine; it would be fairer to say that he was pursued throughout his life by a monstrous fate. He was born in Paris on June 2, 1740, and was baptized the following morning in Saint-Sulpice as Donatien Alphonse François, although he was to have been christened Louis Aldonse Donatien—the two servants who were the sole witnesses had forgotten the correct names on the way from the Hôtel de Condé to the church. The de Sade family tree can be traced back to the early four teenth century, though the family is certainly several centuries older still. It was definitely established in 1323 when, in Avignon, the Marquis’ ancestor, Hugues de Sade, married Laura de Novis, immortalized as Petrarch’s Laura through his imperishable love sonnets. This famous ancestress endowed the Provençal-Italian family with a certain sense of dedication in the course of the fol lowing centuries; they also enjoyed the continued favor of the French kings and thus rose to fame and wealth. The Marquis father became a marshal, ambassador to four European Courts, and the governor of four provinces. By his marriage to Marie Eléonore de Maillé de Carman, he was related to the powerful families of Condé-Bourbon and Richelieu. It was in the vast town palace of the Condés that Donatien Alphonse François spent his early childhood. Connected through my mother with the greatest power of the kingdom; through my father sharing in the exclusive world of Languedoc. Born in Paris in the lap of luxury and wealth, as soon as I could think I assumed that nature and fate had united to shower me with their gifts. I was foolishly assured of this, and believed it, and this conceit made me arrogant, despotic, and hot tempered. I thought that everything should submit to me, that everyone should obey the whims which I alone was allowed to have and satisfy. An example from my childhood should illustrate these dubious ideas which were so thoughtlessly nurtured in me. "Since I was born and lived in the palace of the famous prince to whose family my mother had the honor of belonging, and who was roughly the same age as myself, I was hurriedly brought into close contact with him, so that through this childhood friendship I should at any time in the future be able to seek protection from him. My vanity, which failed to see this ulterior motive, became enraged one day during a game; partly because he wanted to take something away from me, but still more because he felt justified in doing so by virtue of his superiority. I retaliated against his obstinacy with blows. Nothing could dissuade me and we had to be separated by force. (Aline et Valcour) At the age of four, the Marquis, who had scarcely seen his father at all, travelled to the family seat at Avignon. He was greeted ceremoniously by the notables of the feudal estate, and then proceeded, accompanied and protected by his retainer, to the Languedoc to visit his grandmother Louise Aldonse, whose hus band had died the previous year. As de Sade himself wrote later: I was sent to my grandmother in the Languedoc, whose blind tenderness nurtured every weakness in me. The boy could not stay in Paris any longer, for his mother had to go to Cologne for an indefinite period at the request of her husband, on account of the important talks being held there be tween the Elector and the French government. So he was left in the care of his grandmother who, together with four or five aunts, completely spoiled the pretty child and allowed him to get away with every prank. A year later, however, they all agreed that the boy did need a tutor. The man chosen to undertake the job was another relation, Abbé Jacques de Sade, who was also a witty and frivolous writer with a number of affairs to his credit. The Abbé was a friend of Voltaire, with whom he conducted a regular correspondence. He held several rich livings which en abled him to lead a carefree and extremely worldly existence as well as pursue a career as a man of letters. He was widely re spected for his famous book about Petrarch and was altogether the epitome of the “Grandseigneur Abbé” of the ancien régime. When his small nephew came to him, the Abbé was forty years old, the pride of Provence and its nobility, highly cultured, and a sparkling conversationalist. There can be no doubt that the young Marquis learned an extraordinary amount from him be tween the ages of five and ten years, and that his mind was formed correspondingly. Biographers have subsequently main tained that he was already corrupted by the frivolous, libertine personality of his uncle. But past centuries must be judged by their own intellectual standards, not by the norms of the modern age. Morals are just as susceptible to transition and change as fashions in dress. At ten years, de Sade became a boarder at the Collège Louis-le- Grand in Paris, which at that time was run by the Jesuits. Here he found another personal tutor in Abbé Amblet. This college for the sons of the aristocracy then had three thousand pupils. The school day began at six in the morning and lasted until nine o’clock at night, with just one hour free at midday. Even at this time de Sade saw little of his father, and from 1760 onwards he practically never saw his mother, who had retired to a Carmelite convent. On his father’s orders, he had to leave the college when barely fourteen years old, and enter the cavalry school of the Royal Guard at Versailles, where only the sons of the high nobility were accepted. His father presumably desired a military career for his only son—the two other children had died in infancy because the family fortunes had declined sharply owing to mis management. After eighteen months’ training, de Sade became a sub-lieutenant, and two years later he was appointed standard bearer of the Count of Provence’s regiment and started for Ger- many. The Seven Years' War had broken out and Louis XV, urged on by Madame de Pompadour, had formed an alliance with Maria Theresa against the Marquis of Brandenburg, as he mockingly called the Prussian king. Louis was subsequently to regret this; the royal army was in a desperate condition, and was half annihilated by the Prussians at Rossbach shortly after the be ginning of the campaign. But they struggled on in the following years, moving from one quarters to the next, plundering and imposing arbitrary taxes to raise at least some wages for the dis contented troops. The worst atrocities were perpetrated by sec tions of the French army in various regions of Hanover. In 1759 de Sade was serving as a captain in the Burgundian cavalry regi ment, and was given six months leave. His wild life in Paris shocked his father, who also came to hear scandalous stories of his life in the army. At the various garrisons of the regiment, the young officer had thoughtlessly shared the debauched life of his fellow officers, trying wherever possible to outdo their excesses. He had also lost vast sums of money at cards. De Sade himself wrote in a letter of this period: "How could I imagine that the girls I saw could really give me any pleasure? Unfortunately, one can never properly enjoy the happiness that one has purchased ... My self-assurance suffers from the thought that I am perhaps only loved because I pay less badly than someone else. His suspicious father had commissioned the young de Castéra to send him reports of his son's behavior during the campaign. In one such report he wrote: "At each stop he leaves a trail of distress, and himself parts with regret. His youthful heart, or to be more correct his body, is so terribly easily enflamed—woe to the German girls! I shall do everything I can to prevent him from any further follies. He has given me his word of honor not to gamble away more than one louis d’or a day. De Sade himself made little reference to his military service during the war, as can be seen from the following quotation from his novel Aline et Valcour: War broke out. My family, intent on my army career, would not allow me to finish my education. While others were still at school, I was already with the regiment. The campaign began, and I may say that I proved my worth. My inborn wildness of character and the passionate soul with which nature had endowed me united to form that unconstrained virtue known as courage which—without doubt unjustly—together with bravery and dar- ing is held supreme by soldiers. When my regiment was annihilated in the penultimate confrontation of the war, we were ordered back to the barracks. The Marquis, in later life astonishingly well-read and knowl edgeable, must have acquired his learning to a large extent on his own. That he was a courageous officer can be seen from his rapid advancement to the rank of captain. From the moral point of view, this period of his life had an extraordinarily destructive effect. When he finally returned to his father in Paris after the declaration of peace in 1763, he plunged into a life of un bridled pleasure-seeking. He was constantly involved in gambling debts and duels, was a regular patron of the theater boudoirs. and did not even consider it necessary to pay his customary re spects to the King. Wherever possible he avoided his misanthropic, reproachful father, and regardlessly incurred even more debts on the family finances. The old marshal nevertheless continued to regard him as the family heir; he could not disown him, although he gradually began to detest him. He finally realized that mar riage would be the only hope of salvation for his dissolute son; but it was no easy matter to find a suitable wife, for the head strong young Marquis had already acquired a notoriously bad reputation among the upper aristocracy. The fact that he never appeared at the Court at Versailles, which at that time was all decisive, almost certainly contributed to his ill-repute. A further particularly difficult complication was that at precisely this mo ment the future bridegroom fell passionately in love with a certain Mademoiselle de Lauris. She belonged to one of the oldest families of the Provençal nobility, and her extremely influential father had naturally long since destined her for another match. It is important to note that the enigmatic Marquis fell in love passionately with a woman—without a trace of sadism—at least four times in the course of his life; just one of the contradictions of this dark phenomenon. At all events he then wanted to marry no one but Laure de Lauris. He left Paris so as to be near his beloved in Avignon. He even became secretly engaged to her Versailles. when the pretty, coquettish girl, transported by so much passion, became his lover—though this was then strictly forbidden before marriage. What he did not know was that he was neither the first nor the last of Laure’s lovers. Despite her insatiable sensuality she could think quite cooly and rationally in financial matters, so she called in her father at the opportune moment and her lover was forced to declare that he would renounce any thought of marriage with her. The wretched Marquis then had to learn that she had already given her heart to another, and had departed. He sent a desperate letter after her, saying among other things: No doubt you judged the feelings of my heart according to your own. A shallow motive, dictated by falsehood, you thankless cheat! You fear to bind yourself to one who worships you. The fetters of an everlasting chain were burdensome to you only, and your heart, which understands only fickleness and wantonness, was not sensitive enough to recognize their charms. My love does not satisfy you ... you monster, born to make me unhappy. May the unfaithfulness of the traitor who has taken my place in your heart one day make love as hateful to you as your unfaith fulness has done for me! ... But what am I saying? My dear love, divine love! You who alone fill my heart, the sole delight of my life, my love, where is this despair leading tol Forgive the words of an unhappy man, beside himself with misery, for whom Who can death is the only aim since he lost what he loved.. bind me to life, whose only joy you were. I lose you, I lose my life; I die, I die the most cruel death. ... I am so confused, dear love, I have lost my senses, the tears flow, I see as if through a mist... I desire, think, and long only for you!' No one would suspect that this passionate love letter from a twenty-two year old originated from the man whose sexual inferno was to become such a monstrous provocation to the whole of civilized Europe. However, he never saw the fickle Laure again. His father had in the meantime arranged a suitable match for his son in Paris. There could be no going back, and the young Marquis knew that he had to obey. In view of the by then all but ruinous state of the family fortunes, it was essential that this should be a rich marriage—for even the most illustrious aristo cratic title was treated by society with deference and distinction only if it had enough money behind it. His father's choice fell on Renée Pélagie de Montreuil, the twenty-two-year-old daughter of the president of the Paris Taxation Court and his extremely reso lute and intelligent wife. They belonged to the so-called noblesse de la robe—or minor nobility—which began to play a role in France at the end of the seventeenth century. It was an aristocracy of officials and judges who did not have the backing of a prestigious and ancient family tree. The prospect of a son-in-law from the old high nobility, who was also related through the Condés with the royal family, was an extraordinary stroke of luck for the Montreuils. For they were not only extremely wealthy but also held a position of considerable influence at the Versailles Court—on account of their money, of course, by which means many favorites at Versailles had fallen into debt with them. And money was the criterion which finally made the young Marquis give in. How else was he to continue to lead the frivolous, dissi pated life to which he had become accustomed since leaving the army? His father even had difficulty in borrowing the ten thou sand francs necessary to clothe and equip his degenerate son for the wedding. But some weeks before her daughter’s marriage, Madame de Montreuil had come to hear of various not exactly flattering facts about her future son-in-law; of not only the embarrassing affair with Laure de Lauris in Avignon, but his dissipated life in Paris. The Marquis' father had great difficulty in saving the project, pleading against his own convictions for his son, about whom he himself no longer had any illusions. The matter was settled when Louis XV ceremoniously condescended to put his seal to the marriage contract in the presence of the whole Court. Apart from the 300,000 livres which would come to the couple on the death of the Montreuils and several other relations, they were promised an annual income from both sets of parents to the sum of about 30,000 livres, as well as a generous amount to cover furnishings and servants’ wages. The old marshal also conferred on his son the governorship of his four provinces and four estates and manors, though these were severely in debt. The wedding took place with great splendor on May 17, 1763, in the church of Saint-Roch. The young Marquis knew very well that he had married far beneath his rank; yet he did so voluntarily, as can be seen from a letter from his father to his uncle before the marriage: "It is impossible to influence him in the slightest in the most important matters. For he now wanted only to enjoy life like the other young cavaliers of the high aristocracy, and that was only possible with a great deal of money at his disposal. Soon after the honey moon he set up a “petite maison,” as the noblemen’s retreats were known, and several other similar haunts followed. The Marquis obviously had no idea that he was already being shadowed, on the orders of the Court Chancery, by Inspector Marais who sent precise accounts of his private life to the Court at Versailles. The well-known procuresses of the town supplied every wish of clients who paid well, and sent de Sade as many young girls as he wanted. As well as these he had actresses, dancers, and stage extras. Only once after this did he consent, on the insistence of both his father and his mother-in-law, to appear at Court. Otherwise he avoided society and had practically no acquaintances among his own class, for which reason he was subsequently unable to find any protectors or willing friends to give him the help he so often needed. This introversion and dislike of social contact also aroused the indignation of Court society, which looked on his behavior as a disregard for and lack of a sense of social station. Another danger should also be mentioned at this point. In order to conceal the violently debauched private life of Louis XV and the Court as a whole, and to appease public opinion, it was the practice to adopt a highly moralistic and indignant attitude to scandals concerning unpopular outsiders. The Minister, de Saint Florentin, thus welcomed reports of the Marquis de Sade’s un usual excesses, as a result of which he was arrested for the first time on October 29, 1763, barely six months after his marriage, and committed to the dismal prison at Vincennes. Two weeks later, his mother-in-law secured a warrant for his discharge from the King, on the condition—no doubt stipulated by Madame de Montreuil—that he should proceed immediately to Chateau Echauffour, the Montreuil family estate in Normandy, which he was not allowed to leave without special permission. The young Marquise, already three months pregnant, was also living there, and shortly afterwards had a miscarriage. His wife suffered from the all too scant use the Marquis made of their marriage, as well as from his long absences. For Renée loved her husband, despite the fact that he found her "too cold and pious” for his liking. She remained utterly devoted to him for almost twenty years, defending his interests even in the most humiliating of circum stances. In contrast to her sister Anne, whom de Sade would probably much rather have married, Renée was unattractive and had rather a plump figure. She was nevertheless to bear her husband three children. In January 1764, Madame de Montreuil wrote to the Abbé de Sade in Provence: I confess that I lack the courage to inform you of the events of which you must by now know It is entirely up to your nephew to make amends for the past by his irreproachable con duct in the future. Since he returned to us we have been satisfied with him. That is not the cause of my complaint. Although I have the impression that it has all had some effect on him, only experience will prove it to me. Monsieur de Montreuil and I have treated him like our own son, and done whatever we thought necessary to avoid a scandal. As for my daughter, you can easily imagine how she has suffered; but she has shown herself to be a truly virtuous wife, though it is not for me to praise this. May those judge her to whom she has the honor to be attached. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="3">
                <head type="chapter">DISAPPOINTMENTS IN LOVE</head>
                <p>OF NECESSITY, the Marquis spent the winter in strict monogamy at Chateau Echauffour, allowing himself to be pampered, and reading a great deal. He was considered to be truly cured, and was finally permitted to return to Paris again in April 1764. Al most nothing was heard of any debauchery for quite a time after this (and Inspector Marais' agents missed nothing in the Marquis private life). Instead, he indulged in two passionate love affairs. The first was with Colette, a very popular actress of eighteen with the Comédie-Italienne, who was already the mistress of two other rich aristocrats. De Sade escorted her home after a perform ance: “Since I first saw you I have had no rest. One word from you would give me peace. The sincerity of my feelings forbids me to conceal them. Here is my name and address. I await your reply tomorrow. Adieu, Mademoiselle. His feelings were in no way diminished when he had to pay her twenty-five louis d’or (one louis d’or = twenty gold francs) a month maintenance. At the time all actresses were kept in this way, for wages were low and they had to supply their own ward- robes. The affair did not escape his by now extremely cautious mother-in-law. She had Colette shadowed and was soon able to inform him of the extensive love life conducted by the actress with other men, and with such precise details and irrefutable facts that the impassioned Marquis was almost driven mad before he finally decided to break off the affair to avoid public derision. Mademoiselle was naturally furious when he demanded the re turn of his letters and informed her that he was suspending his payments to her. By then he was almost cured of his passion and wrote back to her: You would blush for what you have done to me if you pos sessed a shred of virtue or even humanity. It pains me to have to speak thus to you, for I am unhappy enough that I cannot wholly tear you from my heart. But I hope that it won’t be long before you are. Then may heaven protect me from another such terrible passion. Forgive me for the truths I write so openly. ... So for the last time, adieu. I go, and it gives me as much pleasure now to draw away from you as it once did to approach you. In the meantime he fell in love with a respectable young girl at a ball, and wrote to tell her how much he regretted not having met her earlier, for he would have married her immediately: “The days which in a marriage of convenience only sow thorns would with you have blossomed with the roses of spring. I would have gathered the days which I now detest. In the arms of love they would have flown by too fast for me. The longest life would not have been enough to pay homage to my love. I should have knelt in constant adoration at the feet of my wife, and the chains of duty, forever interlaced with love, would have offered to my ecstatic heart nothing but happiness. Vain illusion! Too blissful dream! In 1765 de Sade was seized by a new passion for the twenty-four year-old beauty, Beauvoisin. In her previous career she had already risen from servant girl to coquette, and was at the time being kept by three men, who satisfied her need for luxury. But she also needed a lover to satisfy her passionate emotions. The Marquis languished in her snares for over two years, and even when he did part from her, it was always to return shortly after. But he could not finance this costly courtesan alone, and in order to have her to himself at least for a time they made several very expensive journeys together, which plunged him even more hopelessly into debt. He was all but enslaved by her; his always well-informed mother-in-law complained that Beauvoisin was his “prison, and he himself later referred to her as “the siren. She no doubt possessed not only erotic qualities, but also unusually great charm and that talent for sophisticated chit-chat which was so esteemed and cultivated at the time. It would otherwise be totally incom prehensible that the Marquis should take his mistress with him to the family château at La Coste near Avignon, where she lived with him for two months, at times even being passed off as his wife. To impress her he organized glittering banquets and theatrical performances, and for this purpose the theater in the spacious château was refurnished in a most costly fashion. The nobility were invited from far and wide, and were sumptuously regaled. Actors were hired, and de Sade himself personally supervised the production, occasionally even taking a hand at acting, for which he demonstrated an unusual talent. A permanent guest at this prolonged love feast was his frivolous uncle, Abbé de Sade. One can easily imagine how completely in his element the host’s former tutor would have been at the festivities at La Coste. He showed such tolerance towards Mademoiselle Beauvoisin that he himself later became anxious and reported it to his sister, the Abbess of Saint-Benoit in Cavaillon. She in turn wrote a highly reproachful letter to her nephew, who answered as follows: Your accusations, my dear aunt, are quite simply not justified. Indeed, I have never heard such hard words from the mouth of a religious. I do not permit, nor suffer, nor authorize that any one shall assume that the woman with whom I am now living is my wife ... When one of your sisters, though married, was living here quite openly with a lover, did you then consider La Coste an accursed place? I am acting no worse than she ... And as for the gentleman who passed on the facts of which you now accuse me, he himself, for all that he is a priest, is always sur rounded by a number of whores. Forgive me for using the same expression as you, but his château is a harem, or rather a brothel. Forgive me my weaknesses, they apparently run in the family. If I have any regrets, it is that I should have the misfortune to be born into such a family... His by now almost despairing mother-in-law wrote to the Abbé de Sade: As long as he continues to behave like a madman, I prefer that he remains in Provence. There at least he does not get in my way; his presence here would upset me, for he would drag his creditors with him, and look for other mistresses. So, for his sake, I prefer him to remain in Provence. The Marquis went to Paris and Normandy only once or twice, when his creditors became so pressing that Madame de Montreuil grudgingly had to come to his rescue with large sums of money. During his stay in Paris in the winter of 1766, his father died. As was common among most French aristocratic families at the time, the relationship between father and son had remained cool and ceremonial throughout. In de Sade’s case this was intensified by the contempt which the old man had for many years held towards his son, whose incorrigible character he considered beyond salvation. A violent quarrel finally put an end to his love affair with La Beauvoisin; de Sade was totally disillusioned and forlorn: You are unmasked, you monster! Your evil is beyond all imagination ... You need only have said you wanted to leave me, I would not have kept you by force. ... Go, I will detest you all my life, you and others like you. The most intense disgust is the only feeling that my heart could now have for you. Adieu, devote yourself to your new conquest and destroy him by the same I will never see you again in my black arts you used on me life. That is what you want, isn't it, you monster of ingratitude and falsity. Be happy if you can, despite the excess of misery into which you have plunged me. You and your kind see it as your right to take advantage of the credulity and good faith of honest men. The following nine years saw the series of scandals which earned the Marquis his reputation as the most profligate libertine of the kingdom. There were, of course, others far worse than he, but they were more adept at avoiding scandals. Whether de Sade knew how closely he was being watched we do not know, but at any event one cannot help wondering at his careless, indifferent attitude to public opinion. It could almost be called ignorance were it not for the many factors which lead us to assume that he quite consciously and obstinately allowed himself the complete freedom to indulge his unbounded ego and fulfill his perverse desires—or sadistic instincts, as they are now, albeit inadequately, called. From this point on de Sade pursued his sexual fulfillment in a strikingly methodical fashion, closely studying his own reac tions to the most perverse and repulsive forms of debauchery. In this vein he staged certain experiments which he was later to use as the basic material for his novels. It was a true pande monium of savage sexuality. Gilles de Rais and the Count of Charolais were real sexual monsters; de Sade himself was not. Most of what he did to this day belongs to the repertoire of perversions constantly practiced in brothels. His subjects were always common prostitutes, or at any rate women who were well paid for their services. That this should have caused such an uproar in an era of such extreme immorality was partly because the nobility—already universally hated—had to find a scapegoat for their own bad reputation. De Sade thus happened to find himself, so to speak, in the cross-fire between two powerful rival groups. On the other hand, he should not be excused; nor should his debauchery be either underplayed or overestimated. Above all we should never forget that the Marquis, because he had taken such pleasure in breaking every taboo in the course of his ex orbitantly licentious life, was later able to depict so masterfully in his books the terrible fiction of a world of ruthless pleasure freed from all sexual taboos. To this end the infernal Marquis carried out his practical studies and experiments, though at the time he was probably not fully aware of their consequences. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="4">
                <head type="chapter">THE ARCUEIL SCANDAL</head>
                <p>ON THE morning of Easter Sunday, April 3, 1768, de Sade accosted an unemployed seamstress, Rose Keller, whom he had seen begging in the city; he brought her to his house at Arcueil. At four o’clock that afternoon, Rose Keller appeared in the nearby Rue de la Fontaine, her clothing torn and dishevelled, and informed a village woman who happened to be passing that she had just fled for her life from the Marquis’ house, where he had brutally beaten her half a dozen times. When she had begged him not to kill her before she had been to confession, de Sade had scornfully replied that he would hear her confession himself if she thought it important. The Chief Constable of Arcueil informed the local magistrate, who ordered Rose Keller to be examined by a surgeon. Proceed- ings against de Sade were then sent to the dreaded Chamber de la Tournelle, the Paris Criminal Court. His wife and mother-in-law immediately sent a lawyer to Rose Keller to persuade her to abandon her charges against the Marquis. They thought that a small sum would be enough to satisfy a beggar woman, but Keller suddenly proved to be extraordinarily stubborn and busi ess-minded, demanding for her silence 2400 livres, an almost 38 incredible amount for someone in her circumstances. Unfortu nately, though Rose Keller did agree to drop her charges, the public prosecutor had already brought the action before the Criminal Court, so the trial still had to take place. The King had also been informed of the new scandal, and immediately ordered de Sade to be arrested and brought to the prison fortress at Pierre-Encise. Just a month later, however, he put his seal to the petition for de Sade’s reprieve, and the trial was dropped, though the Marquis had to remain in prison until November 1768, when he was allowed to return to La Coste. In 1937, the records of the trial were discovered in some for gotten state archive by Maurice Heine, the French de Sade re searcher. From these documents it is clear that there was much exaggeration in the public presentation of the Rose Keller case in 1768. An expert, Dr. André Javelier, has noted that "such scenes take place daily in the torture chambers of modern brothels, but none of the victims involved would ever think of complain ing. This verdict unfortunately came precisely a hundred and twenty-nine years too late for the Marquis. The Keller affair was the first major scandal in de Sade's life. Inspector Marais had often reported that the Marquis whipped prostitutes in one of his five small retreats; he had in fact urgently pressed the well-known procuresses not to supply de Sade with girls, but to no avail, for the Marquis paid generously. This time, however, he seemed to have made a bad choice, for Rose Keller was just an occasional beggar woman and was not acquainted with the professional customs of prostitution. It was also unfortunate for de Sade that he had chosen Easter Sunday for this orgy, and that he was reputed to have said that he would hear his victim’s confession himself. But the scandal was chiefly blown up by certain parties who wanted to use the case to their own advantage. Agitation against the Marquis was now all the more dangerous for him, because he was also branded as a notorious atheist. This may have aroused the particular anger of Louis XV who, in spite of being a thor oughly criminal ruler, was devoutly religious and had done con siderably more in defense of the Church than he had for the stabilization of the country’s finances. Both Parliament and the courts, which had to a large extent been reinstated in their old functions after the death of Louis XIV, had for a long time been waging a secret war against the King. Since he was unassailable, they were trying to discredit the aristocracy. They developed an incredible alacrity in anticipating any possible support for their cause and gladly supplied the press with biased information. In the ensuing period the Marquis turned again to his passion for the theater. He often invited actors from Lyons to his château at La Coste, where the theater had been renovated and refurbished in 1765. De Sade’s first play was staged there on January 20, - 1//2. Even though it would be a long time before the Comédie- Française produced one of his plays, he considered himself to be a great dramatist as early as 1772, and took immense pains to win recognition as such among his contemporaries. That a rela tively large number of his plays has survived (although only one of them was printed after the Revolution) is due simply to the fact that these works, designed for public presentation before a conventional audience, are totally inoffensive attacks on con temporary morality. De Sade no doubt had other aims in mind with his prose works, for which success and public acclaim were not essential criteria. For a time the Marquis' theatrical ambitions definitely outweighed his aspirations as a novelist. His feverish work on his novels in the Bastille served above all as a means of self-preservation at a time when everything had conspired to his destruction. De Sade had been an ardent theater-goer ever since leaving the army, and it would be underestimating the case to say that this was due solely to an interest in pretty actresses. He was very knowledgeable in the whole working of the theater, attended re- hearsals, mastered the difficult skills of voice projection, and justifiably considered himself capable of directing his own plays as well. His greatest successes as a stage director were to come, however, thirty years later; they belonged to the last pages of a bizarre destiny. The period between November 1768 and June 1772 occupies little space in most biographies of de Sade. There was no further scandal to report, and no new complaints were lodged with the King against the Marquis, who was already held in permanent disrepute. In spite of his experiences after the Keller affair, he had not shown his face at Versailles nor even sought trustworthy sympathizers. For a member of the upper aristocracy in de Sade’s position, it was absolutely essential to establish good relations with the Court. But he despised “that unhealthy marshy village called Versailles where the kings, who are here to be paid homage to in the capital, apparently recover from the presence of their demanding subjects. On the wings of boredom, a miserable flock is borne there daily by ambition, greed, revenge, and arrogance to bring sacrifice to the idol. Even the élite of the French aristocracy, who could be playing an important role on their family estates, betake themselves willingly to this place, humiliate themselves in the anterooms, pay court most shamefully to the footmen, or timidly beg for a meal which tastes far worse than their own food at home; fortune emerges for a moment from the cloud of oblivion, only to drop them again later. Although he actually wrote this ten years later, it probably reflects de Sade’s persistent aversion to the conditions at Versailles, combined with the arrogant self-awareness of the Provençal no bility. He still relied on the conviction that in an emergency no humiliation, apart from the passing anger of the King, could befall the heir of such an illustrious family. A number of important events nevertheless occurred in these relatively quiet years. His wife gave birth to two more children (their first son having been born in 1767); their second son, Donatien Claude Armand, was born on June 27, 1769, and a daughter, Madeleine Laure, on April 17, 1771. De Sade was in constant financial difficulties, and his mother-in-law was no longer prepared to give him any assistance. In June 1771 he even had to spend a number of days in the debtors' prison, from which he saved himself only by selling his colonel's commission for ten thousand livres. For what purpose he undertook a four-week journey through the Netherlands there is no reliable evidence. For most of the time he lived at La Coste, spending largs sums on decorations, holding monthly theatrical performances and balls for the neighboring aristocracy. A frequent guest on such occasions was once again his jovial Abbé uncle, who nevertheless shrewdly omitted to make any mention of them in his letters to Madame de Montreuil. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="5">
                <head type="chapter">ANNE-PROSPERE, THE GREAT LOVE AFFAIR</head>
                <p>THE MOST important event of these years was certainly the arrival at La Coste of his young sister-in-law, Anne-Prospère, who was both extraordinarily well educated and full of vitality. Earlier claims that de Sade had fallen in love with this beautiful girl before his marriage to her far less attractive and rather inelegant sister Renée have since been disproved. He in fact met her for the first time at his wedding, when she was still a pupil at a convent school. So it was only when she came to La Coste that he saw her as a young woman in full bloom, and was immediately drawn irresistibly by her beauty. Madame de Montreuil had probably given her a rather unflattering impression of the notorious Marquis, but this only made her adventurous daughter all the more curious. And now she saw this disreputable character for herself: a fair-haired man of medium height, dressed in an elegant silk suit, with an inexhaustible talent for captivation and amorous conversation. After leaving the convent school, Anne-Prospère had had private tutors at home, as was usual in well-to-do families, and had almost certainly come across tutors similar to those of Rousseau’s motherly friend, Madame de Warens, whose educa tion is described in the famous Confessions. Anne-Prospère at any event knew considerably more than most girls about the moral hypocrisy of high society; she was well versed in the intellectual approach of the Encyclopédie, and was a devotee of the fashionable philosophy which put the demands of Nature above those of religious morality. Life at La Coste was precisely to her taste with its banquets, dinners, balls, and theatrical performances. She was pursued not only by the ardently insistent Marquis, but also by the infamous, frivolous Abbé, his eloquent roué uncle. These incidents could not have escaped the notice of Madame de Sade, but owing to her complete subservience to her husband, she did not dare to remonstrate even on this occasion. Besides, her hot-tempered, un reliable husband did fulfill his marital duties, which Madame rewarded with almost canine devotion. It obviously never occurred to Renée that the Marquis’ sinful behavior would ever reach the ears of her powerful, tyrannical mother. For this was no common amorous adventure on the part of the insatiable Marquis, but a matter of incest, a crime penalized with the most severe punish ment. So Renée did everything in her power to set her suspicious mother's mind at rest about the goings on at La Coste, reporting how good the clear, sunny climate in Provence was for her sister's health. The Marquis already had several long love affairs behind him, but his love for Anne-Prospère was to be the greatest passion of his whole life; he surrendered to it with an abandon which could almost be called infatuation, but it nevertheless speaks in the favor of a man whom the world called an immoral monster that he was also capable of passionate love to the point of self-destruction. Since all documents and papers covering the period of this love affair were subsequently destroyed, it is exceedingly difficult to trace the sequence of events with even a moderate degree of certainty. One fact is definite: that the affair began in the autumn of 1771. Anne-Prospère had originally planned a short visit, but eventually remained at La Coste for over a year. In view of her mother’s evident suspicion, this can only be explained by Madame de Montreuil’s friendship with the Abbé de Sade, under whose protection she imagined her daughter to be. But the famous biographer of Laura was anything but a guardian of virtue, despite his ecclesiastical office; for this old Don Juan had also fallen in love with Anne-Prospère at first sight, and outbid the Marquis in showering her with gifts. Anne-Prospère did not hold out long against the Marquis' pas sionate advances, for she herself had immediately fallen in love with this extremely handsome, witty man of thirty-one. She is also known to have been remarkably free from moral scruples of any kind. The spacious château contained many discreet corners, and Renée purposely avoided any jealous scenes. Anne-Prospère’s love was naturally not of the same intensity as de Sade’s; there can be no doubt that he loved her far more than she did him—but such distinctions usually become apparent only later. That winter and spring at La Coste—now a ruin, but at the time one of the most beautiful châteaux in the south of France—was for both lovers a time of happiness and endless sensual pleasure. All during this period there is no word of a single scandal, or even of any other woman. The Marquis left the château only on outings with his wife and sister-in-law, to show them the beauty of the surrounding countryside or to make purchases in Avignon. Then in June 1772 he suddenly had to go to Marseilles to collect the large sums of money which he needed urgently after the extravagant months at La Coste. He was accompanied only by his valet, Latour, and promised to return home as soon as possible. But this time he relapsed, and on June 27, in Marseilles, he again seized the opportunity of carrying out sexual experiments of such a perverse nature that he soon found himself in the midst of a new scandal far greater than the Rose Keller affair. The Marquis ordered his valet to supply him with four young prostitutes—who were to be generously remunerated—for a morning's pleasure. The cat-o-nine-tails (a whip with thongs of parchment studded with short nails) again played an important part, the difference being that this time the Marquis also wanted to be whipped himself. Since the girls failed to show the desired enthusiams, de Sade offered them a crystal bowl of Spanish fly pastilles—at that time widely popular in France for purposes of sexual stimulation—in the hopes of persuading them to agree to anal intercourse. On payment of enough gold pieces, the girls apparently consented, and permitted both the Marquis and his lackcy, who was present the whole time, to serve themselves as they pleased; they were also compelled to witness homosexual ts between the two men. But even such exertions were not enough to satisfy the Marquis. The same evening he repeated the whole procedure with another girl, the twenty-five-year-old prosti tute Marguerite Coste, who, at de Sade’s continued insistence, consumed an unusually large number of the Spanish fly pastilles from the crystal bowl. Of the five prostitutes, only two had taken too many of the sexual stimulants: Marguerite Coste and the eighteen-year-old Marianne Laverne, one of the participants in the first orgy. They both became extremely ill. The doctor was called, and they were persuaded to report to the public prosecutor of Marseilles, who interrogated first of all Marguerite and Marianne, and then the other three participants in the orgies. They all swore complete disgust at what they had seen and experienced, and that they had, of course, firmly refused to comply with the Marquis’ sodomistic desires—understandably, since in those days sodomy was punishable by death in France. So only de Sade and his lackey remained guilty of this crime. They were formally accused of having committed sodomy and of having tried to poison the two girls. The fact that the girls later withdrew their charges, having been appropriately bribed, was not taken into account. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="6">
                <head type="chapter">THE DEATH SENTENCE AT AIX</head>
                <p>THE ORDER of arrest against the accused could not, however, be carried out at La Coste, since both de Sade and Latour had been warned and fled to Italy. On September 3, they were tried in absentia, found guilty and condemned by the Aix Criminal Court to "repent publicly in front of the cathedral, before being taken Place Saint-Louis, where the said Monsieur de Sade shall be be headed on the guillotine and Latour shall be hanged on the gallows, after which both corpses shall be burned and the ashes scattered in the wind.” On September 11, the verdict was declared final, and on the following day, since neither de Sade nor Latour was at hand, effigies of them were made and executed, and the case was officially declared closed. One would not need to be a sympathizer of de Sade to consider this sentence unfair. Even those who find the Marquis personally loathsome will have to admit that this trial, which unlike the usual long drawn-out hearings of cases at the time was rushed through like a witch hunt, was unjustly conducted. Research has proven that, as in the Keller case, the real power behind the ac tion was Chancellor Maupeou. What is particularly monstrous is that Maupeou was initially spurred on by his hatred for de Sade’s parents-in-law—and especially Madame de Montreuil—for which the disreputable Marquis frankly happened to provide a useful public target. As a result of this he was to remain the scapegoat of the frivolous aristocracy. That de Sade acted in a totally thoughtless, irrational manner scarcely needs to be pointed out. He seems to have experienced no moral scruples whatsoever; on the contrary, as in other instances, he acted as if morality simply did not exist, but rather the right to indulge his own desires without reservation. There is a tendency to present de Sade as the ne plus ultra of sexuality, the absolute voluptuary of all time. Since no debauchee is equally attracted to all varieties and forms of sexuality, but limits himself to certain aspects, de Sade must have been the one and only exception the world has known. This seems highly improbable. For who could fail to see the element of research and discovery in all his orgies and scandals? De Sade approached his work like a maniacal re searcher who would like to know of and experience everything, regardless of whether it corresponded to his own inclination or not. For a long time, though, he seems to have had no particular aim in mind beyond sheer curosity. This changed, of course, later, inside the impregnable walls of Vincennes and the Bastille. He was obviously aware that such behavior would inevitably lead to conflict with traditional institutions, in particular the law; but he placed his rights as an individual above everything else on the grounds that they were derived from man's natural state. He later on produced much more comprehensive and logically darinę arguments to justify his ideas. It may seem strange that this vehement apologist of sexuality was often so curiously ignorant of the world and unable to face reality. There seems to be no other reasonable explanation for his astonishing carelessness in his ex periments, which always led to him being discovered and convicted so rapidly. For instance, he quite obviously had not briefed him self on cantharides and the dangers of overdosage. On the other hand, it must be remembered that he still relied on the privileges of his social status, and believed himself to be protected by the King from any dangerous attack—all the more so since his mother was actually related to the royal family. He failed to understand why both Louis XIV and XV had had to supply victims for the ever more critical Zeitgeist. Nevertheless, had de Sade not been a marquis from a family of old standing, he would have certainly experienced the total brutality of the contemporary police system, and possibly met his death much sooner. We may perhaps detect a certain element of caution in the fact that for his worst expedi tions into the realms of forbidden debauchery de Sade as a rule chose prostitutes, who were after all professionally accustomed to satisfying even the most abnormal desires of their customers, provided they were paid accordingly. He only realized far too late that these girls, and the procuresses as well, were totally dependent on the good will of the police, for whom they were consequently one of the most important sources of information. By the summer of 1772, the Marquis was no longer so ignorant of these facts. The moment he heard that the police in Marseilles were searching for him, he immediately packed and left La Coste. On this occasion he was playing for time, and decided to stay abroad until interest in the affair had died down. It was July 3. In the carriage which sped towards the Italian frontier sat the “Comte de Mazan and his young wife, alias the Marquis and Anne-Prospère, who had promised to accompany her beloved brother-in-law to the border so as to be able to re port that he had escaped to safety. But the Marquise waited in vain for her sister’s return, for she remained with de Sade in Italy until that October. De Sade’s mother-in-law, Madame de Montreuil, appears in most books about the Marquis as a malicious woman, filled with hatred, whose sole aim in life was to humiliate and destroy her son-in-law. She was in fact a woman of extraordinary personality, and totally dominated her husband, the former Taxation Court President, who was publicly scorned as a cuckold. Madame never claimed to be more moral than the society of her day; she accepted her son-in-law's constant infidelities quite calmly, but became very angry at his more extreme dissipation. At every major scandal, including the Marseilles affair, she took pains to quash the pro ceedings with the help of lawyers and bribes before they could reach the indictment stage. She did this mainly in the interests of the family honor, though she also intervened frequently on behalf of de Sade himself—and not without success, for Madame de Montreuil had astonishingly good connections at Versailles with all the most important personalities of the kingdom, including the highest dignitaries and ministers, and even the King him self. She was certainly immensely wealthy, and increased her fortune by skillful speculation, but she was also exceptionally eloquent and knew how to present her case convincingly. She was an excellent judge of human nature, and seems even in middle age to have possessed great charm and wit. But the decisive elements in her character were undoubtedly her untiring energy and a will power which few could match. Ever since his marriage to Renée, de Sade had constantly disappointed, annoyed, and shocked his powerful and influential mother-in-law, and must have long since forfeited her good will. But only his irresponsible elopement with her unmarried daughter, Anne-Prospère, finally drove her to deadly enmity. Anything else she would probably have forgiven, but this scandal all but destroyed any hopes of finding a suitable match for the reckless girl, and even if an unusually large dowry did manage to attract a suitor, he would certainly not be from the first ranks of society. This was an irreparable blot on the family reputation, and from the moment she discovered the truth Madame de Montreuil became the Marquis’ sworn enemy—the full implica tions of which he was to experience all too painfully in the future. Of the Marquis' travels through Italy with his sister-in-law, who posed as his wife, practically nothing is known. They probably stayed quite a while in Venice, the pleasure metropolis of the rococo period, since it afforded the greatest possibility of remaining incognito. As long as their money lasted they dis turbed no one; but de Sade, who was never able to economize, was very soon in financial difficulties, so one of the two servants who had travelled with them had to be sent off to La Coste with an urgent letter to the Marquise begging for money. She incurred more and more debts in order to oblige her fugitive husband, for the family’s financial situation was already quite desperate. Whatever steps she took, Renée still suffered greatly from the disgrace of the family name. The gossip and scandal press—not only in Paris, but throughout the country—made de Sade out to be a truly satanic sexual criminal; every child knew the monster's name. Without the effective protection of her power ful mother, poor Renée would have died of despair. From now on, however, Madame de Montreuil intervened only on behalf of Renée and her three children. For these innocents at least she wanted to save her son-in-law’s name in the eyes of the law. The incorrigible culprit himself should be deprived of his future freedom, because he would probably only abuse it by creating new scandals. This much security, after all, would obviously be demanded by any suitor who agreed to marry Anne-Prospère with her much damaged reputation. The unsuspecting Marquis was convinced that his mother-in law, no matter how unwillingly, would succeed in getting his sentence reversed. A free man again, he would be able to return to France. He was confident that she would not lift a finger against him on account of her younger daughter. Surely the family honor would forbid her to allow such a scandal, and this silence would in turn protect him. Little did he know Madame de Montreuil. It took little time for her to discover de Sade’s whereabouts; being such a careless man, he probably did not even make her search particularly difficult. At any rate, she found out that the hated Marquis had rented a house at Chambéry for the month of October. Through the Foreign Minister at Versailles she promptly secured diplomatic intervention with the King of Sardinia, who resided in Turin. Comte Lascaris, the Sardinian Foreign Minister, answered by return of post that the King would be delighted to assist a lady held in such high esteem at the French Court. The Comte de Mazan, alias the Marquis de Sade, was consequently arrested and imprisoned in the fortress of Miolans in Savoy. The commander of the fortress, de Launay, treated him with great deference, and did everything in his power to help the unruly, hot-tempered French nobleman. But he also had strict instructions not to let the Marquis escape. From this time on, Madame de Montreuil made all arrangements concern- ing the prisoner directly with the Sardinian Foreign Minister. The assiduity with which he agreed to all her proposals and replied in such detail also seems to reflect the tremendous power of this woman, about whom the Sardinian ambassador at Ver sailles had no doubt long since informed him. The captive Mar quis had no force to counteract this, other than the constant petitioning of his totally powerless wife. Madame de Montreuil wanted to have every document and letter of de Sade’s in her possession, and ordered everything to be sent to her as soon as possible. Above all, de Sade was to have no contact with the out side world. “AIl that matters is that Monsieur de Mazan remains in captivity. ... everything else is of secondary importance. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="7">
                <head type="chapter">THE LAST FLING</head>
                <p>ON MAY 14, 1773, the Sardinian ambassador had to give Madame de Montreuil the depressing news that the prisoner had escaped during the night of May 1. Police inquiries had so far only been able to establish that the Marquis had already crossed the French frontier on the route to Grenoble. Contrary to ex pectations, Madame remained outwardly composed. Louis XV had died ten days earlier, and she now had to find her ground in the new Court and establish a new circle of trustworthy confidants -a task made none the easier by the strict mourning being ob served there. The Marquis, on the other hand, found the great upheaval caused throughout the country by the change of sovereigns very convenient for his secret return home. He was, after all, still legally under sentence of death, but for a long time no one seemed to be bothering about him and there were no signs of any persecu tion. For a while, though the warrant was still out for his arrest, he lived undetected at La Coste, managing to evade several routine searches without any difficulty. Neither his peasant subjects nor the local priest and craftsmen betrayed him, and the Marquise, who had organized the escape, was overjoyed to have the tem- peramental monster home again. Through his sentence, de Sade had forfeited both his civil rights and the right to administer his own property, as a result of which a notary from Apt was ap pointed as the authorized trustee of the family affairs. De Sade then discovered that this man had been acting as an agent for his mother-in-law and immediately ordered his wife, who had temporarily been named claimant to the property, to have him replaced. Over the years the new custodian, a notary named Gaufridy, became the Marquis’ confidant and, for a time, friend, and played an important role in the remaining years of his life. He promptly commissioned Gaufridy to try to have the Aix trial re-opened in Paris and the sentence nullified. The Marquise also travelled several times to Paris in order to hand urgent petitions personally to the new ministers. It seemed a favorable sign that the hated Minister Maupeou had been dismissed from office by the young King. However, despite all efforts, de Sade did not succeed. The situation was more than unpleasant for him and he gradually felt himself threatened and in daily fear of an unpleasant surprise. As always, de Sade felt most secure at the family château, La Coste. Under the circumstances it might be thought that he would have become more prudent and tried to lead an inoffensive life, but this was not the case. The only difference was that now the scene of his orgies was no longer a petite maison or a provincial hotel, but of necessity his own château. The new series of scandals was known collectively as “the scandal of the young girls” be cause most of the girls involved were fifteen year olds. They had been engaged for “well-paid jobs in the château, when in reality they were to take part in the sexual bacchanals organized by the Marquis throughout that whole winter; his imagination really seemed inexhaustible. A number of the girls had only been won over after their parents and guardians had been assured that it was not the infamous Marquis who was engaging them, but a member of another branch of the family—from which it can be deduced that de Sade was well aware of his evil reputation. Why did he insist so suddenly on having teenage girls, who until then had never been involved in any of his orgies? Again it must be stressed that right from the start de Sade’s over whelming sexual drive had always been combined with an in tellectual curiosity—that enthusiasm for research referred to previously. Thus we may conjecture that a methodical curiosity also governed his habit of gathering sexual experiences, even if this was for a long time subconscious. He was an intelligent monster, and had always been strongly self-analytical; or, to be more pre cise, observant of his own reactions to his orgies. He never under mined his health to the extent of physical deterioration, as had been the case with countless other libertines in this debauched period. Having once indulged his irresistible inclination for "sad ism,” he was then able to lead the normal life of a secluded nobleman, devoting himself for months to his family and read ing. The "scandal of the young girls” was followed by years of turmoil, official inquiries, and embarrasing revelations, stirred up not the least by the parents of the girls, who were hoping for silence money—and who did not always wait in vain. Madame de Montreuil had to intervene with the help of all her powerful connections to protect the reputation of her daughter and her grandchildren, who were then living permanently with her in Paris. She succeeded too, though her methods were not exactly choice; any girl who was too talkative or obstinate was simply imprisoned for some fictitious offense. Another girl was hidden in the Abbé de Sade’s house and treated there by a doctor. One outraged father even tried to shoot the Marquis, though his daughter, known in the château as Justine, defended her master and wanted to stay with him. By orders of the court de Sade was forced to free her, and wrote to Gaufridy that "in this country only a cat need be drowned and the whole world says that the Marquis is guilty.” In the summer of 1775 he discovered to his horror that his mother-in-law had procured a new warrant for his arrest, and that his old enemy Marais was already on his way to arrest him. Once again he fled to Italy, this time for a whole year. In spite of everything, de Sade still considered himself not guilty; at most he reproached himself for his carelessness. Five years later, in the prison at Vincennes, he wrote a kind of state ment of account of this last scandal to his wife. It should be read, for it gives tremendous insight into the mentality of this man who always defended his own behavior and blamed others:  1o throw someone into prison for five years on account of some business with girls such as happens a hundred times every day in Paris! And then to tell him that he can consider himself lucky to have gotten away with five years, and that it is all for his own good, if he is tormented to that extent "Since I had been forced to spend my time alone in a re mote château and almost always without you, and since it is a little weakness of mine—I must confess—that I love women too much, I contacted a procuress in Lyons and asked her to supply me with three or four young and pretty maid-servants. This woman was the officially recognized procuress of Lyons. ... She prom ised me the girls, whom she then gave to me. I took them, and availed myself of their services. Six months later some parents arrived to fetch their daughters, assuring me that these girls were their children. I handed them over, and all of a sudden I found myself being tried for seduction and rape. This is the law. In France a procuress is strictly forbidden to supply virgins, and if the girl supplied is a virgin and complains, then it is not the man who is responsible, but the procuress, who is at once severely punished. Hence this first accusation brought against me in Lyons of seduction and rape is not legal. I am not guilty: the procuress who supplied the girls should have been punished, not I. But there was nothing to be had from her, whereas the parents of the girls hoped to obtain money from me.... In this way the live lihood of the five girls from Lyons was to be assured. This is so clear that I defy even the most skillful and cunning lawyer to prove the opposite to me. To continue: the other girls—of the age and condition that they could not be demanded back by their parents—also lived before or after this at La Coste. I shall tell you their story, even if it takes the form of a general confession. For I intend to do everything possible to refute the slightest evidence that all the outrages are true which are falsely attributed to me and which serve Madame de Montreuil as the necessary weapons for her re venge. The first girl was called du Plan, and was a dancer at the theater in Marseilles. She lived quite officially, not incognito, as housekeeper at the château, and left just as openly.... so there can be no problem on her account. The second came from Montpellier and was called Rosette. She lived secretly for about two months at the château, but then became bored and wanted to leave. We agreed that she should write to a man she knew in Montpellier, a carpenter by profession, whom I believe was her landlord in that town. He was to pick her up at the château wall; day, hour, and meeting place were all agreed upon. On the ap pointed day he duly appeared, and I personally handed the girl over to him ... In October 1776 I had to spend two weeks in Montpellier, and brought a third girl back with me from there. The above-mentioned Rosette was then living in Montpellier; for this I have the absolute proof that I saw here there myself, and it was she who caused this third girl, Adélaide, to come with me and do as she had done. She even assured Adélaide, in the presence of two or three other women ... that apart from the loneliness she had been quite satisfied with everything I did.. "So what is the outcome of all that? Monsieur de Sade is no doubt charged with the most appalling outrages. But Monsieur de Sade wishes to prove that in this last matter, as in all others, he carried out no trials or experiments, nor did he commit any murder, but did only the same as anyone who has sexual relations with girls who have already lost their virginity and who have been supplied to him by a procuress. In other words, what he did had nothing to do with seduction; yet he is being punished and made to suffer as if he had committed the most vile crimes. These are all my alleged crimes .. and I swear I shall prove it so convincingly that no one can possibly fail to see the truth.. Yes, I admit I am a libertine; I have conceived everything imag inable in this sphere, but I have by no means done everything I conceived, and shall never do so. I am a libertine, but I am neither a criminal nor à murderer. The Marquis is exceedingly eloquent; he would certainly have made an incisive lawyer, for he seemed to know that an address must be carefully attuned to the mentality of those whom it is intended to move. As later investigations have proven, events turned out rather differently, and to de Sade’s disadvantage, but these statements are typical of his reactions when he found him self in prison after one of the scandals had been publicly exposed. He always insisted on his own innocence, reduced the incidents to mere trivialities, and could not understand why so much fuss was made about the girls involved—who were, after all, almost always prostitutes. That his was a particularly degenerate case, that did not fit into any existing category of vice, only occurred to him later, when he realized that obscenity could be used as a means of rebellion against a morality with which one did not agree. But such perception comes only with time and enforced solitude away from all distractions. De Sade’s destiny of course amply ful filled this condition, and with each new scandal—nolentem fata trahunt—he persistently provoked this fate and hastened its pro gress. The news of his mother’s death provided de Sade with a wel- come excuse to evade the interrogation and trial in Provence. The Countess de Sade, who had lived in seclusion in a Carmelite convent in Paris since before the death of her husband in 1767, died on January 14, 1777, at the age of sixty-five. Contrary to several claims, de Sade had had little affection for either his father or his cold, indifferent mother ever since childhood; it was a love less relationship, with almost total alienation between mother and son and only occasional brief courtesy visits, as was customary among the French nobility at the time. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="8">
                <head type="chapter">THE "LETTRE DE CACHET"</head>
                <p>DE SADE was implored from all sides not to return to Paris, where Madame de Montreuil was lying in wait for him. As usual, the Marquis disregarded all good advice, and entered Paris on February 8, 1777. Two days later the Marquise was unwise enough to mention it to her mother, and on February 13, In spector Marais appeared in the Hôtel de Danemark where the Marquis had taken rooms, and arrested him on the authority of a Royal Order, or “lettre de cachet,” just signed by Louis XVI. Before midnight the deeply shocked Marquis was taken to the notorious state prison at Vincennes. In his first letter to his wife he wrote: “I have been confined in a tower behind nineteen iron doors. The only light I have is through two small windows, each with twenty bars.” Madame de Montreuil, on the other hand, had this to say about her imprisoned son-in-law: “The man has been taken into custody and imprisoned in a fortress near Paris. My mind is now at rest and I believe that everyone will be satisfied. With few exceptions, this was the case; the Marquis was con sidered to be the outcast of the French aristocracy, and there was general relief at the knowledge that this scandalous, coarse confrère had been removed from the public eye. The effect of the lettre de cachet was to provide a kind of safe-custody for a notoriously incorrigible man. At the same time, it ensured him incomparably better treatment in prison than he would have re ceived in these days of equality; for a marquis from an old family with connections with the Bourbons enjoyed certain privileges, even in prison. He was allowed to bring in his own furniture and to feed himself at his own expense, though he remained a prisoner—and one who never knew how long his captivity would last. De Sade’s often very macabre descriptions may at times seem exaggerated, for he had no idea how the unprivileged prisoners were treated in the dungeons below—some of them un derground—and therefore had no basis for comparison. Since all the letters he wrote or received were strictly censored by the governor of Vincennes, it took the Marquise over six months to find out where her husband was interned, and even longer before she was allowed to visit him for the first time. De Sade energetically rejected Madame de Montreuil’s demand that he should have himself declared mad, which would cause all his affairs to be seen in a different light and make the Aix death sentence null and void. He insisted instead on a new trial before new judges. Finally, at the end of May 1778, the King authorized the reopening of the trial. The original verdict was declared in valid and in a hastily rushed-through hearing the only sentence imposed on the Marquis was a caution for his excessive debauchery and a small fine. The whole de Sade family could breathe freely again at last; there was no longer any blemish on the family honor and the careers of his growing sons would not be en dangered. This was precisely what Madame de Montreuil had been aiming for; however, her actual opinion of her acquitted son-in-law had not changed at all. Immediately after the acquittal, the Marquis, who had imagined he would soon be returning to La Coste, learned to his horror that the royal “lettre de cachet was still valid. He was promptly taken back to Vincennes by Inspector Marais and two policemen. Madame de Montreuil was quite determined never to allow her hated son-in-law to appear in public again. In those days the journey from Aix to Paris took about two weeks, and on the second evening at an overnight stop in Valence, the Marquis outwitted his guards and escaped. With the help of the municipal guard they searched for him all that night and the following day, but in vain. I hid in a shed like a farmer’s threshing barn only a few hundred meters from the town, and got two peasants to take me in the direction of Montélimar. But after several miles we changed our minds and plodded along the Rhône looking for a boat, but none came. After sundown I finally sent for a small boat from Vivarais, and for one louis d’or I was rowed to Avignon. A few hours later the fugitive reached his château at La Coste. For some unknown reason, he again believed he was safe there, and for weeks was filled with a feeling of euphoria at his lucky escape. A clever and very cultured friend of his from earlier days, Mademoiselle de Rousset, who had been looking after the château in his absence, now kept him company, and he was at tended to by the cheerful, coarse maid, Gothon. Just four weeks later he received a warning of the presence of spies in the neigh borhood. He spent a few nights with a friendly canon, Vidal, but his old carelessness came to the fore again, and he returned to La Coste. At four o’clock in the morning of August 26, a dozen policemen led by Chief Constable Marais broke into the château and, after a brief search, found the Marquis in a broom cupboard where he had tried to hide at the last minute. He was securely bound and escorted under the most humiliating conditions to Valence. From there, still bound and closely watched the whole time, he had to undergo the thirteen-day journey to Vincennes, where he now had to be satisfied with a much worse, barely lit cell. This time he had to wait much longer before he was allowed any concessions. The first winter—1778/9—was particularly miser able for him. He was not even allowed any exercise, as were the other prisoners. In one of his countless letters to his wife in the course of the following twelve years he wrote: “Explain to me, please, what you mean when you write: f you cannot write yourself, then let me write?’ You must think I have secretaries at my disposal, but I am far removed from any such luxury; in fact I can scarcely meet my most pressing needs! A man in a perpetual rush appears in my room four times a day. The first time at daybreak, to ask me it I have slept well; the other times to bring food, etc. This makes exactly seven minutes four times a day, and that is all: die of boredom or anxiety if you will, it is of no interest to us! Earlier on I was attended to far better than I am now. I was able to go for walks, I had company at mealtimes, and lived in a good room, which I was allowed to heat. Now I have no one to eat with, very few walks, and am banished to the dampest room in the whole prison—that is why I have so many headaches. And on top of all that there is no possibility of heating. I was not able to make a single fire the whole winter, and I can assure you that I cannot go on like this. That, dear friend, is how it stands. I am not needed any more, for my trial is settled. And if I should die, so much the better, then they will be rid of me once and 11„ for all. Throughout the years of his captivity, de Sade remained an extremely restless, temperamental and quarrelsome prisoner, and moody and erratic as well. One day he was quiet and polite, and the next he would abuse everyone he encountered. His wife also suffered bitterly from these changeable moods. Though she was constantly working on his behalf, she was never able to carry out his instructions and messages to his satisfaction. He was hurt ful to her in his letters, and later insulted her verbally when she came to visit him. He even developed a jealously complex to wards her, stubbornly tormenting himself with suspicions that she had taken a lover. This was only partly due to the fact that she was free and he was in prison; he had come to hate her as the daughter of the woman whom he held to blame for his mis fortune. Self-criticism was not de Sade’s strongest quality. Besides the Marquise, Mademoiselle de Rousset also intervened on his behalf with Madame de Montreuil and at Versailles. As a result of her petitions, Minister de Maurepas agreed to study the whole dossier to establish whether there were any valid reasons for holding the Marquis in captivity, and if not to ask the King for his release. Mademoiselle de Rousset even bribed a clerk to study the entire document in secret. In October 1780 she wrote the following account of the result to the trustee Gaufridy, who as de Sade’s legal adviser had to be informed: The situation is the same, and I believe will remain so for some time to come. After long delays and many vague promises I asked to see the evidence for his arrest and arranged for Madame de Sade to see it too. It was no easy matter, and the person who was brave enough to undertake the scheme did so at the risk of the galley or imprisonment for life. By this trick we discovered that his revered mother-in-law is not as guilty as we thought. He has other more powerful and distinguished enemies. There are serious grounds which make us fear a long imprisonment. Whether valid or not, they are the Minister's trump-cards with all respect able people. After hearing the proof, the Minister and his wife, two princesses and others said that de Sade should stay where he is, and that his wife must be either mad or his accomplice if she dares to demand his release... . Various police officers who searched the château gave the most shocking evidence, and such people are believed. Monsieur de Sade’s whole life is recorded in a file—but let us not reveal by whom, for he should be hanged. Certain details which I had assumed only few people knew of are known; and many others too—which must be kept in strictest secrecy—make me believe that his captivity will be long. However, this is all very nebulous. The dossier on de Sade ap parently made it impossible to plead for him on the grounds that he was the victim of injustice. One word from the King would, of course, have dispensed with the dossier—at least if one of the Ministers or the King's confidants had requested it. This did not happen simply because the introverted Marquis had no friends at Court. Instead, the case was used as a welcome excuse to demonstrate the King's virtuous indignation to the public. Such methods had already been applied in Louis XV’s reign to appease the public wrath over his extravagant mistress, Madame du Barry, and under Louis XVI over the necklace affair, in which Cardinal de Rohan sought to win favor with the Queen by buying her a diamond necklace worth almost a million dollars, and then defaulting on his payments to the jewelers. If we add to this the Marquis’ scarcely veiled atheistic outlook and the way he had always deliberately provoked new scandals, we can see how fashion- able Court society regarded the case of the Marquis de Sade as a demonstration of contempt for their own way of life. Every ruling society takes the most cruel revenge against such scorn, as for instance was to happen later in the case of Oscar Wilde. In spite of all his risky carelessness and negligence since the Keller affair, de Sade knew very well that he could expect nothing further from his own class. It almost seems as if he himself regarded his down fall as inevitable, and even precipitated it. Even at this stage, the Marquis himself still refused obstinately to see any guilt in his actions. From quite early on his crimes fall into two distinet categories; those which were perhaps con sciously experimental, and those which satisfied his eminently perverse nature, to which he was drawn by an irresistible force, and which he did not consider any judge in the world competent to penalize. Why should he atone for what was “cruel Mother Nature’s” fault, as he defined it later? </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="9">
                <head type="chapter">HOW DE SADE SAVED HIMSELF</head>
                <p>BEHIND the thick walls of Vincennes he no longer had any opportunity whatever for debauchery. He could only remember the orgies of the past and dream up new ones for the future. But such an overwhelming erotic imagination as de Sade’s could not be satisfied with the pale shadows of memories and ideas; it strove for the active realization of desire. Since, however, the enormously thick walls of Vincennes stood between him and the subject of his craving, he attempted another kind of realization, by fixing his monstrous dreams with pen and ink onto the purity of blank white paper. From this year of despair of 1780 onwards, de Sade worked at writing as a form of sexual release. As an author, he created his own private world populated with thou sands of characters—personifications of cruelty and lust—which were to outlive not only the rococo period but also the subsequent bourgeois century. The question has often been posed whether de Sade would have become an author had he been a free man, or whether he would have devoted all his time to new orgies. Very few people seem to know that a volume was found after the last war contain ing his early writings from the period between 1764 and 1769, most of which have never been published. He also seems to have written some early plays. In addition to this there were the great variety of manuscripts confiscated by Madame de Montreuil from Miolans and La Coste, which were almost certainly destroyed. The Marquis had therefore had a certain amount of practice in writing before the start of his long solitude in prison. We also hear how much time he devoted in the early years to reading, occupying himself in particular with the works of his contemporaries. Nevertheless, what he had written before this period in prison was very much the work of an amateur. Indeed many noblemen at that time in France occupied themselves with occasional writing for pleasure, and because they had enough money and leisure. For de Sade in captivity it was quite a different matter. He began writing as a means of continuing his very existence. Cut off from the world and people, and above all from women, he tried to create an imaginary world which conformed to the laws that had determined his own fate. The whole action was to be a giant, never-ending dispute between his personal world and the despised world of degenerate morality, of which he felt he was an innocent victim. Until 1782, he concentrated mostly on keeping a diary (also lost) and he then embarked at a feverish tempo on the mass of books which is still condemned because of their unsurpassable obscenity, even though written by an author who, however un- willingly, must be acknowledged as a genius. These works will be discussed later in this book. At any event, one fact is definite: whereas other prisoners, robbed for years of their freedom, as a rule become mentally dulled and lapse into gloomy resignation, the Marquis, after an initial period of utter despair, rapidly rose to the heights of his intellect and laid the foundations of his dia bolical immortality. In his twelve years of isolation from the outside world, de Sade was to fill sixteen thick volumes with his extraordinarily elegant, almost calligraphic handwriting. This excludes his diaries, notebooks, and countless letters. The sheer mass of these works clearly presupposes that he was allowed complete freedom to write, though it is known that there were checks, confiscations by the order of the Governor, and occasional complete bans on writing. Later on, the prisoner even made copies of his writings, which he then passed to his wife when she was allowed to visit him in his cell. He was permitted to work by candlelight on dark days and in winter until midnight, and never lacked paper, ink, or books, though each book apparently had to be individually ap proved. When he was refused Rousseau’s Confessions in 1783, he wrote an indignant letter to his wife, whom he also blamed: To refuse me the Confessions of Jean-Jacques Rousseau is a fine thing, especially after having allowed me to have Lucre tius and Voltaire. It shows a fine discernment and power of judg ment in your advisers. Alas, they do me too great an honor if they believe that a free-thinking author would be harmful for me to read. I would that it were true. You are not particularly elevated in your methods of cure, my venerable supervisors. Learn that it is the character of the individual that renders a thing bad or not, not the thing in itself. . Go on from there, gentlemen, and have the good sense to understand, in sending me the book I ask for, that Rousseau could be a danger to bigoted hyprocrites like you, but is an excellent book for me. Jean-Jacques is for me what the Imitation of Christ is for you. The morals and religion of Rousseau are important for me, and I read them when I imagine I should like to improve myself. If you don’t want me to become better than I am—so much for that. To be good is something painful and repugnant to me; I wish for nothing better than I wager, you to remain in my morass—I am happy there.. imagined you would work a miracle by reducing me to the terrible abstinence of the joys of the flesh. Well, you were mistaken. You have heated my mind, you have made me conceive phantoms that I now have to bring forth. When one makes the pot boil, it spills over, as you very well know. This desperate brooding always led the Marquis back to the conviction that all morality is relative. Not only in his period but throughout history there were numerous moral systems which al most all contradicted each other, established more or less arbitrary regulations, and were therefore altogether artificial and could not refer to man’s true nature. There is no reason why any one desire should be better than any other, and gratification should primarily meet the preferred tendency of the individual instinct. In the sexual act it is always the stronger of the two who imposes his personal form of gratification, thus even in the tamest case there is an element of force and cruelty. Even enduring cruelty can be a form of desire, and as legitimately natural as inflicting pain. Where sex is concerned it is absurd to use antitheses such as good and bad, beautiful and repulsive, natural and unnatural, or normal and perverse. Only the man who scorns all this and considers solely his own maximum sexual desire can attain harmony with himself and demonstrate the unconditional natural freedom of his body as a spontaneous experience. De Sade made it his revengeful ambition in the dungeons of Vincennes and the Bastille to insist on this radical right and free dom of the individual who knows himself to be the stronger and more powerful. In his days of freedom, restrained by all kinds of social considerations, he had confined his experiments and scandals to the much despised prostitutes, and what good had it done him? In a letter to his former servant Carteron, he wrote: "In France, lack of respect for a whore is punished. One may criticize the government, the King, or religion, but one must be very careful not to insult a whore, confound it, for Sartine, Maupeou, Montreuil, and other accomplices of the brothels all come immediately to the whore’s assistance, and without more ado imprison a nobleman for twelve or fifteen years. Here, as in many other similar statements, de Sade concealed or persistently refused to acknowledge that it was not the pros titutes or their complaints that had really aroused the powerful Madame de Montreuil’s undying hatred for him. This aspect probably no longer had any real meaning for him; he merely felt that he was persecuted and imprisoned as the innocent victim of his instincts. His anger thus simultaneously became his salvation. He created himself a world of bodies, where he could dispense with prostitutes and was totally free from the hypocritical moral canons of the time. Here he could demonstrate his own boundless freedom with impunity, and through this he achieved something of which he frankly remained unaware: he sublimated his in satiable, savage sexuality. Writing gradually came to be more than a mere substitute for action. The prison cell was no longer so unbearably oppressive, the walls became penetrable. His world was free because he had created it according to his own ideas and convictions. In it vice was powerful, strong, and always savagely victorious, while virtue was presented as completely unnatural and consequently inferior. It as the virtue of vice, by which he could follow only his own inclinations and never succumb to the corruption of compassion. What is generally called per versity here often meant only the innate drive for sexual satis faction. In Juliette, Clairwil says: “I should like to find a crime which would never cease to have an effect, even independently of me, so that there would never be a moment in my life ... when I was not causing universal corruption—a destruction that would con tinue long after my death. Juliette, as the ultimate incarnation of vice, then replies: “Then try an intellectual crime and write! Writing behind the thick walls of the prison, de Sade no longer needed to deny his true being; he identified wholly with his real, unconcealed self, and thus gained a position of unfearing superiority over his enemies, who were always ready to destroy him for the sake of fashionable morality. At another point in Juliette, one of the characters says: “The true libertine even loves the stain left by his despicable way of life. Were there not people who even loved the torture inflicted on them by human vindic tiveness which they suffered with joy? People, in fact, for whom even the scaffold was a glorious place, and who would have been ashamed to experience less delight in dying there than they once did at their debauchery? In this way, man consciously reached the height of his depravity. De Sade did not change either his character or his mentality. Circumstances—or if one prefers, fate—merely removed even those few considerations to which he had ever paid the slightest regard. He no longer had to make any compromise with pre vailing morality, and was able to be the spokesman for his own existence. His enemies in fact procured for him the greatest possible intellectual freedom, secure from any disturbance. In the spring of 1781, Madame de Sade, with the help of one of the King’s sisters, obtained royal permission to have the prisoner transferred from Vincennes to the fortress of Montélimar in the south of France, from where it would be easier for him to organize the management of his estates and affairs. But the Marquis adamantly refused to make use of this permission: if he was not to be given total freedom, then he prefered to remain at Vincennes. Less than a month later he heard that Anne-Prospère had died of smallpox. All her ingenious mother's attempts to find a hus band for her scandalous daughter—even with the enticement of a large dowry—had failed, largely because Anne-Prospère her self had showed little enthusiasm and had preferred to retire to a convent. As already mentioned, every word of correspondence between her and de Sade has been destroyed, so we can only surmise what might have happened to cause such a marked cool ness between them ever since the Marquis’ escape from Miolans. In July 1781, when de Sade had been in prison for four and a half years, the Marquise was permited to visit her husband in Vincennes. But even at their first reunion de Sade flew into such violent rages of jealousy at his almost certainly innocent wife and behaved so wildly that it resulted not only in visitors being for bidden for quite some time, but also in his being denied any cor respondence. The Marquise’s self-defense against her husband's suspicions shows a truly noble and loving heart: “I am not con tent merely to know that my conscience is clear: I also want you to be happy and satisfied. I almost prefer that you tell me all your fears and suspicions quite openly, for I can dispel them quite easily ... Yet it humiliates me that you should think such things of me—for I live and exist only for you. I shall say noth ing, but you have wounded me to the quick. ... I have no need to justify myself, my manner of living is open for all to see. No, you could not possibly think and write like this of me if you knew me as you really should. My heart has not changed: it beats for you and will always love you. The only reprisal I plan is that when you are free again and have made all the necessary inquiries, you will have to admit that every thing that went through your head in prison was pure imagina tion. In order to calm her husband, the Marquise even gave up her apartment in Paris and moved into the convent of Saint Aure. De Sade’s fits of jealousy were partly due to the mental state caused by imprisonment and the pathological mistrust of every thing which arose from it; on the other hand, he did know more than enough about the ways and habits of contemporary society to doubt that a marquise at the prime of life would care to live four and a half years without either husband or lover. Finally, however, she was the only person whom he knew really loved him, and he wanted to be quite sure that this continued; for though he did not love her in the full sense, he had long felt a kind of unerotic attachment towards her. There are many indications that the Marquise even gave in willingly to the abnormal wishes of her husband in the latter years of their marriage, no doubt com forting herself with the thought that it was at least happening within marriage and not in any forbidden relationship. De Sade also seemed at times to have put a certain trust in his wife's intellectual capabilities, as can be seen from many of his letters to her from prison. He would not otherwise have written the following to her in November 1783: You say that my way of thinking cannot be tolerated? What of it? The man who alters his way of thinking to suit others is a fool. My way of thinking is the result of my reflections. It is part of my inner being, the way I am made. I do not contradict them, and would not even if I wished to. For my system, which you disapprove of, is also my greatest comfort in life, the source of all my happiness—it means more to me than my life itself. ... The reasonable man who scorns the prejudices of idiots necessarily makes himself the enemy of those simpletons—but that is unimportant and one must simply put up with it. .. If, as you write, the price of my liberty would mean the renuncia tion of all my principles and tastes, we would have to say an eternal farewell, for I would sacrifice a thousand lives and a thou sand liberties rather than surrender my ideas. I carry my tastes and principles to the point of fanaticism, and this fanaticism is the work of my persecutors. The more they attack me, the more strongly do my principles become rooted in my heart, and I declare categorically that no one need talk to me of liberty if it is offered at the cost of destroying all that I believe in. Madame de Sade did not usually share her husband’s views, and more than once wrote to him that the public would never tolerate such ideas. She was, however, totally devoted and obedi ent to him, even forgiving all his faults and atrocities. Despite his scorn, she remained faithful to the moral principles she had learned at the convent school. We can be sure that she brought up her three children wholly in accordance with conventional morality, insofar as her overpowering mother gave her the time and opportunity; for the two sons and daughter (of whom nothing is known other than that she was very ugly and coarse) lived mostly at Madame de Montreuil’s château. At the end of 1783, the elder son, Louis-Marie, then seventeen years old, was allowed to write and tell his father that he was going into the Rohan-Soubise regiment. De Sade was furious that he had not been consulted, but this was no longer necessary because the boy had long since been placed under the control of a guardian. De Sade thus had to put up with his son being accepted as a lieutenant in this regiment. In January of the following year, his devoted Mademoiselle de Rousset died. At de Sade’s request she had spent the last two years of her life looking after his château at La Coste. Since no money was available for maintenance and repairs, the château then fell into complete ruin; most of the windows were already broken, the dilapidated roof let in the rain in numerous places, and the costly furniture and carpets were covered with mildew. This sad news was soon followed by another surprise. On February 29, 1784, the unsuspecting Marquis was moved—on the King’s orders—from Vincennes, which was being given up as a prison, to the Bastille. He had to wait many weeks before his things were sent on from Vincennes, so that he could install himself in his new cell on the second floor of one of the four towers. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="10">
                <head type="chapter"> TRANSFER TO THE BASTILLE</head>
                <p>THE ROOM was octagonal, about fifteen feet wide and nine feet high, and had a window with a strong iron grille. There was a stove which could give heat in the winter. As the King’s state prison, the Bastille had its own statutes, and the giant complex never contained more than two or three dozen persons of note, without exception victims of the lettres de cachet. More effort was taken than in other prisons to treat them according to their rank, so they were permitted to furnish their cells to their own liking. De Sade therefore sent for his wall hangings, and had a good bed and other furniture placed in his room. There was ample food and the dishes were excellently prepared. The Marquis, like his fellow prisoners, nevertheless had to pay an annual sum of 2,400 livres for his keep, even by today's standards a considerable sum. It was here, in the heart of Paris but behind thick walls, that de Sade wrote several of his major works: his first novel, Justine; the long neglected, very important novel in the form of letters, Aline et Valcour; La Philosophie dans le Boudoir (Philosophy in the Boudoir); Dialogue entre un Prêtre et un moribond (Dialogue of a Priest and a Dying Man); several dozen stories of varying length; and Les 120 Journées de Sodome (The 120 Days of Sodom), which was so long believed lost. What hopes did he still hold out for the future? He had long given up any expectations of mercy or understanding from his enemies. Fashionable society had cast him out like a mangy dog, and all his relations hoped to save at least their honor and the family prestige by keeping him behind bars for the rest of his life. He no longer had a single friend, for even his lawyer obeyed Madame de Montreuil’s secret instructions, and his own wife, although she remained faithful to him, was totally powerless. In his endless solitude, the Marquis wrote on indefatigably, filling volume after volume. This was his only means of leading an ac tive existence and gaining a freedom which was not just a sub stitute for that which had been denied him, but one forced out of the circumstances of his fate, a protection, in fact, against the tyranny to which he would otherwise have fallen victim. The enormous number of works is itself proof—it was desire, trans port, happiness. There is a report written by the governor of the Bastille, de Launay, on July 7, 1786, to the supervisory Lieutenant-General of Police, de Crosne. From this it can be seen that the Marquis had not changed at all even after the transfer from Vincennes to the Bastille: I had the honor of receiving a letter from you concerning the Marquise de Sade’s petition. It is true that at the beginning of her husband's internment ... she had permission to visit him once a week. But the prisoner is very changeable and hot tempered, and created a scene whenever she came. One day in particular, when he refused to comply with the regulation that they must speak audibly, he flew uncontrollably at Monsieur de Losme. Piles of his letters have been censored, full of slanderous remarks about his wife and family, and even about us. Without the slightest reason he insulted the guard accompanying him dur ing a walk. Since this appalling behavior was becoming more frequent all the time, Monsieur Le Noir, my predecessor, con sidered it advisable to withdraw the visitors' permit at least for a while. I believe we are rendering a service to his wife and family if he is allowed to have visitors only once a month in future. If he no longer abuses this permission, then it can be given more frequently later. He has become much quieter since he has seen no one. Madame de Sade only seeks permission to visit him out of loyalty and the goodness of her heart, although she always has to face a storm of insults and reproaches. In truth she almost fears for her life in case he is set free one day. All the men here could verify this fact. About a year later, when he received a miniature of his wife in a tortoise-shell frame, this extraordinary man was overjoyed with this "exquisite, heavenly present” and finished his rapturous letter of thanks to his wife with the words: “I embrace you and would thank you even more if I could really take you into my arms. The portrait, the tortoise-shell, it is all beautiful. It gives me great pleasure and indescribable joy. In 1787, his wife was again allowed to visit him regularly. He was also permitted to go for an hour’s walk each day, and was given an invalid as a servant, who for eight louis d'or a month looked after him like a real valet de chambre. At his demand, the best eye specialist in Paris was permitted to treat him, for partly owing to his long hours of work with bad light he had contracted a particularly unpleasant case of keratitis. To give him better light, he was permitted to move from the second to the fourth floor of the prison tower, and he again furnished his new room to his own taste. He also had some new, elegant clothes made, which was urgently necessary because the long imprison ment and lack of exercise had made him extremely fat. Then came the year which history would never forget—1789. As the summer progressed, the whole of France was seized by fever. An entry in the duty book of the Bastille for July 2, 1789, reads: “Monsieur de Sade has been repeatedly shouting out of his window that the prisoners of the Bastille are being slaughtered and must be saved immediately. Throughout his unlawful imprisonment—148 months long by July 1789—de Sade had taken every opportunity to protest and rebel. He was the King's most rebellious prisoner. He occasionally threatened to make every possible attempt to escape, and had never been on friendly terms with his “jailers,” as he called the governors. He never accepted his position or became resigned to the circumstances, but demanded his unconditional right to free dom. He had long ceased to feel any solidarity with the aristocracy which had so coldly deserted him, or with the King, who had so unscrupulously sacrificed one of the old nobility to the wife of a member of the bourgeois aristocracy. Agitation had been building up in France ever since the necklace affair of 1785, and de Sade had certainly been informed of all important events. The unrest in Paris filled him with the most glowing hopes, for it was the expression of a fierce determination to overthrow the rotten ancien régime and to set up a state of freedom and justice in the spirit of Rousseau, as well as to disestablish a Church whose moral laws were no less despotic and tyrannical than the King’s justice. It would be unfair to say that de Sade was no revolutionary merely because he was concerned solely with his own personal freedom. A radical individualist, he despised the lower classes throughout his life; but he had also made a pact with Satan and all the monsters of hell to destroy the despotic State which had unlawfully caused him to spend so many years in prison—him, the man who had discovered the secret of all sexual desires. One of the reports written by his guards at the time states: The Marquis de Sade was allowed to take a walk at a stipulated time. The riots in Paris, which increased daily, forced the governor to double the security measures and to load the cannon. Conse quently, he had to forbid several prisoners’ walks on the towers. Monsieur de Sade refused to accept the reasons for this, stormed and threatened to shout loudly if Lossinote did not accept the petition he had given him for the governor. Monsieur de Launay still firmly refused, so Monsieur de Sade seized the long fun nelled pipe he had had made to facilitate pouring out water and used it as an amplifier by shoving it through the window looking out on to the Rue Saint-Antoine. He then shouted through it, his insults against the governor rapidly gathering a large crowd whom he asked for help because, he said, he was going to be murdered. In a rage the governor then sent a courier post-haste to Versailles, a special order was drawn up, and Monsieur de Sade was transferred to Charenton the following night. Ten days later the great Revolution broke out precisely at the Bastille, which was finally stormed, demolished, and set on fire, and the governor, de Launay, killed. The people of Paris rejoiced at this victory, and July 14, 1789, is celebrated to the present day as the start of the Revolution. It is one of the paradoxes of history that the unfortunate Marquis de Sade should have undeniably contributed to this by drawing the attention of the public to the Bastille as the stronghold of royal tyranny. But the Marquis was still to have ample opportunity to study the Medusan face of history, and in particular of revolutions. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="11">
                <head type="chapter">FREEDOM UNDER THREAT</head>
                <p>ON MAY 19, 1790, almost a year later, he wrote to an old ac quaintance, the lawyer Reinaud in Aix: “The dear Montreuils foresaw a week before the storming of the Bastille the confusion it would cause. They feared that I would escape to freedom with the other prisoners on the day of the storming, and so had me taken to Charenton. There, Monsieur, these criminals, these black guard Montreuils, left me to vegetate for another nine months among idiots and epileptics. I still wonder that I survived it at all ... After nine months they allowed my children to visit me, with the news that the billets de cachet had been declared invalid. One of them had the inspiration to ask the prior [the asylum was at the time run by the religious order of the Brothers of Mercy) with what right and on whose orders I was being held there. The prior first of all did not dare to mention the King's order, and pushed the blame on to the family. ... Stop, I said to the shepherd of the insane, such family wishes mean even less these days than the orders of a Minister, which I scarcely care to think of. Monsieur, I demand that you open the gates for me immediately!' The confused man did not have the courage to refuse, the iron gates were opened, and I wished him good evening and departed. At this point I was reminded of the saying: Il n'y a si bonne compagnie, qui ne se quitte. ... The settlement of important matters and the fear of being strung up on a demo cratic gallows in Provence will keep me here until the spring. Valence, Montauban, and Marseilles are all scenes of horror.... Alas, it seems a long time ago since I said that this lovely, peaceful nation ... was only waiting for the opportunity to show its enthusiasm, and to prove that, although she has al ways found herself balanced between atrocity and fanaticism, she could recover her natural style whenever the time came! But enough of such talk; we must be careful in letters. Freedom opens many more letters than despotism once did. To his old friend Gaufridy he wrote: the disease in my eyes has almost robbed me of my sight. I have acquired, because of lack of exercise, an enormous corpulence, so that I can hardly move. All my sensations are faded, nothing gives me pleasure any more, I love nothing. The world that I desired so madly now seems so dull—and sad. There are moments when I feel I should like to be a monk. I should not like to guarantee that one day I shall not simpły disappear without anyone knowing where I have gone. ... I kept very busy during my detention. Just imagine, I had fifteen manuscripts ready for press, but when they let me out of prison I only had a quarter of them left. It suited Madame de Sade to lose some, to leave others behind, and that means thirteen lost years. Three-quarters of my writings had re mained in the Bastille when I was transferred to Charenton on July 4. When the Bastille was then stormed and plundered on July 14, my manuscripts, six hundred volumes of my library, two thousand livres' worth of furniture, including many costly objects and pictures, were torn, burned, stolen, or thrown away. Not a thing was ever found again, and all due to Madame’s carelessness. She had ten days in which to collect my possessions. ... Why was she so slow to rescue my things? I weep tears of blood over my manuscripts. One can buy other beds, tables, and commodes, No, my friend, I am in but one can never recover ideas. capable of describing my despair at this loss—it is irreparable. Since then my sensitive wife wants to have nothing more to do with me. She even wants to ruin me totally, for she has filed a petition for divorce. Since the Marquise had patiently endured so many years with utter loyalty and selflessness at the side of her extremist husband, what in fact induced her, now that he was finally free, to obtain a separation? She was tired, she was growing old, but above all in the years of enforced separation she had become very pious again, and was tortured by countless moral scruples. The children were grown up and no longer needed to be protected from the destructive influence of their father. The Marquis' attitudes, espe cially his radical atheism, were even more repugnant to her than before. The days of love and passion were over, and the enor mously corpulent, asthmatic man who left Charenton was very different from the slim, youthful cavalier she had known in the glittering days at La Coste. But would even this have been enough to sever the Marquise’s previously immutable ties with her husband? After de Sade’s release from Charenton it appears that his wife even refused to let him have back the many manuscripts which he had secretly given her for safe-keeping on her visits to Vincennes and the Bastille. She said that she had given some of them to other responsible people, who had burned some of them, allegedly out of fear that they could be harmful if found in one of the revolu tionaries' frequent house-searches. One can imagine the Marquis frenzied rage at hearing this, and the violent scenes which no doubt ensued. It was in fact a severe breach of trust on the part of his suddenly over-pious wife. When he threatened her with a scandal, she inferred that it would be far more critical for him, since, if forced, she would declare everything and clear herself of any blame. De Sade finally had to agree to an almost ruinous divorce settlement, which plunged him into endless financial difficulties. On the other hand, at his request the compulsory order on his estates was removed, and he was able occasionally to make use of his property, including La Coste. He soon consoled himself over the separation from his wife. Since his release from prison, Citoyen Donatien Sade—as he was then known—had again turned to his beloved theater and moved mostly in acting circles. There he met a pretty, twenty-one-year-old actress, Marie-Constance Ren elle, who had a child, and had mysteriously been deserted by her husband some years before. She occasionally played small parts and received a meager income from her husband. She was to re main with de Sade until his death, and doubtless understood how to deal with this difficult, temperamental man, so obsessed with wild ideas. Right to the end, he expressed nothing but love and gratitude for her, as he wrote to Reinaud in June 1791: If Madame Quesnet (for that is the name of her faithless husband) does bind herself to me, then I shall have to promise her a small sum every five years so as to oblige her to prolong my life. That is frankly a crude way of making her interested in my old age, which she will then only care for out of self-interest—but I have no illusions. How could I have lived alone with just two or three servants, who would have robbed me or even perhaps murdered me? Was it not essential to have a responsible person between these fellows and myself? How else could I protect my self against swindlers or have checked the butcher’s bills, when I am buried in my study, surrounded by the works of Molière, Destouches, and Marivaux ... which I am reading, studying, admiring, and will never be able to surpass? Do I not then need someone on the spot with whom I can read and discuss everything: My companion is ideally suited to this. May God preserve her for me, in spite of the incredible attempts which are constantly being made to entice her away from me. A novel of mine is currently being printed, but it is so exceedingly immoral that I do not dare to send it to such a virtuous and correct man as yourself. But I need the money, and my publisher wanted it liberally spiced; so I have done him the favor, so much so that it would poison the devil himself. The novel is called Justine ou Les Malheurs de la vertu. Please burn it; don't read it if it should by any chance come into your hands. In any case, I shall disown it. But you will shortly be receiving a philosophical novel, which I am forwarding to you by the next post. De Sade was probably delighted to agree to his publisher’s request for “liberal spicing,” but he also needed the money des perately. In the Bastille he had been completely free to write whatever he thought important or necessary, but those days were past. As a professional writer, unknown and dependent on ad vances, he was in no position to disregard his publisher’s wishes -not that they were necessarily very difficult for him to fulfill. The novel was already obscene in the draft he had written in the Bastille, even without the extensive pornographic scenes which he now added, developing the earlier Justine into La Nouvelle Justine. Together with the later Histoire de Juliette it was to form the climax of his black novels. In the late autumn of 1791, one of his plays was actually pro duced at the Theâtre Molière, and its author was greeted with applause by the audience. The play was called Le Comte Oxtiern ou Les Effets du libertinage (Count Oxtiern or the Effects of a Rake’s Life). It dealt in three pathetic and moving prose acts with the evil intrigues of a Swedish libertine who, at the moment of his supposed triumph, is killed in a duel by the noble lover of the abducted girl. Just a year later, de Sade’s one-act play Le Suborneur was given at the Theâtre Italien, but a group of Jacobin hecklers in Phrygian caps made so much noise that the actors could scarcely be heard. In the meantime, de Sade, with Gaufridy’s assistance, had suc ceeded in salvaging some furniture and other household effects, as well as several cases of books, from the hopelessly decaying château at La Coste. He had managed to rent a rather large apart ment with several rooms, which he could now furnish. With some pride—and his usual tactlessness—he wrote to Gaufridy that hav ing come out of Charenton wretched and almost naked he now possessed over eight suits, good linen, and a good kitchen with enough wine in the cellar. All doors stood open to him; he was a welcome visitor in all the theaters, enjoyed a literary reputation, and his life was brightened by the faithful care of his tireless companion. Madame Quesnet, whom he soon only called “La Sensible, had already become totally indispensable to him. Since he now regarded himself as an old man who needed to be looked after, he was careful not to make any scenes or to hurt her by any unkindness. After all, she was his voluntary companion, not his legally bound wife; she could have left him at any time, and that he wanted to avoid at all costs. In any case, as he assured Gaufridy, he was now enjoying peace of mind, and stoic phi losophy supplied all the comfort he needed. He was no longer engaging in "impure pleasures. All that sort of thing now only disgusted him. His passionate disposition had faded, and he had hardly any physical strength left. However, the books he wrote in the following years—in par ticular Justine and Juliette—proved that de Sade’s sexual drive was by no means dead. He nevertheless found a far greater satisfaction in inventing and writing, and had really devoted himself utterly to becoming a real author. Although he had originally sympathized with the Revolution, and soon collaborated on a practical level in one of the Parisian sections, he also saw through it, and made increasingly skeptical and sarcastic comments about its ideals. He secretly despised the masses, still identified with the aristocracy, and wanted to keep both his privileges and his château. At the end of 1791 he wrote a statement on his attitude to the Revolution: I am on neither side, but accept the best ideas of both. I am anti-Jacobin; I hate them to the death. I love the King, but I detest the old abuse of power. I love many of the articles of the Constitution, others re volt me: I would that the Nobility should be restored to their ancient glory, because to have stripped them of it has improved nothing: I would that the Kings were head of the Nation: I do not want a National Assembly, but two chambers, as in England, which leaves the King a mitigated power, balanced by the op Printing. Woodcut, late eighteenth century. position of two orders within the nation. The third order, the clergy, is superfluous. That is what I believe. So what am I aristocrat or democrat? You can call me what you will, for I do not know. De Sade does not seem to have had much to say for equality either. Like most French intellectuals before 1789, he was con vinced of the advantages of the English parliamentary system, influenced as they were by Voltaire’s and Rousseau’s famous re ports. He obviously took care not to air such views publicly, preferring to howl with the wolves when expected. Only once did he expressly refer to his necessarily changeable attitude. After the royal family’s unsuccessful attempt to escape in June 1791, public opinion became noticeably more radical. The Jacobins dominated events, while the Girondists drifted more and more into the background. De Sade had already tried to make himself useful in the revolutionary council of his Section of Paris—known as the Section des Piques or the Section de la Vendôme—and on September 3, 1792, he was elected secretary of the Section. It was an influential position, and also afforded him considerable personal security. As a member of the fourth battalion of the fifth legion of the National Guard, he also had to perform frequent guard duties. The guillotine began to work more and more menacingly; Danton and Marat daily incited the people against the royal family, the nobility, and the clergy. The provinces were in a state of almost complete chaos, with plunder and arson constantly increasing. Towards the end of September 1792, a mob broke into de Sade’s château at La Coste, not only looting all the con tents, but senselessly and wildly demolishing it as well; furniture was thrown out of the windows, everything of no use was smashed to pieces, and the rest was set on fire. All that remained was the ivy-covered ruin we can still see today. Whatever properties survived this devastation were confiscated by the governing body of the Département, as was the fate of all aristocratic estates. In spite of this de Sade was honored when shortly afterwards he was appointed to serve as a judge of his Section, and was then even elected Chairman. He had already done some very useful work to improve the conditions in public hospitals. His demand for better equipment had resulted in more than a thousand new beds being installed, so that the patients no longer had to sleep three to a bed. The Section even decided to have several of his speeches printed and distributed throughout the country. These included a long discourse entitled Idée sur le mode de la sanction des lois (Consideration of how to support legislation by sanctions), which was followed later by a pathetic obituary on the murdered Marat. As Chairman of the tribunal, he once received a petition against Madame de Montreuil and her husband. He could so easily have pronounced the death sentence (a mere formality) against alleged "enemies of the Republic”; but he chose to postpone the action as long as possible, thus giving this woman—whom he hated more than anyone in the world, since it was chiefly because of her that he had spent seventeen years behind prison bars- enough time to flee the country. This was unquestionably an act of the greatest generosity, though de Sade was probably also influenced by his lack of illusions about the new state of affairs, and deeply abhorred the now daily savage bloodshed. His “sadism’ was of a different sort. What de Sade was observing with such gloomy interest at this time was the jubilant pleasure of the crowds round the guillotine; the myriad screams of joy every time a bleeding head was held up and shown to the mob; the eager, breathless tension each time a new victim climbed or was pushed up the wooden steps; the cynical jokes of the executioners as they pulled up the skirts of the bound women; the surging throngs round the headless corpses. This horror, and worse, is found in scarcely any of the countless histories of the course of the Revolution up to the end of the Reign of Terror, for it would upset the generally idealized picture we are used to or would like to have of this period. Here, as in the often even worse atrocities in the provinces where not a few of the revolutionary leaders behaved like com pletely unrestrained sadists—Citoyen Sade was able to study mass sadism, that terrifying lust for blood and death, so long curbed and suppressed, which then burst out like a suddenly released natural instinct. In La Nouvelle Justine he wrote: “The Portias and Cornelias wept over the tragedies of Sophocles, yet they eagerly took their places in the Roman circus to enjoy the slaughter of the Christians. Nero could give a remarkable performance as Oedipus, and shortly after take great pleasure in watching the tender bosom of Cecilia or the well-formed buttocks of Agatha being lacerated. Such spectacles, once absolutely worthy of a great nation, we now find repugnant, because our senses are no longer used to them. Would we not soon find tragedies boring, and trample each other to death to get a seat at one of those circuses: Where so many other hidden atrocities are permitted, it would be totally incomprehensible to have any dubious feelings about such spectacles as these. Who knows, by allowing such human cruelty to pass for amusement, might we not also be quenching the stimulus for much worse crimes? This is an indication of one of de Sade’s deepest thoughts, a very original interpretation of an ancient institution, totally ne glected by historians, which we today can no longer understand because of its repulsive cruelty. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="12">
                <head type="chapter">SAVED FROM THE GUILLOTINE</head>
                <p>DE SADE frequently had to defend his mildness in cases against alleged enemies of the Republic—for the most part all innocent —and finally had to relinquish his post as Chairman to a more efficient” judge. From then on he was no longer considered re- liable, and many small signs made him aware of this. On the laughable charge of having applied for service in the Royal Guard, he was suddenly arrested just before midnight on December 8, 1793, in the presence of Madame Quesnet, in his small house in the Rue Neuve-des-Mathurins. The charge cited the “constitutional guard” which the legislative assembly had approved two years previously to replace the King’s Swiss Guard. It has, however, long since been proven that this was merely a convenient excuse to dispose of de Sade as a member of a conspicuous atheist group which had aroused Robespierre’s increasing wrath. De Sade was first taken to the Madelonettes Prison, which had formerly been a convent for the correction of prostitutes. He at once wrote an imploring letter to his citizen comrades of the Section des Piques, saying among other things: “Is it possible that the nation that tore the chains from me should now put them back on again after three years?” But his former comrades did not dare to say a word in favor of the accused. The Jacobin terror was noticeably stifling all revolutionary courage among the citizens; no one felt safe, and a paralyzing atmosphere of fear and distrust was rapidly spreading. From dawn to dusk the carts of offenders condemned by the tribunals rolled through the city. On January 13, 1794, de Sade was transferred to the Carmelite Convent (later a women’s prison where, in World War I, Mata Hari was held on charges of espionage), but he was soon moved again, because of over-crowding, to the Maison de Saint-Lazare in the village of Pipcus. Fortunately for him, he fell ill and had to be taken to a private hospital run by the resourceful Citoyen Coignart. At this equally sinister and remarkable time, there were several of these private sanitoriums for sick or debilitated prisoners in Paris; the owners or leaseholders had to pay large bribes to important functionaries, and consequently charged their patients exorbitant fees. In retur, the patients could in general feel safe there for as long as they were recovering from their supposed illness. Where de Sade got the money from is not known. La Sensible probably came to his assistance as she had so often before now and was to do in the future. On July 27, three dozen prisoners from Saint-Lazare were summoned before the tribunal and the next day, after spending the night in the Conciergerie, the so-called asylum of the condemned,” were taken to the guillotine. Citoyen Sade was also on this list, but he, of course, could not be found. At the time the guillotine was set up very near Pipcus, and the victims were buried in a mass grave in the garden of the Maison Coignart—before the eyes of the understandably scarcely edified patients, who owed their own lives only to money and public corruption. The very next day, on July 28, Robespierre, Saint Just, and twenty other followers of Robespierre, were executed to the frenetic jubilation of the entire population. The Terror was broken. Paris could breathe again, and the tide turned, setting the scene that was eventually to make Napoleon the hero of the nation. The Section des Piques was now suddenly unanimously pre pared to listen to Citoyen Sade’s renewed petition, and he was rehabilitated as a good and reliable patriot: However, owing to the general confusion after the fall of the extremists, this took several months to effect, and de Sade was finally released by an order of the Committee of General Security on October 15. After another ten months' detention, one can understand him writing: “My imprisonment by the Republic with the guillotine before my very eyes was a hundred times worse than all the Bastilles in the world! The 1789 Revolution had freed de Sade as it had all the prisoners jailed without trial under the ancien régime. But the freedom which this Revolution had preached, together with equality and fraternity, as a national ideal, was not what de Sade understood by freedom—liberation from the moral tyranny of unnatural prejudices. Besides, the new rulers of France had shed far more blood than the kings had done in centuries. Added to this, the new freedom was completely insecure; it was enough to denounce any unpopular person as an enemy of freedom for him to be delivered after a brief show trial to the guillotine. In spite of this, de Sade had at first undoubtedly set great hopes on the republican revolution. Even his bitter experiences in prison under the Reign of Terror did not prevent him from summoning re newed courage after the fall of the Jacobins. Pehaps reason was at last entering the Republic; perhaps there was now some purpose in publishing suggestions for a new legislation and the rationalization of State institutions. From such considerations derived the now famous pamphlet: Français, encore un effort, si vous voulez être Republicains (Frenchman, one more effort, if you want to be Republicans), written in 1795. Since it apparently met with no official interest at the time, he later published it in La Philosophie dans le boudoir. In this he declared at the beginning: I admit that there cannot be as many laws as there are people; but the laws can be mild and limited in number so that all people, regardless of their disposition, can easily follow them. I would also demand that these laws be so constituted as to apply to the different dispositions. The spirit of the law should indicate more or less what should be attained with regard to the individual. It is clear that there are virtues which some people cannot fulfill, just as there are remedies which are not suited to all tempera ments. Would it not be the height of injustice to aim the law against those who cannot possibly follow it? The Marquis then declared his unconditional opposition to the death sentence, and divided the crimes he considered it justifiable to find in a legitimate republic into four categories: slander, theft, sexual immorality, and murder. He asked whether these deeds, in the days of royalty mostly punishable with the death sentence, should also be so severely punished in a republican state. In particular, where so-called sexual immorality is concerned we should listen only to the voice of Nature, for “the real crime consists in resisting and fighting the tendencies which Nature has endowed us with.” He then continued: We must strive to enable the citizens to indulge in the object of their lust. No one should ever be hindered in this, for no other passion in man is so dependent on complete, unrestricted freedom. Large, clean, and sanitary buildings should be erected in the towns, and they must be assured of complete security. Both sexes of all ages will be offered there, capable of satisfying any type of sexual desire. Unconditional submission will be the principle for all the inmates of these houses. I must explain how this subordination does not contradict the principles of republicanism. ... If, as stated, precisely this passion is dependent on complete freedom, then on the other hand no passion is as despotic as this one.... This is because a human being loves to command, to demand obedience, and to be surrounded by slaves who must satisfy him. The citizen will only be tempted to turn against the objects of his environment and consequently threaten the structure of the state if he is not allowed the possibility to indulge that portion of tyranny which nature has given him. If you wish to avoid this danger, then you must give free rein to those tyrannical drives which are stronger than the will. De Sade was not the only one to put forward proposals for sexual reforms. The government was chiefly concerned with ending the widespread prostitution and controlling the general state of excessive immorality throughout the country, but especially in Paris. Even de Sade’s malicious enemy, Restif de la Bretonne, who had a unique knowledge of prostitution in Paris at the time, in 1795 submitted a comprehensive plan to the government proposing the state management of brothels. Like countless other projects put forward in this transitional phase, it was ignored. The frank presentation of sexual excesses had always figured in French literature, and anyone who knows of Restif de la Bretonne and the somewhat earlier Brantôme and Laclos, will find many things in de Sade’s works in no way so novel or shocking as is often claimed. Sexual matters occupied only a part of the new legislation for all possible crimes mentioned by de Sade in his pamphlet, but one cannot help suspecting that everything else is more or less a camouflage. The way he indirectly returns, despite digressions, to his idée fixe demonstrates unequivocally the monomania of this strange writer who could never distinguish between illusion and reality. In addition to his material distress, the winter of 1794/5 was bitterly cold; wood was virtually unobtainable, and even the ink froze overnight. De Sade did succeed in persuading Gaufridy to ﻿108 sell his country house at Saumane, though the prices at the time were very low; he was then able to take Madame Quesnet for a few weeks to the country. There he finished the manuscript for his long novel Aline et Valcour, which was eventually published at the end of August that year. In October 1796, he sold the château at La Coste, together with whatever was left of the estate, to the influential deputy, Rovère. He himself, however, received little from these transactions, because his ex-wife—in the interests of her children—did everything in her power to procure as much as possible for herself. This was within her rights according to the mutually agreed divorce settlement. Like her mother earlier, she seems to have won over the notary, Gaufridy, who consequently gave false information to his friend and client. A subsequent in quiry was later to reveal this man’s totally chaotic methods of accounting. In his favor, it must also be admitted that de Sade was chronically suspicious, and demanded money in a violently aggressive manner even when he knew very well that it was impossible. “Money, money, money, for heaven’s sake send me some more money"—this was nearly always the closing sentence of his letters. An extended journey to Provence with Madame Quesnet in the spring of 1797 led to no improvement of the situation. Since one of his sons had emigrated at the beginning of the Reign of Terror, de Sade’s name was also put on the much feared list of emigrés. Although he filed numerous declarations proving that he had never left France, he had to expect that all his remaining estates would be sequestered. His request to be struck from the list of emigrés constantly came up against bureaucratic quibbles and the confusion reigning in the administrative authorities. He was placed under police supervision until the summer of 1798, and the case was only finally cleared at his death. That year also saw the publication of his great double novel, La Nouvelle Justine on Les Malheurs de la vertu, suivie de l'his toire de Juliette, sa soeur (The New Justine or the Misfortunes of Virtue, followed by the Story of Juliette, her Sister). It was as a result of this work, which established his fame and his much quoted depravity, that he incurred the lasting hatred of bourgeois society and persecution up to the present day. La Nouvelle Justine contained far more sexual descriptions than the two previous versions. In this havoc of virtue, the heroine is constantly raped, and becomes the victim of the most depraved orgies despite her pure heart and virtuous character. In the companion novel the heroine is her sister, Juliette, for whom crime and lust are synonymous. De Sade’s new publisher—the previous one having been guillotined in the meantime—had no doubt also insisted on the books being “well peppered” and the author again complied so that the devil himself would have been poisoned. It must be remembered that de Sade at fifty-five, though not old, had in his own sexual life become mellow and almost in different. Even with La Sensible there was no erotic passion, and some writers even doubt that they ever lived together as man and wife. Ever since leaving prison, he had been enormously corpulent and wheezing with asthma, and lacked any attraction whatever for the opposite sex. Otherwise he could have freely indulged in any perversions he liked in Paris in the years leading up to Napoleon’s coup d’état. The number of prostitutes had more than doubled since the Revolution; Europe had never seen the like of what was happening in the Palais-Royal, the Champs Elysées and the Boulevard du Temple, where flocks of girls and boys between seven and fourteen years old were offering them selves for prostitution. This was due largely to the economic misery of the time. Famine was a frequent occurrence in Paris, where even the most vital necessities of life were all but unattain able. The revolutionary police no longer paid any attention to prostitution, so had the Marquis wanted to lead a dissolute life there would have been no dangers or restrictions at all. But this was not the case, for Citoyen Sade no longer had any practical needs of this kind. But he nevertheless realized that his novels would have to be extremely well spiced if they were to find any buyers, for which reason he crammed his books, particularly the Histoire de Juliette, with enough material for half a dozen novels. His income from these two novels was swallowed up by urgent credit and promissory notes; he had also become involved in the purchase of several dubious properties to make up for the estates he had previously sold very much below their true value. Un fortunately, his desperate financial situation scarcely changed at all. All attempts at producing another successful play failed, either because the author no longer appealed to the new tastes, or because he lacked the contacts so vital in Parisian society. In the winter of 1798, life in Paris became so impossible that he moved out to Versailles, where living was a little cheaper. He lived in an attic with Madame Quesnet’s son; they fed themselves on carrots and beans, and warmed themselves by burning brush wood in a stove whenever they could afford it. Their misery was so appalling that when Madame Quesnet came to see them, she used to bring food from her friends' tables in her pocket. On February 13, 1799, he wrote to his negligent notary friend, Gau fridy: ... as an assistant at the Versailles Theatre I earn forty sous a day, with which I also try to feed the boy. That is nothing compared to the worries, afflictions, and expenses of his mother, who is out every day in this awful weather begging creditors for respite. This woman is truly an angel. She has been sent to me from heaven that I be not completely destroyed by my enemies. At the beginning of December 1799 his play Oxtiern was pro duced in the theater of the Versailles dramatic society, with de Sade himself in the lead. Only a couple of months later Madame Quesnet was forced to look for work in Paris, and the destitute Marquis was able to avoid starvation only by retreating to the hospital in Versailles where he was admitted out of pity, given a bed for a while, and fed with “the soup of the poor.” He had reached the climax of poverty and misery. Another very dark cloud, which was to have dire consequences for him, also arose on the horizon. On November 9, 1799, the government had been overthrown and Napoleon became First Consul and virtual dictator of France. He was determined to put an end to the dissolute conditions in the country, to the extent of reinforcing moral norms at the point of the bayonet. With foresight, de Sade’s publisher had deemed it prudent to publish Justine et Juliette anonymously, but even so it rapidly became ap parent that de Sade still had a number of old enemies who had been harboring their moral hatred for him over the years. In the Amis des Lois newspaper, a certain Monsieur Paulthier pub lished the following report: “As we have heard, de Sade is dead. The mere name of that notorious writer exhales a corpse-like odor which stifles virtue and inspires loathing, for the man is the author of Justine ou Les Malheurs de la vertu. The most depraved of hearts, the most degraded of minds, the most fantastically obscene of imaginations could invent nothing which would so outrage reason, modesty, and humanity. This work is as dangerous as the Royalist paper Le Necessaire, because if bravery founds republics, then good morals preserves them, but the ruin of the latter always drags down empires. De Sade’s rejoinder was published three weeks later in the same paper: "No, I am not dead, and I would like to imprint the ir refutable proof of my existence on your back with a very rough stick. I would certainly do so, did I not fear the contagious miasma of your stenching corpse. But when all is said and done, scorn is the only weapon that a decent man such as I need use to repel the insinuations of a blockhead like yourself. It is not true that I am the author of Justine! To any other than an idiot such as you I might take the trouble to prove this, but what emerges from your stinking mouth is so stupid that refutation would dishonor more than accusation. De Sade thus suddenly denied that he was the author and creator of his major work, which seems astonishing for the man who had once written in the Bastille: “My imagination and way of life ... are of unprecedented impetuosity. I am a fanatical atheist. In one word, that is how I am: kill me or take me as I am, you will never be able to change me. For the first time since the downfall of the ancien régime, the author of La Nouvelle Justine again heard murmurs of ir reconcilable hatred against him and his work. But this time it came from the French bourgeoisie, which finally felt secure under the protection of the bayonet and forcibly asserted its true men tality. As might have been expected, the new class proved itself to be far more intolerant than the old aristocracy had been, and created an ideological virtue out of universal hypocrisy. This new France did not hesitate to make Citoyen Sade the outcast of morality, and found its best ally in the newly established ﻿116 clergy. A few years later, Bonaparte was even to make his official peace with the Pope. The ancien régime alliance between the aristocracy and the clergy as the privileged classes was now re placed by that of the bourgeoisie and the Church. The Roman Church has often managed to switch neatly in this way—in most cases with astonishing success. De Sade must have been very well aware of the dangerous opposition looming up against him, for he followed the progress of public affairs with skeptical interest. If we accept that he had supplied the over-large quota of pornographic ingredients only at his publisher's insistence, and for financial reasons, it now seemed all the more appropriate that his name had not been mentioned, since he could now simply deny authorship of the books in question. There was only one person who did know the truth—his publisher, Nicolas Massé. On March 6, 1801, while de Sade was in Massé’s office on business matters, the police suddenly appeared and confiscated several of his manuscripts as well as a number of volumes of Justine and Juliette with the author’s handwritten corrections. They also searched his house and claimed to have found a secret cabinet containing further incriminating objects. Both publisher and author were arrested, though the former was released the following day after revealing the location of his secret storehouse containing all unsold copies of de Sade’s books. According to Gilbert Lely's investigations, there can be no doubt that under pressure the publisher betrayed his author to save his own skin. Massé remained a free man and continued to run his business, whereas de Sade never knew freedom again in the remaining thirteen years of his life. From later documents it can be seen that de Sade’s family fully agreed with his detention "for the sake of the family honor,” and accepted the confiscation of the obscene books and writings. As before, they had to pay for his keep. Both his sons were serving in Napoleon’s army and were ambitious. They had long con sidered their father’s literary activities both extremely embarrass ing and damaging to the family reputation. They also feared that they might lose some of their income through their father's gifts to his new companion, Madame Quesnet. The age of the lettres de cachet was clearly over, but Fouché, Napoleon’s all-powerful Minister of Police, had discovered a far easier method of removing unpopular persons from public life; they were declared by the administrative bodies to be mentally sick and dangerous to the community, and interned without the courts being troubled or public opinion even being stirred up. It was long believed that de Sade had been arrested and interned for life on account of a pamphlet attributed to him entitled Zoloé et ses deux acolytes, which savagely satirized the private life of Napoleon’s wife, Josephine. As a result of Gilbert Lely's conscientious research, this motive now seems highly doubtful. It cannot, however, be totally disregarded, for there is still the decree signed by Napoleon in 1812 to the effect that de Sade was to remain in prison. The Emperor obviously had his reasons for re fusing de Sade's numerous petitions, but these he kept to himself. De Sade spent almost a year in the Sainte Pélagie State Prison, apart from the weeks he was incarcerated in the infamous Bicêtre Prison on account of his allegedly “outrageous behavior” towards other prisoners. His family—probably somewhat guilt-ridden finally succeeded, by means of petitions and mediation, in getting the now sixty-three-year-old Marquis admitted as a special patient to the well-known Saint-Maurice asylum at Charenton. There Joseph Fouché. they also had to meet the bill for his living costs, amounting to three thousand francs a year; but for this the Marquis was given privileges similar to those he had received in the Bastille. The director of the asylum, Monsieur de Coulmier, was given detailed ﻿120 reports beforehand about the dangerousness of the new patient, and had to take special security measures to prevent any possible escape by the Marquis. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="13">
                <head type="chapter">THE THEATER IN THE ASYLUM</head>
                <p>ON APRIL 27, 1803, de Sade was taken under police escort from the Bicêtre to Charenton, and handed over to Monsieur de Coulmier. It was an ironic reunion after fourteen years; for it was here that de Sade had been brought a short time before the storming of the Bastille, and had had to wait for almost a year under the mild rule of the Brothers of Mercy before finally being granted his freedom. The monks had long since moved out of the great house, which had been taken over by a purely civil administration. Monsieur de Coulmier, who received the old Marquis, was quite willing to stretch the regulations as much as possible to ease the fate of this strange man who was being un lawfully interned there. De Sade was given a small apartment on the second story of the right wing, which he was soon allowed to furnish with his own things. After a while, he had even amassed a library of nearly three hundred books. For years he was per mitted to take as many walks as he wished in the spacious grounds of the asylum, and even succeeded in getting permission for Ma dame Quesnet to live several months of the year there with him. She used to spend the days writing down whatever he dictated, and the evenings reading aloud to him for hours on end. He was particularly thankful for this assistance, for the eye disease he had contracted during his years in the Bastille had steadily wors ened, to the extent that he sometimes feared that he would lose his sight altogether. This time, after a brief period of obstinacy and sudden fits of anger, de Sade acclimatized himself extraordinarily quickly to his fate, which after all the unhappy ups and downs of his life he now accepted as a destiny from which a man like him could never escape. Because he had drawn back the curtain from man's true nature and his all-dominating instinct, and had re vealed the illusion of happiness and the absurdity of a moral system which referred to God and denied the incorrigible nature of man, he had become intolerable for any regime, and even dangerous for otherwise totally antithetical ideologies. He knew very well that he would never be forgiven: he had been perse- cuted by Louis XV, Louis XVI, and Robespierre, and he was now being persecuted by Napoleon. Nothing could be unsaid or undone; he probably smiled to himself at his denial of the author ship of Justine and Juliette, though he still held to it for another few years to come. In Paris alone, the Revolution had caused tens of thousands to die by the guillotine, until even Paris had had enough of the diversion. Napoleon was to inflict his faithful France with the greatest shedding of blood in its entire history. More than a dozen age-groups were systematically eliminated, and by the end Na poleon was fighting with an army of invalids and youths. How ever, when his body was brought from St. Helena to France, the people knelt along the roadside to see his coffin on the gun carriage pass on its way to Paris. In spite of police confiscations, de Sade's prohibited books still continued to be printed, though in what quantities is naturally not known, since no records were kept. For quite a while he was considered to be an ordinary pornographer; in fact, this image was vigorously projected to act as a camouflage and to give the books an appearance of harmlessness. That this did not succeed was due to the evil literary minds who began to discover a totally unknown sphere in his work. In Charenton the Marquis, always a dark experimenter, em barked on his last fantastic research into the dark sides of the human mind. With the permission of the tolerant director, Coul mier, de Sade was allowed to stage theatrical performances in this strange institution, before an audience including many in terested Parisians. The project clearly gave the theater-loving Marquis considerable personal satisfaction. He obviously tended to choose his own plays which had all been turned down by pro fessional groups apart from the Comédie Française. He found enough suitable actors among the male and female patients of Charenton, who were only too glad to be snatched for a while from the monotonous flow of institutional life. Naturally enough, he could use only patients who were not serious cases, but then there were an outstandingly large number of people interned there solely for the convenience of their families, who had of course to pay the fees. So here at long last the Marquis could properly indulge his passion for the theater, hold rehearsals to his heart's content, have costumes made and scenery painted. What may have been lacking in elegance, de Sade more than compensated for by his originality. Before the premiere he sent invitations to the large circle of ac quaintances he had met during his years of freedom with Madame Quesnet, asking how many tickets he should send. Instead of charging a definite admission price, he proposed a kind of dona tion for the benefit of the poor of Charenton. The asylum theatre at Charenton was a sensation among certain elements of Parisian society: ladies of the Court, bankers, salon habitués, and above all theater personalities, including the most famous actresses, all thronged there. De Sade was even occasionally permitted to put on concerts and ballets, and to have his guests of honor to dine in his rooms. Nearly one hundred and fifty years after his death, the Berlin Schiller-Theater staged a very successful production of a play by Peter Weiss called The Persecution and Murder of Jean Paul Marat presented by the theater group of the hospice of Charen ton under the direction of Monsieur de Sade. For the first time de Sade stood as an historical figure on the stage, and within the period of his life which coincided with the dawn of the revolution ary era; the era beginning with an oath in a ballroom in 1789 and ending with the battle of Waterloo in 1815. De Sade can no more be understood apart from the spirit of this era, than the period itself can be understood without the deep in sight into the connections between cruelty and lust which he revealed. Peter Weiss, it must be said, made liberal use of the author's right to freedom of invention, and it would be totally superfluous to argue whether he has portrayed de Sade properly or without distortion. To complaints from various Prefects and Ministers, Coulmier replied that the performances were taking place with his express approval and acknowledged support. He could not find enough praise for de Sade’s idea of acting plays with the mentally sick, for it had turned out to be the best possible cure for many of his patients. When the Minister then retorted with sharp in tructions that de Sade was to be kept in solitary confinement and forbidden any possibility of writing or doing anything, Coulmier courageously replied that if the man was so dangerous, then he should be removed elsewhere, for he felt it was humiliating to act as jailer to a man whom he had come to esteem. For a long time de Sade had given no cause for complaint, behaved irre proachably, and suffered only from the fact that his relations gave him virtually no money, while they themselves profited freely from his imprisonment. Both his sons were officers in Napoleon’s army, and married about this time. A descendant of the family of the elder son was Adheaume de Chevigné, Proust’s model for the Duchesse de Guermantes. The elder son was murdered by rebellious Neapoli tans in 1809. On July 7, 1810, de Sade’s ex-wife died at Echauf- four, the Montreuil family château in Normandy. She and de Sade had never met since her last visit to him in the Bastille, and he had never forgiven her for her carelessness in losing so many of his precious manuscripts. In contrast to this, it appears there was never the slightest cloud in his relationship with Madame Quesnet, despite the fact that the Marquis’ choleric temperament had not quite disappeared, even with the many years in Charen ton. After 1813, nothing more is heard of theatrical performances in Charenton; Coulmier probably had to give in to the strict ban imposed by the Minister of the Interior. This man, Monsieur de Montalivet, then suspected de Sade of knowing where the copper plates of Justine and Juliette were hidden, for new edi tions of these dangerous novels were constantly being printed and sold everywhere under the counter. He continually threatened to have de Sade transferred to Ham Fortress or to some other state prison. The theater had, however, by no means exhausted the Marquis' phenomenal need for activity. In his fourteen years in Charenton, he wrote about ten more volumes, including three novels of greatly differing quality. Of these, the supposed masterpiece, Les Journées de Florbelle ou La Nature dévoilée (Florbelle’s Days or Nature Unveiled), was discovered during one of the numerous police raids and destroyed. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="14">
                <head type="chapter">DAMNED FOR ALL ETERNITY</head>
                <p>HE WAS often denounced for working on yet another immoral or atheistic work. Napoleonic France abounded in spies, Charenton not excepted, and de Sade was not by any means the only victim of an administration which wished to avoid any court tribunals or supposed public disturbance. The same administrative author ity, the Paris Police Prefecture, under the direction of Fouché, then carried out a search of de Sade’s apartment, confiscating whatever writings appeared in any way suspicious, and burning on the spot anything they thought obscene. His younger son, Donatien Claude Armand, was also frequently called in to assist in these decisions. He was motivated solely by personal interests and the family honor, despised his father, and would gladly have burned every line he had ever written. De Sade was as powerless against such confiscations as Director Coulmier. It was impossible for him to hide anything; only Madame Quesnet may have been able to smuggle one or another manuscript out of the asylum, though this was strongly forbidden, and she might have forfeited her permission to visit him. At any event, works like Les Confessions, La Réfutation de Fénélon, Con rad on Le Jaloux en délire (Conrad or the Delirious Jealous Man), and Marcel ou le Cordelier (Marcel or the Cordelier) all either disappeared or were destroyed. Only the totally harmless novel La Marquise de Gange was issued anonymously by a Paris pub lisher in 1813. The royalties from this probably went to Madame ﻿128 Quesnet who had done so much for the prisoner not even sparing her own few possessions. De Sade therefore had to be constantly prepared for sudden checks and searches; he could never be sure that a book on which he had been working hard for months would not abruptly be torn away from him forever. These were obviously hellish condi tions for an author to work in, and the behavior of a despotic State that saw fit to deprive a man already illegally imprisoned of any means of legal redress if they considered it appropriate. After many futile petitions and protests against his illegal de tention in the first few years of his final internment, de Sade then concentrated his efforts solely on being allowed at least to remain in the relatively bearable asylum at Charenton. He realized that the ultimate decision on him had been made, and would not alter for the rest of his life. This knowledge did in fact have a certain settling effect on him and enabled him to treat all officials with cold disdain. To all appearances, he was once again both in speech and address the unapproachable mar quis of an old family. In the times of the ancien régime he had trusted in his social status so implicitly that it had taken him quite some time to realize that Madame de Montreuil was far more powerful than he, for all that she came from the dubious bourgeois nobility, simply because she had incomparably more money than her hated son-in-law. Napoleon created a new no bility, which the Bourbons to this day have not recognized, but he did not hesitate to take de Sade out of circulation. All systems of government and all classes were completely unanimous—and have remained so up to the present day—that de Sade must stay banned and in exile. Since it had not been possible to stop de Sade from profaning all moral taboos, he himself fell under a kind of taboo. The universal aversion to his name equals the disgust at eating horseflesh felt by untold millions of Christians for centuries, despite the fact that there was absolutely no reason able or logical argument against it. This form of defense is probably the most effective possible, for its forces even the righ teous to the conformism of silence. But his name itself was not concealed; it became instead the term for a repulsive perversion which made a hypocrite out of anyone who used it thoughtlessly. An analogy would be the case of Onan; the biblical figure him self meant something quite different by his action from what is now conveyed by the term “onanism.” Up to the present, no one has in fact dared to say what is sexually normal or not, or whether it is even possible to speak of either a sexual or a moral norm. It is astonishing that de Sade should have encountered such emotional opposition precisely in France, which throughout the centuries since it had achieved political stability had never been a prudish country. In French literature it has never harmed even famous writers, as for instance Mirabeau, Diderot, Beaumarchais, Gautier, or Verlaine, to mention but a few, if they occasionally turned their talents to pornography—if only for financial reasons. De Sade could therefore have pursued this métier without reprisals of any kind; but it was precisely this approach that he so despised. When he found himself removed from the active satisfaction of his abnormal sexuality, and from life, he saved himself by creating his own “artistic paradise.” Sitting in prison he wrote volume upon volume of his natural philosophy of sex, exposing the natural man” who raised even his most devious desires and pas sions to the level of a personal norm. One of the most frequent contradictions in de Sade is that this natural man was in no way to be understood as synonymous with a rational individual. But who are we to deny him his contradictions? Are there not even more contradictions in Rous seau or Diderot, not to speak of Montesquieu or Voltaire? It is thus the easiest thing in the world to dismiss de Sade as a man of unstable character, at times even of shocking charac terlessness. He lied at every opportunity, cheated, and practically never showed either pride or honest reliability. He was almost devoid of self-criticism, aware of faults only in other people, and showed little sympathy or gratitude. The impression he gives is anything but that of the exemplary French nobleman, though he considered himself an aristocrat and despised the lower classes -of course, under the Republic he was sometimes forced to say the opposite out of necessity. His attitude to money, economy, and all the practical aspects of life was nothing short of infantile. What we are used to calling a man’s character or disposition was still virtually unknown in eighteenth-century France. There are hundreds of examples of men of letters carrying on the most dubious affairs and exhibiting the most repugnant characters. For instance, Voltaire became a millionaire through usury, and Beau marchais even made money from the slave trade. On the other hand they were also philosophers. At that time in France this meant primarily to approach all matters and prob lems with reason—and to this day the French still use the phrase: Vous avez raison.” They preached progress, demanded a consti tutional state, and damned the privileges of the nobility and clergy, though these had in reality long since ceased to be justified. This all took place in the form of an intricate daily guerrilla warfare, in which the participants needed to be armed with mimicry, constant denial, and above all the protection of good connections. In other words, it was a certain capability of action within the limits of general corruption. Money was consequently far more important than character in this country which listened to even the most idealistic claims when they were presented with wit and intelligence. Seen in these terms, de Sade’s alleged weaknesses of character —apart from the really scandalous ones—can scarcely be held against him. He usually had to do or appear to do whatever seemed most likely to protect his precarious existence. For this reason, he denied being the author of his greatest and most dangerous book, unhesitatingly changed his opinions in the most humiliating and base fashion to gain his freedom, and occasionally even greeted the Archbishop of Paris, who was the spiritual over seer of Charenton, with a pious elegy—he, the atheist par ex cellence. In the latter instance he was probably in fact fulfilling a request of Monsieur de Coulmier, to whom he was too obligated to be able to refuse. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="15">
                <head type="chapter">DEATH IN CHARENTON</head>
                <p>IT was a hard blow for de Sade when Director Coulmier was dis missed after Napoleon’s downfall, and the lawyer Roulhac de Maupas, a favorite of the new Minister of the Interior in the re enthroned Bourbon regime, was appointed to replace him. At the beginning of September 1814, the new director made an urgent request to the Minister of the Interior that the aged de Sade should be removed from Charenton, as he could not be adequately guarded there. It was even more shocking that de Sade’s son refused to pay the outstanding bill for the Marquis' living expenses, amounting to 8,934 francs, even though he had illegally taken possession of most of his father’s property. The last reliable descriptions of the seventy-four-year-old Mar quis are those of a nineteen-year-old medical assistant, L. J. Ramon. He saw de Sade for the first time on the morning of November 11, 1814, and years later wrote this account of his impressions: “After this I frequently met him alone, walking with heavy, sluggish steps along the corridors leading to his rooms. He was very carelessly dressed, and I never noticed him talk to anyone he passed. He always answered my greeting with such frosty politeness that I never dared to start a conversation with him. At the time I had no idea that he was the author of Justine and Juliette; I just thought that he was an arrogant, sulky old tristocrat. By December I the badly asthmatic Marquis could no longer leave his bed and was given an attendant. The following day his son Donatien Claude Armand appeared at his bedside and per suaded de Sade to agree that the medical assistant should spend the night in his room. No one would believe that de Sade made his peace with the Church before he died, without Ramon’s very reliable evidence. When Ramon appeared to start his night duty, the priest suddenly emerged from the dying man’s room and seemed, if not exactly moved, at least very satisfied with his visit." The patient's panting and rattling increased as the evening wore on. Ramon several times gave him his sirup and herb tea, and had scarcely seated himself again after the last of these ministrations when de Sade breathed his last. It was then ten o’clock. The next day, December 3, at midday, the official decla ration of his death was read by the mayor in the presence of a commission. A few days later de Sade was buried—against his wishes, according to Catholic rites—in the cemetery at Charenton. De Sade’s will was made in 1806, and contained the following wishes: "I forbid my body to be opened on any pretext what- ever. I demand that it shall be left for forty-eight hours in an open wooden coffin in the room in which I die. Only after these forty-eight hours may the coffin be nailed down. During this time a message shall be sent as quickly as possible to Monsieur La Normand, wood merchant, of 101 Boulevard Egalité, Versailles, requesting him to come personally with his cart to remove my re mains to the wood on my land near Malmaison, in the parish of Emancé near Epernon. My body shall be buried without any cere mony in the first copse on the right-hand side, as seen from the direction of the old château. My grave shall be dug by the farmers of Malmaison under the surveillance of Monsieur La Normand, who shall not leave my body until it has been buried as I here describe. If Monsieur La Normand desires, those of my relations and friends who wish to show me this last mark of espect may attend, provided they do not wear mourning clothes. As soon as the grave is filled in, acorns should be planted over it, so that new trees will grow out of it later, and the wood will be as thick as it was before. All traces of my grave shall vanish from the face of the earth, as I flatter myself that my memory will vanish from the minds of men... Made at Charenton, Saint-Maurice, in a condition of sanity and health... D. A. F. Sade." Fifty years later, the same Dr. Ramon, by then himself an old man, wrote the following account of the subsequent fate of de Sade’s grave: “A few months later, though I am not sure of the exact date, the cemetery was being reorganized and a number of bodies, including de Sade’s remains, were exhumed. I made sure I was present, and acquired the Marquis’ skull. I was absolutely sure of its authenticity, for there were many others present who knew de Sade and his grave as well as I did. At home, just as I was on the point of treating the skull, I received a visit from a friend of mine, the famous phrenologist Spurzheim, who was a pupil of Gall’s. At his request I gave him the skull, which he promised to return to me shortly, together with several casts which he proposed to make immediately. But soon after that he made a number of lecture tours in England and Germany, and then suddenly died. I never saw the skull again. According to recent investigations, Spurzheim is thought to have gone to America as well, and probably left the skull there. Ramon concludes his gruesome report as follows: “However, in the few days that the skull was in my possession, I did manage to give it a close phrenological examination. The results were: a well-developed cranium (theosophy, good will); no notice able bulges on the temples (cruelty); no striking bulges behind or above the ears (irritability); a cerebellum of average dimensions, and no unusually large distance between the projections and depressions on the surface (abnormal sensuality). In a word, I would never have recognized the author of Justine and Juliette in the dignified, even patriarchal old man shuffling round Charenton, and having now studied his skull I would quite defi nitely acquit him of any accusation of having written those books. His skull resembled in every respect that of a clergyman." Ramon's last sentence seems particularly malicious, yet it also lights acutely upon one vital point. One has only to think of the unforgettable confessions of such holy men as Augustine or Saint Anthony, who were both haunted by severe sexual hallucinations. Gall is as little remembered today as his theory of phrenology, by which it was claimed that a person’s character could be indis putably established from the shape of his skull and the appear ance of his brain. This doctrine continued to hold considerable weight until the middle of the nineteenth century, when it was finally scientifically disproved. Memories of the Marquis de Sade were, however, not so successfully erased as he himself had willed. This man, the greatest of the damned of European literature, has his place of honor in the crypts of Parnassus, and still ranks as the classic "black” author par excellence. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="16">
                <head type="chapter">HIS WORKS AND THEIR CONSEQUENCES</head>
                <p>DE SADE’s most important surviving works are undoubtedly the two complementary novels Justine and Juliette in the third and last version of 1797, so futilely confiscated. The original edition comprised ten volumes, of which six were devoted to the story of Juliette. This does not mean that it was de Sade’s only important work, or that the others were more or less insignificant. There are reasons to suppose that Les 120 Journées de Sodome was per haps his greatest and most frightful masterpiece. Even the long lost manuscript published in 1937 by Maurice Heine, a prominent de Sade expert, is only the plan for the work, not the work itself. Another long novel, Aline et Valcour, is definitely important for anyone wanting to become acquainted with de Sade and his specu lative philosophy; surprisingly, the whole novel is extraordinarily inoffensive. Of the fifty other stories which he wrote in the Bas tille there are about a dozen successful and original pieces, some filled with a dry humor at times reminiscent of Rabelais. But his unique fame as a “black” novelist nevertheless remains cen tered on Justine and Juliette. There are four versions of the story of Justine. It was originally conceived as a short story and appeared in 1791 as a short novel entitled Justine ou les Malbeurs de la vertu. The final version. La Nouvelle Justine, was published only in 1797; its heroine has not unjustifiably been called a female Don Quixote fighting un flinchingly against the enemies of virtue, and failing dismally. Even in the second draft of 1791, Justine's martyrdom is por trayed with acute realism, but with scarcely any suggestive details; obscenity, in fact, is remarkably restricted. But in this in stance it was all the more effective because—in contrast to the final version, three times the length—Justine herself describes all the stages of her fate. It is a small, compact masterpiece, crushing in its inscrutable, piercing consistency. Towards the end of the book, the heroine herself gives the following brief summary of events: Under what fatal star must I have been born?’ I said to my self. As soon as I have made some virtuous resolution I am promptly swept away in another deluge of misfortune. How is it possible that this noble providence, which I have always extolled, should raise those who have violated and ruined me to the pin nacle of good fortune, while I am continually punished for my virtue? During my childhood, a money lender tried to persuade me to steal. I refused, and narrowly escaped being hanged on the gallows, but he grew rich. A couple of villains tried to rape me in a wood. Nothing happened to them, but I fell into the hands of a wicked marquis who practically beat me to death because I refused to help him poison his mother. I then tried to prevent a surgeon from committing an abominable crime, and as a reward was branded with the mark of a thief before being thrown out onto the street. I wanted to receive the Holy Sacra ment and to pray to the Almighty, by whom I had already been given so much suffering. The occasion on which I hoped to be forgiven and comforted in one of our most pure and holy sacra ments became instead the scene of my defloration and the most vile depravity sa pilgrimage monastery where four monks in dulge in the most disgusting orgies with kidnapped girls). The monster who defiled me subsequently ended up extremely suc cessful, whereas I suffered in misery. I wanted to help a poor man on the street, but he robbed me. I rushed to aid a man who had been attacked, but the villain made me turn a water wheel like an animal. Whenever I became too weak he showered me with blows. Yet fortune continued to favor him, while I all but paid with my life for the work I had been forced to do for him. A worthless woman attempted to incite me to a new crime, and again it was I who lost everything I possessed in my efforts to rescue her victim. This young man wanted to reward me by offering me his hand in marriage, but he died almost im mediately afterwards in my arms. I even risked the dangers of fire to rescue a stranger’s child—and here I am for the third time before the law. I implored the wretch who violated me for help; I had a wild hope that his heart would be moved by my misery, but he offered his assistance only at the price of further humiliations ... Oh, providence, must I now doubt your eternal justice? Would it have been worse if I had done as my perse cutors, and devoted myself totally to vice? There follows the recognition scene between the two sisters. Juliette’s friend, the powerful Monsieur de Colville, immediately intervenes on Justine’s behalf. On the king’s orders, all proceed ings against Justine are dropped and she is restored to freedom. In spite of this, she remains in a deep melancholy. One summer evening a violent storm breaks out. Juliette, who is frightened of storms, asks her sister to shut the window. Justine hurries to do so and is killed instantly by a flash of lightning. Suddenly Juliette’s eyes are opened, as if by a miracle: if her constantly virtuous sister should come to such a horrible end, what can she expect from the eternal judge after a life of unbelief and de bauchery? So Juliette enters a Carmelite convent and becomes an example of penitent austerity. In La Nouvelle Justine, the heroine herself no longer narrates her sufferings, whereas Juliette is written in the first person. In this version of Justine, however, there is no hint of sympathy or compassion for the heroine, who is dishonored much earlier than in the first version. This time there are not four but six monks dwelling in the infamous abbey, each having a harem of youths and girls at his disposal. Not only are the numbers of characters and orgies increased in the best-known scenes; Justine also has to endure three times as many torments and afflictions. Crime and vice lurk everywhere, and by the end Justine has done no less to satisfy the worst perversions and lusts than the most wicked character imaginable. The difference is that she has never felt the satisfaction, the malicious sensation of the willful sinner. Justine is understandably revolted at the end of Juliette’s ac count of her life. The latter then secretly decides, with the help of her guests, to get rid of the unbearably virtuous Justine as soon as possible. Just then a storm blows up, and they resolve to let a kind of ordeal decide Justine’s fate by sending her out of the house. Before she can reach the street, she is struck down by a flash of lightning and killed on the spot. They are all over joyed. Here is the indisputable proof of how providence rewards those who aspire to virtue! We shall have to forego a similar résumé of the Histoire de Juliette, not on moral grounds—whoever is susceptible in that direction should steer clear of the Marquis altogether—but be cause a summary, which must inevitably restrict itself to the superficial progress of events, runs precisely the risk from which this novel should be protected: that it should be understood merely as a catalogue of all conceivable pornographic activities. Practically everything that happens in this long novel is pre meditated and considered nationally. To disregard this aspect would be to deny the real worth of the book. What might be called Juliette’s philosophy of life (appropriately, perhaps, for a character who so totally embodies vice and cruel desires) fre quently assumes the most terrible, at times almost crushing, pro portions. It is de Sade's bitter pleading against those who deprived him of his freedom that is formulated here more emphatically, forcibly, and brilliantly than anywhere else. As already mentioned, he drew largely on actual contemporary incidents when writing his novels; but the skill with which he applied them and loaded them with atmosphere and tension is that of a considerable literary artist. After the death of their parents, who left the two daughters virtually penniless, Juliette strikes out—in contrast to Justine in the direction of vice, having previously been thoroughly cor rupted by the Abbess Delbène in the Panthémont convent where she was educated. There is a famous scene at the beginning, where a dissolute group climbs through a grave into the catacombs under the convent. Every night, orgies take place there with priests, monks, nuns, and pupils as participants. Without losing her vir ginity, Juliette takes part in a variety of the worst perversions. They dine naked at the most sumptuous banquets where they drink the finest wines of the land, and indulge in erotic diversions on the coffins of dead nuns. Suddenly a large owl flies through the catacombs, causing the candles to blow out, and they all flee. After several years of hard prostitution, Juliette becomes ac quainted with a very rich and influential libertine, Noirceuil. Though she satisfies him, he still wants to leave her immediately, because he admits to having ruined her parents, and is almost certainly guilty of having poisoned them too. But Juliette is only filled with wild admiration for the immensity of this unscrupulous crime, and Noirceuil for his part is delighted to have found an accomplice of equal rank at last. He installs her immediately in his luxurious house and one day introduces her to the most accomplished villain in the whole of France, the Minister of State, Saint-Fond. This man is very proud of the fact that he was responsible for landing more than twenty thousand inno cent people in prison by means of the royal lettres de cachet. At seventeen years of age, Juliette becomes the center of a circle of relentless vice which is beyond the power of the law. Saint Fond soon puts her in charge of his poison department, where she is responsible for disposing of about fifty troublesome people each year. By this time, Juliette has already discovered how much she is in her element with cruelty of all kinds, and how shallow life is for her without the pleasure of seeing others suffer. She considers it a sign of stupidity to conform to moral laws; these were after all only meant for the weak, whose irrevocable fate it was to be more or less willing victims. Her handsome, arro gant friend Saint-Fond seems to have endless powers of invention for new perversions and sensational orgies, as a result of which at least fifty young girls die every month. At the climax of one of the most repulsive orgies, he cries out jubilantly: “Je parricidais, j'incestais, j'assasinais, je prostituais et je sodomisais!” This prince of crime and satanic debauchery covers, needless to say, the fan tastic expenses of his private life from the public exchequer. Lady Clairwil, a woman with the most evil heart in the world, becomes Juliette’s best friend, and introduces her to the “Society of the Friends of Crime,” whose members obey strict rules, and con stantly have to prove themselves by committing inconceivable cruelties. Saint-Fond is so convinced of Juliette’s total nihilism that he one day tells her of his plan to reduce overpopulation in France by starving two-thirds of the inhabitants to death. When he sees Juliette turn pale for a moment, he rejects her con temptuously. Warned by Noirceuil, she has to leave Paris as quickly as possible. “Oh, fatal virtue, she cries. “Once again I was taken in by you for a moment. Never again shall I be found at the foot of your miserable altar. All virtue is throttled in me forever, for it leads nowhere but into a destructive world held together only by corruption.” At twenty-two, Juliette now has to start afresh in Angers. She is saved from her distress by the Count de Lorsange who marries her, only to be poisoned by her after a few years of dull married life. He leaves her an annuity of 50,000 livres, but, still afraid of persecution by Saint Fond, she flees to Italy. The description of her long travels through the many small states which then made up Italy almost constitutes a second novel within the novel, written in the style of contemporary travelogues. It is frequently clear that de Sade was drawing from his own experiences during his visits to Italy in 1773 and 1775. He uses his own impressions in the description of certain works of art and other objects of interest, as well as in the portrayal of cities and landscapes. The art of description is now universal, but in the eighteenth century and for the larger part of the nineteenth, things were quite different. The author’s intention was hardly to write a travel novel. He set his scene in Italy because he knew it intimately, not only topographically and artistically, but also from the point of view of manners and moral customs. He was acquainted with all the scandals and crimes that had occurred in the capital cities of the states: Turin, Rome, Naples, Parma, Lucca, Venice, and the several provincial capitals of the Duchy of Tuscany. De Sade praises one of his best informants by name in the novel. This was Giuseppe Iberti, who supplied him in particular with material about Rome, which he then had to pay for with four months imprisonment by the papal inquisition. Another of the Marquis' secret informants was one Mesny, the Duke of Florence’s personal physician. All in all, de Sade possessed first-class contemporary material, al together extremely well-suited to provide an appropriate back ground for his heroine Juliette the courtesan, lesbian, participant in all possible vices, orgies, atrocities, and endless crimes. On their journey through the Appennines, she and her com panions fall into the hands of a man-eating giant called Minski. He waylays travellers whom his cook then serves up as roasts or ies. They eat off "living tables,” the backs of girls kneeling on all fours, and then wipe their hands on the girls’ hair. While eating one particularly delicious dish, Juliette asks her giant host whether it is poultry or game, to which the jovial Minski replies that it is neither, but Juliette's own chambermaid. After the banquet, Minski—who in the meantime has fallen in love with Juliette —entertains his guests by feeding the wild animals in his den. Girls from the bandit's storeroom are thrown to the bears and lions. He also demonstrates his latest invention, a machine which can stab, decapitate, and hang sixteen people at the same time. Juliette escapes soon afterwards, having put a strong narcotic into Minski's chocolate. “One cannot kill such a monster, she says with admiration, but nevertheless takes all his gold and silver with her. In her honor, the Duke of Florence stages a performance of executions to a musical accompaniment, the heads falling in time to the music. In Rome, she enjoys the favor of the lesbian Princess Borghese, who has just realized the most passionate wish of her entire life; with the help of the Rome chief of police she set fire to all the thirty-seven hospitals in the city, killing about twenty thousand people. In Rome, Juliette also inspires the admiration of the atheistic Pope, who stages an orgy in St. Peter’s and celebrates black masses to oblige her. On the way to Naples, she is attacked by a band of robbers led by the widely feared brigand Brisa-Testa. Juliette recognizes his blood-thirsty wife as her old friend, Lady Clairwil, who is living there incestu ously with her brother. Together with Lady Clairwil and Princess Borghese, Juliette reaches the totally depraved kingdom of Naples. As a special attraction the king invites them to a performance of the Theater of Cruelties.” In each box there hang seven pictures of seven different methods of execution. A guest only has to press the required bell-push, and four burly hangmen on the stage immediately carry out the specific execution desired: burning, whipping, hanging, breaking on the wheel, impaling, decapitation, or quartering—almost one thousand two hundred victims are sacrificed at each performance. On an excursion to Mount Vesuvius, Juliette and Lady Clairwil pounce on Princess Bourg hese, tear off her clothes and throw her into the boiling crater. When this is followed by an eruption, Juliette makes the mock ing observation that Olympia is missing her clothes. Soon after wards Lady Clairwil is poisoned too. After sundry incidents, Juliette then moves with her poisoner friend, Durand, to Venice where they set up a brothel specializing in satisfying the most depraved desires of rich men and women. In this way, she in creases the vast fortune she has amassed in the course of her travels through Italy. However, when she refuses to supply poison for the Doge, the brothel is closed and half her fortune is confiscated. Juliette flees with the rest of her money to Lyons. In the mean time, her old patron Noirceuil has murdered the menacing Saint Fond, and soon celebrates a joyous reunion with Juliette. His first words to her are: *You find me a thousand times more depraved than when you left me! At the end of her story, Juliette breaks out with a veritable hymn in praise of vice: “That, dear friends, is the happy situation in which I now am. Yes, I admit I love crime passionately. It alone can stir my feelings, and I shall sing its praises until my dying day. Free from any religious fears, and safely protected from the law by my discretion and my wealth, there is no power, either divine or human, which dare oppose my desires. The past encourages me, the present electrifies me, and I have no fear of the future. So I have reason to hope that the rest of my life will be even more pleasurable than my youth. Nature only created man to conceive as much pleasure and enjoyment as the earth can offer. That is Nature’s most precious law, and will always be that of my heart. All the worse for the victims, without whom it would obviously not be possible. But without the sublime laws of balance, everything in the universe would be in danger. Nature is regenerated only by evil deeds, winning back again the ground on which virtue has robbed her. Let us therefore obey Nature by siding with evil. The only crime for which Nature would never forgive us would be resistance. Oh, my friends, let us all obey these principles, for only in realizing them can we ever experience the true source of human happiness. De Sade’s unconsciously anti-Rousseauian attitude is here clearly expressed as the victory of natural man over the retreating world of virtue—in other words, moral man. In de Sade's interpreta tion, Nature is equated with evil, though evil as a natural force is always despotic. As he explains elsewhere: There is no man who, when aroused, would not like to be a despot. If another man experiences as much pleasure as he is capable of, then his own pleasure, in that situation, seems to be diminished. By an extraordinary act of pride, to him all too logical, he would like to be the only person in the world capable of so intense an experience of pleasure. The idea that anyone else could experience the same pleasure degrades him to a level of equality that instantaneously destroys even the most unique de lights of despotism. It is also false to assume that one experiences pleasure merely by giving it to someone else. Only by humiliating others can man experience true excitement, like a nervous indi vidual who enjoys his powers through exercise. So he finally becomes a tyrant because it gives him the greatest scope for his egoism. In comparison to the whole, these details from the Histoire de Juliette are spotlights briefly illuminating a vast panorama. It is a quite unparalleled mass of material, acquiring through its sheer dimensions an almost hallucinatory power. The Marquis was certainly not primarily concerned to make his novel a work of art. Novels at that time were on the whole regarded as a light, entertaining genre, and as such were used by the literary talents of the eighteenth century to present ideas, problems, and trends in a manner easily understandable outside the narrow circle of the salons. Up to 1789, this was found above all in the informative, liberal wealth of thought of the Encyclo pédie. This didactic tendency is found in almost all French novels towards the end of the ancien régime; they are novels with a purpose, and authors never dealt with themes in any way de grading. The Revolution gave birth to no great literary era— in fact the years between 1789 and 1815 can more aptly be termed a period of stagnation or even of decline. Only with the restoration of the Bourbons in 1815 did literature begin to revive. The common accusation that de Sade's novels are unartistic therefore bypasses their inherent meaning. They are obviously novels with a purpose; in fact there is scarcely a page on which the Marquis does not proclaim his message. He fulfilled his astute publisher’s request for liberal spicing; not so much with an appropriate vocabulary as with an overloading of obscene epi sodes and anecdotes of sex, blood, and cruelty. To read the Story of Juliette in an unabridged edition would certainly be a very laborious task for the modern reader. One can all too easily understand the disappointment of countless readers, who expect sheer pornography, and instead find themselves con fronted with a totally unknown world devoid of all pleasure. However, even the 1797 edition of Juliette contained sixty-four illustrations of the kind commonly associated with pornographic literature. They were obviously commissioned by the publisher, who knew his customers’ tastes, and the relatively abundant illustrations must have offered some consolation to many dis appointed readers. Expert artists were probably too expensive for the publisher, so the illustrations are without exception inferior in quality, sketchily executed, and even clumsy. Whether they aroused de Sade’s criticism is not known. He himself at any rate was an extremely competent art critic, as can be seen from many of his notes, especially in his accounts of his journeys through Italy. Sex aside, the most important theme in the novel is de Sade's categorical atheism, as can be seen from the following statement in Juliette: "Oh you, whom it is claimed created the world and everything in it; you, of whom I have not the slightest conception; you. whom I know only know as the written word; of whom I know only what I have been told by others, who are always wrong; you strange, imaginary being called God, I declare openly and emphatically that I do not believe in you at all! I have the best of all reasons for this: that I could never perceive anything to convince me of your absurd existence. There is nothing in the whole universe to prove your presence. In La Nouvelle Justine, he deals similarly with his other enemy, Nature: “The more I try to discover her secrets, the more I am convinced that her sole interest is to do men harm. In everything she undertakes, she is always voracious, destructive, evil, incon sistent, and full of contradictions and disaster. She is constantly seeking new victims, and uses her creative power solely to fill the earth with blood, tears, and distress. Is she not always brandishing her whip over our heads? A contemporary philosopher has called himself Nature’s sweetheart. Well, my friend, I prefer to call her my executioner. You should observe and study this cruel Nature, and you will see that she is only fearful in order to destroy, that she achieves her aims by murder. Like the Mino taur, she feeds on misery and the destruction of human beings. De Sade’s atheism is absolute, and apparent in all his works. To a large extent, it is aimed chiefly at the Catholic Church, and in particular at the clergy of his time. In his youth de Sade had, after all, known a scarcely worthy representative of this body in his uncle and tutor, the Abbé de Sade. In addition there was the close alliance between Court and Church which existed in France up to the Revolution, making any open attack on ecclesias tical abuses a virtual impossibility. In this respect de Sade was considerably more radical and audacious than even the majority of encyclopaedists, though his long imprisonment in Vincennes and the Bastille never really gave him the chance to develop this attitude to religion. His irreconcilable hatred for religion stems from the time of the Arcueil affair, which ultimately became so exaggerated and dangerous for him precisely because he was ac cused of having intentionally violated the holiness of Easter. De Sade later extended his atheism to include a no less passionate hatred for the various substitute ideologies which sprang into being at the outbreak of the Revolution. It is no wonder that Robes pierre, the ideologist of the Terror, very soon became suspicious of this former aristocrat: for whatever other objections one may have against de Sade, he was undoubtedly bitterly opposed to any form of suppression or personal restraint, and never abandoned his anarchic individualism. He himself had caused the great tragic tension in his life by staying at the crossroads between belief in God and Nature; in the freedom of choice he always perceived the deceitful element in either alternative, and this only resulted in his being inde pendent of any decision and consequently led him to the other extreme of submission. It is understandable that this sad aspect of his life should have particularly fascinated Simone de Beauvoir and become the theme of her famous essay Faut-il brûler Sade: (Should we burn de Sade?). It is part of de Sade’s greatness that he portrays Nature as man's enemy, malicious and cruel; ﻿156 her creations are simultaneously her victims, which she devours indifferently and without feeling. For the thinking man, who refuses to acknowledge any metaphysical presence, yet as an emo tive being denies the sentimentalization of Nature, inevitably lands himself in a state of extreme loneliness. Such was the situa tion in which the aged de Sade found himself, clinging silently, without faith or hope, to a contemplative grief which none could share. How should we approach him or come to meet him? There will always be people who are not satisfied merely to know that there is a great writer called de Sade, whom it is, however, not advisable to read. In the long run it is embarrassing to speak on the one hand of an author's significance, and on the other hand not to be able to recommend his works. This is an obvious con tradiction in terms, and an attitude based equally on embarrass ment and hypocrisy. One fact can nevertheless be stated with absolute certainty, and that is that no one has ever been corrupted merely by reading Justine and Juliette. On the contrary, both novels have always tended to produce the same three reactions: disappointment for those expecting pornography, disgust for those unacquainted with the seamy sides of human nature, and lastly the joy of discovery for all those courageous minds who, as Baudelaire expressed it in “Le Voyage” (Les Fleurs du Mal), are willing to dive to the bottom of the deepest abyss, into the totally unknown, in order to discover something new. No reader of de Sade who takes the necessary trouble will find his efforts unre warded. No one has yet exceeded the abundance of opinions and insights contained in his works, and it is unlikely that anyone will ever attempt it in the future—for there can never be an other monomaniacal genius of the extreme originality of de Sade. The reader who is not deterred by any difficulty or verbosity will be rewarded for his toil by encountering one of the most complete autonomous worlds created by fantasy to be found in literature, with an utterly dreamlike quality contrasting so vividly with the appearance of the world of reality. Despite the pro fusion of characters, this is no comédie humaine as in Balzac; it is more like a comédie satanique des moeurs, which, having first revealed itself to the reader, then discloses a dark and terrifying magic. However, if the reader is moved, he can remind himself that this thousand-roomed torture chamber of sex could only derive from the imagination of a great writer propelled by suf- fering and dreams. Ever since his death de Sade has remained a unique event in the history of literature, and has formed the subject of endless sci entific investigations and sexual and literary research. The light ning of divine judgment which strikes Justine during the orgy in the catacombs, Juliette’s laughter on Mount Vesuvius, or the satanic majesty of evil in Saint-Fond are brilliant conceptions which will always bear witness to de Sade’s genius. De Sade’s works cannot be “recommended,” nor in fact do they need to be recommended. Each reader must discover them for himself and at his own risk. For de Sade, as he still exists with all his inconceivable hatred and delusions, is one of the greatest mysteries of Europe and hints at many closed dungeons in her civilization and way of thinking. “Do not love either the sun or the stars too much, but come, follow me down into the kingdom of darkness!" This admonition of Oreste in Goethe's Iphigenia might well serve as a motto for all the Marquis’ surviving works. It is obviously very important that de Sade’s works be translated as reliably as possible, and without any omissions—re gardless of where, in what quantities, or with what restrictions they are published. The translations that do exist are only partly satisfactory. Footnotes, comments, and explanations are essential; rstly because of the time gap between the eighteenth century and the present day, and secondly because without guidelines the reader cannot penetrate successfully into de Sade’s labyrinth, or comprehend the many contemporary details he includes. It remains only to glance briefly at some of the important works written about de Sade. Simone de Beauvoir’s essay has already been mentioned. Another brilliant essay was written by Maurice Blanchot. An equally important contribution to the modern image of de Sade is Guillaume Apollinaire’s long essay, which was originally the introduction to a single volume of selec tions from de Sade’s works published for a book collector’s circle in 1909. After World War I, this evaluation of de Sade was taken up by the Surrealists led by André Breton, who placed him alongside Lautreamont in the pantheon of the great precursors of their movement. Pierre Klossowski made the strange confession that de Sade was “son prochain” (his brother). There is also Geoffrey Gorer’s extremely intelligent and balanced biography The Revolutionary Ideas of the Marquis de Sade. Another book to be quoted in this context is Norman Gear's The Divine Demon, but it is more strictly biographical and does not at tempt the level of interpretation attempted by Geoffrey Gorer. The most eminent contemporary de Sade expert is, of course, Gilbert Lely, to whose untiring investigations we owe so many important discoveries and explanations that he can easily be for given his somewhat gushing tone. These books stem without exception from the twentieth cen tury, or to be more precise, from the period since World War I. De Sade was, however, in no way forgotten during the nineteenth century. On the contrary, he exerted an extraordinary influence not only on the French, but also on the Russian, English, and Italian literatures of the time, as can be seen from Mario Praz's standard work, The Romantic Agony. Why then did no one in the nineteenth century, even in France, write anything specifically about de Sade? There were, of course, countless allusions to and remarks about him. For instance, his name appears frequently in the famous Goncourt diaries. But it remains a mystery why Charles Baudelaire, for example, who was more indebted to de Sade than to any other author (except perhaps Edgar Allen Poe), never actually made any direct mention—apart from a couple of short notes in his diary—of the man whose ideas he so suc cessfully advocated. Almost every second poem in Les Fleurs du Mal, and even its very title, betray de Sade’s influence, though this obviously does not in the least detract from the originality of a genius like Baudelaire. Almost the same can be said of Gustave Flaubert. For hours he would talk admiringly of de Sade, especially when he was working on La Tentation de Saint-Antoine. But he too never wrote anything about him. Why? The only viable explanation is to be found in the permanent condemnation of de Sade by the bourgeoisie, as a result of which even his name was so long tabooed. Because his name was later incorporated into the terminology of sexual research, de Sade himself was eventually identified solely as the discoverer of the sexual perversion known as sadism. While it is true that France after the end of the Napoleonic era was able to defend itself against political reaction far sooner than the rest of Europe, the decisive influence of the bourgeoisie undoubtedly introduced a definite moral reaction. Both Baudelaire and Flaubert had to answer before the law for certain offensive elements in their books. They were thus clearly not in a position to risk public advocacy of a reform of the general attitude to de Sade, whose books had been consistently prohibited by the police since 1801; no doubt they also feared the circulation of their own books would be adversely affected. They therefore took the only course open to them in the cir cumstances: they bought copies of the Marquis' works under the counter from antiquarian booksellers, studied them, and made use of whatever they felt appropriate. They never actually men tioned them directly, but, in the circumstances, who can blame them? On the other hand, the Marquis did in this way assemble a truly intellectual élite in support of his remaining works, which thus paradoxically achieved the improbable feat of surviving the bourgeois era unimpaired, to be accepted without dispute by the twentieth century. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="17">
                <head type="chapter">REFLECTIONS</head>
                <p>NICOLAS EDME RESTIF DE LA BRETONNE: No one has waxed more indignant over the works of the scandalous de Sade than myself ... This scoundrel represents the joys of love only in connection with torture, indeed even with the death of women. My aim is to write a book that is more savory than his .. -L'Anti-Justine, 1798. GUSTAVE FLAUBERT: What a lesson Lacenaire has administered morality through his philosophy—a wonderful, deep, bitter philosophy sui generis. How openly he scourged pitiful, prudish, dessicated morality. What hard blows he dealt it, how he dragged it through the mud! Such men delight me, as Nero delights or the Marquis de Sade ... Such monsters elucidate history for me, they are its supplement, its climax, its morality and its dessert. Believe me, they too are great men, they too are immortal... Alas my dear Ernest, speaking of Marquis de Sade, it has occurred to me: if you could procure for me some novels by this honorable author, I would make up for it in gold! -Letter to Ernest Chevalier, July 15, 1839. CHARLES AUGUST DE SAINTE-BEUVE: Without fear of refutation I venture the assertion that Byron and de Sade (please excuse me for mentioning them both in the same breath) perhaps have provided the two greatest stimuli for us moderns, the former in the glare of publicity, the latter secretly—albeit not exaggeratedly so. When one reads of our fashionable writers and wants to penetrate into their most secret recesses, and to use the backstairs of their alcove, one should never forget this key. -Revue des deux mondes, 1843. CHARLES SWINBURNE: I should have bowed to the judicial sentence if instead of “Byron with a difference” you had said “de Sade with a difference. The poet, thinker, and man of the world from whom the theology of my poem "Atlanta in Calydon" is derived was a greater one than Byron. He indeed, fatalist or not, saw to the bottom of gods and men. -Letter to Lord Houghton, August 1865. CHARLES BAUDELAIRE: One must always go back to de Sade, that is to say, to the natural man, in order to explain evil. -Intimate Journals, 1867. ANATOLE FRANCE: It is not necessary to handle a text of the Marquis de Sade like a text by Pascal... -Sade, Dorci ou la bizarrie du sort, 1881. GUILLAUME APOLLINAIRE: A great number of writers, philosophers, national economists, natural scientists, sociologists, from Lamarck to Spencer, have argued about the Marquis de Sade, and many of his ideas which horrified and shocked the minds of his time are still wholly new ... it seems that the time has come for these ideas, which have ripened in the dank atmosphere of the underworld of libraries. This man, who seemed to be of no account during the whole nineteenth century, could very well dominate the twentieth. -L'Oeuvre du Marquis de Sade, 1909. PAUL CLAUDEL: It is at least good that de Sade was made to spend half of his life in darkness. -Une semaine dans le monde, May 15, 1948. ALBERT CAMUS: De Sade is an example of the fact that a cruel answer will be given to cruel treatment meted out by society. Despite some happy shouts and the unconsidered praise of our contemporaries, the writer is secondary. He is admired today with so much naïveté on grounds that have naught to do with literature. He is glorified as the philosopher in chains and as the first theorist of absolute revolt. He could in fact become that. In the depths of prison, imagination is boundless, reality cannot bridle it. In telligence in chains loses in lucidity what it acquires in passion ateness. De Sade knew only one logic, that of feelings. He founded no philosophy, but he pursued the monstrous dream of a persecuted man. It turns out, however, that this dream was prophetic. The desperate demand for freedom led de Sade into the realm of slavery: his boundless thirst for a life thenceforth denied him was quenched, from fury to fury, in a dream of universal destruc tion. To this extent, at least, de Sade is our contemporary. -The Rebel, 1951. SIMONE DE BEAUVOIR: De Sade’s merit is not only that he loudly proclaimed what everyone shamefully admits to himself, but also the fact that he did not resign himself to it. He opted for cruelty to combat indifference. It is for this reason no doubt that he finds so great an echo today, inasmuch as the individual knows that he is more the victim of his fellow man's good conscience than of his wickedness. De Sade actualized the moment of selfishness, in justice, and unhappiness in his life in its most bitter consequences. The true value of his example lies in the fact that it disturbs us. It compels us to pose anew the essential question which haunts our age in a different form: the true relation between man and man. -Les temps modernes, January 1952. JEAN COCTEAU: De Sade is a philosopher and in his way a moralist. -L'Affaire Sade, 1957.]</p>
            </div>
        </div>
    </body>
</text>
</TEI>