<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
<teiHeader>
<fileDesc>
    <titleStmt>
        <title type="main">Thérèse and Isabelle</title>
        <author>
            <persName>
                <forename>Violet</forename>
                <surname>Leduc</surname>
            </persName>
        </author>
        <respStmt>
            <resp>Encoded in TEI All by</resp>
            <name xml:id="MD">Miki Derdun</name>
        </respStmt>
    </titleStmt>
    <editionStmt>
        <edition n="0.5">Non-public release for research purposes. Basic annotation with minimal enrichment.</edition>
    </editionStmt>
    <publicationStmt>
        <p />
    </publicationStmt>
    <sourceDesc>
        <p>From the Internet Archive edition of Ravages by Violet Leduc, trans. Derek Coltman.</p>
    </sourceDesc>
</fileDesc>
<encodingDesc>
<projectDesc>
    <p>This version of The Childlike Life of the Black Tarantula uses TEI All to encode Acker's texts and sources. The primary research aim at this stage is to understand Acker's textual reuse habits and interrogate their uses in the formation of narrative identities on the level of varying personas.</p>
</projectDesc>
</encodingDesc>
</teiHeader>
<text>
    <body>
        <div type="text">
            <div type="chapter" n="1">
                <p>I wandered away from the others over towards the lavatories. I went in. An odour halfway between the chemical smell of a sweet factory and that of school disinfecant still hung inside the little cubicle. But my loathing for these exhalations, for the general disinfecting process that always sapped our energies on the first evening back at school had left me. The odour was a backdrop awaiting our meeting. The shrieks of the younger girls receded behind me. A vapour rose from the pale, much-scrubbed wood of the seat: the vapour of tenderness given off by a mass of flaxen hair. I leaned over the bowl. The sleeping water gave me back a refiection of my face before the creation of the world. I fingered the handle, its chain, then took away my hand. The chain swung to and fro beside the melancholy water. Someone called to me. I didn't dare put on the hook and shut myself in. 'Open it,' the voice begged. Someone was rattling the doors. I could see the eye. It was blocking the heart-shaped air-hole cut in the lavatory door. 'My love.' Isabelle was there from the land of meteors, of avalanches, of wrecks, of plunder. She had thrown me a word of libera-tion, a programme; she was bringing me the invigorating breath of the North Sea. I had the strength to remain silent, even as I swelled with pride. She was waiting for me, but that did not guarantee security. The word she had used was too strong. We looked at one another, we were paralysed. I threw myself into her arms. Her lips were trying to find Thérèses in my hair, in my neck, in the folds of my pinafore, between my fingers, along my shoulders. Why couldn't I reproduce myself a thousand times and offer her a thousand Thérèses... I was nothing but myself, and that was not enough. I wasn't a forest. A blade of grass in my hair, a piece of confetti in the folds of my pinafore, a ladybird between my fingers, a piece of fluff on my neck, a scar on my cheek would have given me more body. Why wasn't I the weeping locks of a willow tree beneath her hand as it stroked my hair? I made a frame for her face: 'My love.' I contemplated her, I was remembering her in the present, savouring her nearness to me from final moment to final moment. Those in love are always standing on the platform of a railway station. 'You're here, you're really here?' I was asking questions and demanding silence in reply. We changed our responses and laments together, revealing ourselves as actresses to the manner born. We hugged each other till we could no longer breathe. Our hands were trembling, our eyes were falling shut. We stopped, then began all over again. Our arms fell to our sides, and we marvelled at our poverty. I moulded her shoulder with my fingers, I wanted to find simple, rustic caresses for her, I longed to feel her shoulder as rough as bark beneath my hand. She closed my fingers into a fist, she was polishing a pebble. I was blind with tenderness. Forehead against forehead, we told one another no. We hugged one another for one last time after the last time, we were joining two tree trunks together into one, we were the first and last lovers in the world, just as we are the first and last of mortals when we discover death. The shrieks, the bellowing, the noisy conversations out in the yard were reaching us in sudden gusts. 'Harder, harder... Hug me till I can't breathe,' she said. I hugged her, but I couldn't annihilate the shrieks, or the yard, or the boulevard and its plane trees. She pulled herself free, backed away, came back, transformed me into a magnolia, bent me backwards, then said: 'Like that, you do it like that' Her strength made me feel sad. 'Now I want to hug you.' 'You don't know how,' she said. Isabelle was gazing at me with melancholy in her eyes. I pulled her against the lavatory door and stumbled into the pedestal. She held on to the door to keep herself from falling and the hook fell at her feet. She was already making good my own incompetence. 'Come back,' she said. She let her head fall onto one shoulder, cooing like a dove as it lay there. 'Don't move. 'I'm seeing you,' I said, lost inside her. I dug into her neck with my teeth, I breathed the darkness under the neck of her dress into my lungs: the roots of a tree gave a sudden shiver. I hugged her, suffocating the tree; I hugged her, stifling the voices; I hugged her, annihilating the light. 'Is it true?' 'It's true,' Isabelle said. Now we were looking at the blue heart of the sky through the airhole in the door. The eight o'clock morning sky was hatching out the earth. Isabelle conveyed to me without words that we weren't staring at one another intensely enough. Love is overwork. Our two gazes wandered from their paths, lost their way, then found each other again. I followed a shout from one of the girls outside in Isabelle's eyes: 'I wish I could eat you.' I pushed her against the wall, I nailed her hands against it with the palms of mine. My eyelashes flickered between those of Isabelle. 'It's incredible,' she sighed. My eyebrows were caressing Isabelle's. 'It's incredible how much I can see you,' she said. We were talking. A pity. To say something is to murder it. Our words, which wouid never grow, never grow more beautiful, could only wither away inside our bones. I plunged into her eyes. 'I feel...' But feelings wither away with words. I put my hand over her mouth. Isabelle wanted to tell me what she felt. 'I feel...' I stifled back the confession she was trying to make. I took my hands away from her mouth: her arms had fallen to her sides. 'Don't be afraid. I won't say it.' She glanced sadly out at the sky through the hole in the door. I'd hurt her. We were being borne aloft by the storm of shouts outside. 'You don't understand?' 'I don't understand,' Isabelle said. 'What you wanted to say to me... you can tell it to me later.' She took my hands away from her waist. The sky through the hole was changing: the cloudless sky with its anonymous blue was depressing us. 'This is so silly. We understood one another so well a moment ago.' 'And now we don't,' Isabelle said. It was her prim double with closed eyes speaking for her. I took a step backwards and held Isabelle in gentle silhouette through a mist. She had withdrawn into a dream that was growing slowly colder. We were being pierced through and through by the shrieks from outside. 'Are you sulking?' 'No, I'm not sulking,' Isabelle said. 'Say something.' 'No.' The statue was going to disappear into the wall, it was going to be absorbed by the wall. 'Are you leaving me?' 'I'm waiting too,' she said. The ripe fullness of that quietly spoken no: the tight-squeezed beauty of a snowball made in May that I would forget again as soon as I began to die outside the gardens. By cheating, I could see the tarry glint of the stagnant water. Isabelle lifted her arm, pulled at the tortoise-shell pin holding her coiled-up hair, but did not take it out. I was charmed by her unfinished gesture. Isabelle still didn't open her eyes. The arm fell to her side once more, defeated by the lethargy of the lavatories. I hugged her with all the strength of my repentance, I breathed her in, I pulled her tight against my belly and made her into a loincloth for myself. I staggered as I felt Isabelle become embedded into me. She was melting my ankles and knees into delicious decay. I had burst with warmth like a fruit, I was running with the same liquid sweetness. There were pincers softly tearing at me, oh so softly. Her hairpin fell into the bowl and we lost our balance. I plunged my hand into the water, then replaced the pin in her hair. 'I want that hand,' she said. Her fondling was turning me to ice. I was being separated from my hand; I could no longer recognize it. I took it back from her, dried her wet lips with my dry ones, and thrust my tongue into her mouth. Isabelle clasped her hands: she was making a rest for my chin. 'Thérèse...' I pulled away from her in order to see her better. 'Yes,' my rose-filled heart replied. She had moved around to my back, circled me with one arm, pulled me to her, hollowed herself against me. I was ashamed at having my back to her, of showing her those sullen hanks of hair I could do nothing to make fine. The blood rose into my cheeks, into my throat, as I tore at her pinafore and crushed the hairs beneath. Her hand was making it difficult for me to breath. I was sobbing without a sound, without tears. Isabelle was sobbing too as she pressed her hand against my pinafore: my clothes were crushed against me. A cry from the yard outside pierced me where her hand was, and my heart began to beat down there instead of the cry. One of the girls was doing her piano practice: the pearly notes made me think of the necklace of cool droplets from a park fountain. My breathing became regular again. 'What's the time?' I said. 'Recreation's been extended. There won't be a study period.' 'I know. What's the time?' I pulled myself free. She gave a contemptuous pout. 'The school can burn down for all I care.' 'Or me. Let it.' 'I don't care a damn about being expelled, but I do care about being separated from you. Don't you understand that?' 'We shall be separated anyway,' I said. Isabelle threw herself upon me. She twisted my wrists. 'Separated, us? You're mad. Anyway, not before summer vacation.' 'You'll see. My mother, Isabelle, my mother ..? I was choking. 'What about your mother?' 'I must always stay close to her...' 'They're not going to separate us,' Isabelle said. Our lips had achieved a reconciliation, our kiss of dalliance held firm. Someone shook our door, then went into the lavatory next to ours: it didn't disturb us. The pattering of her feet on the cement told us that the little girl next door had waited until the last moment. She lifted her pinafore, her skirt, her under-clothes. My tortured flesh was falling in tatters onto lace. I opened my eyes, I saw in Isabelle's eyes that I had been unfaithful to her with another's secret linen. The little girl was relieving herself, but we, we felt only shame at that monotonous stream descending into the lavatory bowl. I sensed already that it was to become a memory. The little girl jumped down off the seat, fell on her feet, then closed the door carefully behind her. 'Say something, Thérèse.' '...' 'No, I won't give you the slushy nonsense you want of me. Be quiet. Hold me tight. You are a village of five hundred 'Oh,' I said, my lips at the hole in the door, 'the other girls have gone in. All of them.' 'Doesn't matter in the slightest. I shall say I didn't feel well and you, you'll think of something.' 'What shall I think of?' 'A lie,' Isabelle said. That lock of hair would always be a slash of madness carved above one eye. Isabelle was kissing me all over. She was covering me with decorations; I was weighing her down with medals. The springtime in her fleece was fraternizing with the springtime in mine. 'I can't go on.' 'I can't go on.' We were weakening; the sensations in our loins were no longer sharp. Isabelle's head fell onto my shoulder. I had a falcon on my shoulder, I was the Lord High Falconer. 'Enough,' she said. 'You said that last night.' 'We must separate. I'll leave first.' But not till I had pinned three kisses like rosettes onto the belt of her pinafore. 'Keep this. It'll be a bond between us until this evening,' Isabelle said. She stretched out her arm and unbuckled her wristwatch for me. A fly flew away: its was the moment to part. Through the heart-shaped hole in the door I watched Isabelle walk away. The dust in the yard had her feet, the tortoise-shell pins had her hair, the air outside had her lungs, which I could never see, which I could not have against me as I breathed. The porter was ringing the bell for the first period. There were day girls running across the main quadrangle. The boarders were banging the doors of their lockers. One of the younger girls walked past with a bunch of flowers for her teacher. The new assistant, questioning me in a corridor, decided to believe me when I said I had been practising scales in the music room. She made me repeat my lie, buttoned up her gloves, clutched her box of writing paper to her heart, then walked away towards the town, towards the post office, towards the benches in the municipal park. The porter's arm, going up and down, up and down as he rang the bell for the next lesson, was pumping air into us. 'Where were you?' one of the other girls also asked. I said goodbye to the assistant, and to a companion: I had made my life elsewhere, I escaped in the direction of the study hall. When I was bored - which was rather often, since I didn't work - I would open the door of my locker, gaze at the labels on the books without opening them, and imagine that my books were living in a daydream like their owner. I had written the names of their authors on the labels. I would fold my arms, listen and listen for a long while, and then, finally, I would hear the distant clamour of antique tragedies. I wanted Isabelle. The undertaker's mutes hadn't come and carried her off, so why didn't she come to me? I was waiting for her on her bed, keeping vigil at all four corners of that white hearse, breathing in the smell of her counter-pane, waiting for her with the tears streaming inside my belly. The principal was going to come and inspect the cubicles, she would find me on Isabelle's bed, she would expel me. We were going to be parted. But I couldn't leave her bed. I lay there as though in a vice. What were we going to do that night? My mother had given way, but she had given way with bad grace. My mother had warned me over and over again that she would take me out of school again before vacation if she began to miss me, if she got bored. If she hadn't got married, then I would have been the one to beg her: anything you like, but don't send me to live away from you in a boarding school. Now it was the opposite. She had married. We were cut off from one another. How long would we be cut off from one another? The time was past when I had scrabbled in the earth for her, when I had slithered under the barbed wire, when I had stolen potatoes for us to eat out in the fields. She had taken the factory from me, and my shoulder bag and my lunch box too. She had sold our rabbits at a loss - oh, the pity of it! - a week before her wedding. It was the bankruptcy of all my fields. I told her that I was engaged to her myself. She sighed, I didn't know what an exasperated look was. She had married without ever being engaged. I was there to scrub our three front steps, but she wanted a tradesman. I wasn't to be her journeyman, I wasn't to be the factory worker bringing her home his weekly wage. When the old-clothes man came she sold him the drawer of ashes I used to empty out in the poultry run while the first drops of coffee were falling into our coffee-pot, imitating the sweet chirping of the finches. Where had our clothespegs gone? Where was our blue bag? She threw everything away. Mademoiselle was getting married. She got rid of everything. She had what she wanted. She was a married woman. I had become a boarder in a boarding school: I had no home. A man had come between us. Hers. Your mother would be so pleased if you stopped calling me 'monsieur'... I was never going to stop calling him 'monsieur'. A little more bread, monsieur. No, monsieur, I don't like meat when it's rare. Call him 'father', she would say to me after meals. Never. I liked it better eating off the refectory table at school with the bread in the middle. We dug our hands into the basket, we didn't say no thank you, yes thank you. I had crawled at her feet: don't get married, don't get married... We would have done great things together: we would have been all in all to one another. I had been so warm in her bed. She used to call me her little rogue. But now she she had a Borelly bed and didn't give me her arms any more. Monsieur was there between us. She wanted a daughter as well as a husband. I had a demanding mother. I was chained up in a boarding school, I no longer walked behind them during their evening walk, I no longer slept in the bedroom next to theirs. She wanted me to be there, to devote myself. to her as soon as he left the house. There's no one on earth but you, there's no one on earth I love but you, she told me, but she had someone else. I had met Isabelle, and now I had someone else. I was Isabelle's. I didn't belong to my mother any more. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="2">
                <p>In the dormitory, that evening. In the dormitory, that night, in Isabelle's cubicle. I put my baby to bed, I lifted up its head, I plumped up its pillow, I straightened its sheets and freshened its bed. 'I feel as though you're my nurse,' Isabelle said, I warmed her foot against my breast. Isabelle had brought me a child. Sometimes I made love to it, sometimes I put it back in its cradle. I have never wanted any other children from those I have loved than they themselves. They were love, all of it. 'I'm going, Isabelle.' She held on to me. 'I'll scream if you do.' I stayed. 'Not so stiff,' she said to the hand that was no longer mine, that she was guiding with hers. I was back in the old shelter. 'You're dozing off,' she said. My finger was dreaming, I was in the grip of a hidden delirium. She laid her arm on mine, she had found a way of giving me pleasure by making our arms touch. To give oneself, one must annihilate oneself. I wanted to be a machine without being mechanical. My life was her pleasure. I was aiming further than Isabelle herself, I was taking Isabelle inside a womb of shadows. We were so much in harmony with one another that we ourselves were dis-appearing. She lifted herself up, frightening me. Was she dying, or would she live? It depended on the rhythm. I was following everything taking place inside her, I could see with my inner eyes the light in her flesh. In my head I had a Thérèse with opened legs, straining up to the sky, who was receiving all that I was giving to Isabelle. 'Come and rest,' she said. I became a little child again. Living, lying, floating, apart and calm again, we were able to believe in eternal rest. How cool the funereal, trickling stream... 'I wish I could tell you...' 'You're happy. Don't try,' Isabelle said. We put our nightgowns back on. I said: 'What are you thinking?' 'I'm just letting myself exist. And you?' 'I was listening to your heart. What a prison!... Are you listening to it too?' 'No, I'm quite happy,' Isabelle said. I turned towards her. 'You're not asleep?' 'I was seeing us in a cinema. I was behaving badly,' Isabelle said. 'In a cinema... How very strange!... It's almost as though that meant something to me. Yet it can't be a memory. It's as though I'd really been in that cinema, even though I don't know it,' I said. 'It will never happen. We're not free,' Isabelle said. 'Let's run away.' 'I have no money.' 'Neither have I. Let's sell everything it's possible to sell, then buy train tickets. Let's try. We won't die of hunger.' 'We shan't run away. This is where we have to be. We shall have every night together if we're careful. Don't you like being at school?' 'On the contrary. I'm afraid of being taken out of it... Will you come and see me between your classes? Tell me, will you?' She didn't answer. Two pink flowers melted one into the other. 'Who taught you?' 'I've always known,' Isabelle said. 'I'm hungry.' She opened the drawer in her bedside table and then, without letting go of me, thrust a dusty square of chocolate into my mouth. 'Eat,' Isabelle said, 'eat.' My cheek felt a chill from time to time as it came into contact with my flashlight on the pillow. Separately, I lit up the palms of her hands, far away from where we were joined. 'Need you,' I said. 'Need you,' Isabelle said. 'Yes. Yes,' I moaned. 'Someone coming,' Isabelle said calmly. She got up and looked out into the aisle. 'It's all right. There's no one there,' Isabelle said. She leaned over the bed. She wasn't going to lie down again. She had sent her hand to dance gaily between my thighs, to draw breathtaking figures of eight there over and over again. bending over me as she caressed me. Three fingers entered me, three guests for the flesh to cling to. She lay down again like that, like an acrobat who lies on the floor holding his partner up with only one arm. 'You're not listening to me,' Isabelle said. 'I am listening. You're saying little things to me, you've come back, you are there inside me. The rain... Oh, yes... Let's die together, Isabelle, let's die while you are me and I am you. Then I'll never think about us being separated again, Let's die, shall we?' 'No. I don't want to die. I want this. I want to be deep inside you. Dying.. that's so stupid.' 'If I had leprosy, would you leave me?' 'I havn't got it, you havn't got it, we havn't got it. Why have you switched on the light?' Isabelle withdrew her hand and crossed her arms over her eyes. 'Would you leave me?' She shrugged her shoulders. 'Look at me,' I said. 'I'm looking at you with my eyes closed.' 'If I died tomorrow, would you go on living?' She turned towards me. Whenever she turned like that, I could see her withdrawn into the heart of a frost-covered bush. 'You'd go on living. You can't answer.' Isabelle clasped her hands together. There were tiny twitches, tics, chasing one another across her face: her soul was quivering. 'It's a difficult question,' she said. She didn't open her eyes. 'Answer!' 'Problems like that are too big for us.' Isabelle lifted her eyelids. Now she was staring at me. 'When you say you want to die with me, do you really mean it? Would you really like us to die together?' Isabelle tilted back her head. She was concentrating hard on her thoughts. 'I don't know any more,' I said. 'Give me your hand,' she said. 'No... don't give me your hand. Not now.' 'You're so beautiful... I really would like to but I couldn't. I can't imagine you dead. You're so beautiful...' 'Let's talk about us. Could you?' 'I don't know, I don't know any more. One can't help loving life. But you. What about you?' 'And yet, if we don't want to be separated,' Isabelle said. 'You could?' 'One would have to get used to the idea,' Isabelle said. 'You couldn't, but I don't hold it against you. I never imagined that I would ask such a thing of you. From a cliff... at night... together..' 'How terrible, when you say it like that.' 'How quick you are to be afraid!' With you, it doesn't frighten me at all.' 'Don't think about it, Isabelle.' 'I told you: problems like that are just too big for us.' 'You're beautiful. I don't want to lose you.' Isabelle turned away towards the wall, but I told her again and again, into her hair, against her eyes, how beautiful she was. She loathed the frippery of compliments. She closed up, she withdrew into the distance. 'Stretch out, take up all the room. Be beautiful,' I said. Isabelle sat up. 'Listen: it's three in the morning. I don't want to leave you.' She hung herself about my neck. The night had betrayed us. I was worshipping her vulnerability. 'Hold the flashlight. I'll do your hair. Shall I?' She shrugged her shoulders indulgently. 'Can you hear? It's raining.' It was only the last of the night sighing out its tenderness. I let her hair down onto her shoulders, framing her face in tumbling madness. Yet there was nothing abject in her look. Her little nose would never grow old. The earthworms might eat their fill, but her little nose would never change. It would be the treasure in the tomb, the perfect little bone. How puritanical it was, that straight little nose of hers. 'What's the matter with me, what is it I can see?' 'Nothing.' I didn't dare talk to her about her immortality. She took my hand and laid her cheek inside it. 'Let me do your hair.' Isabelle was quite willing to let me do as I wished. 'What are you doing?' 'I'm putting flowers in it.' 'That's serious. Did you know that?' Isabelle said. 'I'm not doing it just for fun.' 'It's not real. We have no time to waste.' 'You're beautiful and I'm making you more beautiful.' 'I don't want you to idolize me.' I could see the glitter of my tears. But I wasn't weeping. 'What is it I've done, tell me what I've done,' I begged 'I wanted to make you look pretty...' 'Is that all?' Isabelle said. 'Yes, that's all.' But I was loving her with bows of black crepe on every finger. She sat up in bed. 'I know: we shall be separated,' she said. I picked up the eiderdown, I went into battle against the curse hanging over us. We created a fiesta to celebrate the oblivion of time. We hugged to our hearts all the Thérèses and Isabelles who would make love to one another later with other names; we finished our embrace with cracking and trembling limbs. We rolled, intertwined, down a slope of shadows. We held our breaths so that life and death themselves should come to a halt. I stormed her mouth as one storms a beleagured city: I was hoping to plunder and destroy both her entrails and my own. The sound of a whistle, a train, a railway station, but the silence still weighed down on our heads. Isabelle spread her hair over my shoulder. 'Are you sleepy?' 'No, I'm not sleepy.' She stammered out her reply. Something unhooked itself from my hip and fell onto the mattress: a hand. Isabelle was asleep. The dawn would be our twilight any moment now. My face brushed against hers. 'Don't go to sleep.' Dawn, always punctual when there is something dying somewhere, was waiting with its muslin veils. There were boats, tearing themselves away from the clinging rushes, already drifting downstream. 'Don't go to sleep...' I opened the hand lying curled on her curling hair, I listened over my domain. Her sleep excited me. I laid my lips, the lips of a little girl of eight, against her tasteless lips, I was unfaithful to Isabelle with herself, I was depriving her of the kiss that I was giving her. She woke up against my mouth. 'You were there?' She spoke: she had brought me back a flower culled from. the shadows in which she had been resting. I breathed in the sulphurous odour of her presence. 'Do you want to?' 'Yes,' Isabelle said. We flew above each other's shoulders, brushing them with tawny autumn fingers, we sent great beams of light flashing into nestling hollows as we passed, we fanned one another with our caresses and blew sea breezes into patterns on our flesh; we wrapped our legs in zephyrs, we felt the rustling of taffetas in the hollow of our hands. How easily we found our way in! Our flesh made love to us and scent welled out of us like a fountain. Our yeast, our rising flesh, our bread. The to and fro was no servitude, it was the to and fro of beatitude. I lost myself in Isabelle's fingers just as she was losing herself in mine. What dreams they contained, our diligent fingers... What weddings of movement! There were clouds to help us. We were streaming with light. The wave stole upon us like a wary scout, it washed our feet with ecstasy, then returned. Lianas loosed their coils, our ankles became a source of light. This unfurling sweetness finished me. My knees were in ashes. 'It's too much. Tell me it's too much.' 'Quiet.' 'I can't be quiet, Isabelle.' I kissed her shoulder and abandoned myself once more to our shipwreck. 'Speak.' 'I can't,' Isabelle said. 'What are you thinking?' 'About you.' 'Speak, speak.' 'Aren't you happy? 'Look... No, don't look.' 'I know. It'll be light soon. Close your eyes. Don't let it come,' Isabelle said. Day was breaking. Isabelle went back to sleep. I was yawning in wet and milky meadows, seeking help and protection from the sleeper by my side, repository of the dark night whose passing I regretted. My sleeper's head was filled with darkness that would not wear out, my sleeper's heart was filled with the song of the lark that had not slept. I took only tiny breaths, I was eking out the moments beside her as economically as I could. She wound her arms around me, she was not forgetting to worry even in her sleep. 'Aren't you asleep?' 'Yes, I'm asleep. Go to sleep.' Some of the other girls were shifting in their beds: the dawn was quivering through their dreams. I got up, and Isabelle got up too. I went out into the corridor, but she pulled me roughly back into the cubicle. She opened her dressing gown and bruised my pubis with her thigh thrust between mine. I wanted to leave. Her sleep had filled me with despair. 'Don't go!' Isabelle crumbled. 'Why did I go to sleep?' She was trembling. An excess of love saps one's strength. 'Do what you like,' I said. She hunted for remnants of darkness on my face with her tongue. She knelt down. Her face was travelling all over me, her face was exploring me. There were lips seeing and touching what I would never see. I was humiliated for her. Indispensable and ignored, that was what I was with my face so far away from Isabelle's. Her damp forehead disturbed me. A saint was licking away my soils. Her gifts were making me poorer. She was giving herself too much: I was guilty. 'Go and rest. There's a girl up and working already,' Isabelle said. I obeyed. I hurled myself into the slow river of sleep. 'You're not still asleep, I hope?' the assistant in charge of our dormitory said. I was asleep on my feet. 'Relative clauses can, in addition, be used to indicate various sets of related circumstances..' Isabelle was saying that to some other girl. Isabelle was already tidying up her cubicle. I shook myself completely awake and set to work diligently on my appearance so that I would be ready for her good morning. She swept in like a disdainful hurricane just as I was putting brilliantine on the brush that was to transform me into a shining, precious bud. 'Good morning.' 'Good morning.' We couldn't look at one another. 'It's a lovely day.' 'Yes, lovely?' But the sun was putting us out of countenance. We lowered our eyes. 'Are you ready?' Isabelle asked. 'No. You can see I'm not.' I was avoiding saying her name, I could no longer swallow my saliva... 'Do you want me to help you?' 'No.' 'I'd like my watch back,' Isabelle said. 'Of course. Your watch.' I busied myself at my bedside table. 'Strap it on my wrist,' Isabelle said. We saw one another again, we looked at one another with our eyes of before. 'Strap my watch on... please.' 'You must tell me if I pull it too tight.' 'It's easy. There's a mark.' 'Can't you do it?' Isabelle asked. 'Yes,' I said. 'You've lost your voice,' she said. 'Me? Do you mind? I have to finish tidying up.' I threw the lid of my slop pail onto the floor and emptied my basin. 'Too much noise down there,' the assistant called out. 'Don't file your nails here. Don't file your nails.' 'Why not?' Isabelle said. 'Not here. Not now.' 'Why not? You're dusting.' 'Don't file your nails. Stop it.' Isabelle opened my cubicle window. 'Have you thrown your nail file out?' 'It was offending you,' Isabelle said. I was wiping the pottery plate on which I kept my tooth-brush. Isabelle was preparing to stab me: the idea flashed through me as I went on to straighten my towels and facecloth on the towel rack. I waited for the dagger to pierce me. 'Did the assistant see you come in here?' Isabelle wouldn't answer. I took my towel back off the rack and wiped my glass. 'Does she know you're in here?' Suddenly Isabelle pulled my hair: she was burying her blade deep in my neck. 'Someone's coming,' Isabelle said. She tore herself away from me, pulled the curtain open a little way, then slipped through. 'False alarm. The aisle's empty,' she said. Then, having reassured me, she vanished. But the assistant did come in. 'There was someone in your cubicle. Don't deny it. I want the name of your companion.' 'Companion?' I said scornfully. 'Why are you smiling?' 'Isabelle was helping me. Isabelle always helps me when I'm late. Our last assistant knew that.' 'You astonish me. Now hurry up, hurry up, we're going downstairs now,' the assistant said, glad to have her mind set at rest. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="3">
                <p>Andrea, a day boarder who arrived very early and ate lunch with us in the refrectory but had her dinner and slept out in the country, used to spend all her Thursdays and Sundays looking out over a meadow, beside a cowshed. Andrea was a pretty slice of winter. Her eyes glittered with cold, her lips were always split and chapped by the frost. I used to squeeze her hand, imprisoning the oxygen of her liberty. 'Is it lovely weather at your home?' I'd ask. 'It's the same weather as it is here,' she'd answer. 'No more frosts,' I'd say then, nostalgic for the sight of white hoarfrost. 'No, the frosts are over. My father is sharpening his scythe for the hay,' was her answer. That morning I left Andrea to her hoarfrosts. 'Renée has been showing me some photographs. What do you think of this one?' Isabelle said to me in the assembly hall as we waited to go in to breakfast. 'It's a landscape. It's good.' Isabelle was making advances to me with her hair, letting it brush against mine. I was afraid I would scream. I pulled away from her. Isabelle tossed back a lock of hair. Her cheek imprinted a long kiss on mine. 'Stop,' I said, 'stop, or I shall die.' She pushed me furiously against Renée, then apologized. The little girls nearby were tearing us apart with their cries. I love you and you won't answer, the hand in mine insisted. Renée, gazing at her photograph, could probably sense the intimacy beside her, since she did not dare to look up. I was trapped between her mock innocence on the one hand and Isabelle's boldness on the other. Isabelle's hand, hidden in the folds of my pinafore, had caressed me. It was madness. I was deliquescing, all my flesh was overripe. 'You must have looked at that photograph enough by now!' Renée said. 'Leave her alone. She wants to see the details,' Isabelle answered for me. She had guessed I was using the glossy rectangle as a shield. It was keeping away the lightning that would have torn open my entrails, that would have revealed the glowing nimbus inside my belly. I crumbled to the floor with the landscape in my hand. 'Slap her,' Renée said to Isabelle. 'Slap her, that will bring her round.' Isabelle didn't answer. 'A handkerchief, quickly, a handkerchief and some cologne!' another girl cried. 'Thérèse has fainted... Thérèse is sick.' 'Go and get some vinegar, go and get some smelling salts!' Lying there peacefully on the tiled floor, I listened to them talk as I counterfeited the necessary swoon after my fall. I didn't dare get up again for fear of their ridicule. I often exhaust myself upon waking with imagining people's grief, then people's lack of grief, when they hear that I am no longer alive. Isabelle was silent, Isabelle was accustoming herself to the idea of my death. Other girls were shaking me, pushing up my eyelids, calling my name, but failing to recall me. I had made myself disappear because I couldn't love her in public: the scandal I had spared us both was now falling on me alone. I got up to spare myself the horrid smell of their vinegar. 'It was nothing,' I said. I patted my forehead. 'Go up to your dormitory,' the new assistant said. 'Who will go with her?' She was dabbing my forehead and lips with her filthy vinegar. 'I'll go,' Isabelle said. We set of like two beggar women, hearing the soldierlike tread of the other girls as they filed into the refectory behind us. Isabelle had her arm around a boarder who had fainted. The penance was out of proportion to the sin. We went forward without speaking, without looking at each other. She stopped when I stopped, moved forward again when I did. I paused gloomily on the mat at the foot of the stairs, hoping for a reconciliation. And Isabelle, I loved her along every inch of the banister, at every step... I made a vow of reconciliation every time I lifted my foot. She took away her arm, she buttoned up the cuff of her pinafore, then took me by the waist again in obedience to the assistant's orders. It was a nurse who thrust me into the dormitory corridor, who pulled aside my cubicle curtain, who left for her own cubicle. My vinegar-sprinkled pinafore and my wet hair were draining away my strength. I too went into my cubicle. She pulled the curtain wide open, airing everything inside before coming in. She was disinfecting my soul, intimidating me. 'Why did you do that?' Her voice was gentle, making what had happened less terrible. 'Why did you do it?' '...' 'Were you pretending, or was it because you're tired?' 'I was pretending. Don't scold me.' 'I'm not scolding you.' 'Put that brush down! Don't go.' She came back into my cubicle, a gift brought in by the sun. I pressed the deepest kiss I had into her hand. 'Forgive me,' I begged. 'Be quiet. Don't say such horrible things. Are you tired?' 'I shall never be tired until vacation comes.' 'I have to go and show my face in the refectory, Thérèse.' Her weight on my knees had comforted me. 'Close your eyes and listen: I fell down in the assembly hall because you came too close to me. I had no strength left. You knew you were upsetting me.' 'It's true,' Isabelle said. 'I knew I was upsetting you.' She opened her eyes: we both moaned at the yielding sweetness of our kiss. 'Someone's coming,' Isabelle said. The saliva... Wipe away the saliva..' 'Not back at breakfast yet, Isabelle!' the house mistress said. 'As for you, Thérèse, I'll see that yours is brought up to you here.' When I went back to the study hall, I found an envelope in my locker. I sat down in Isabelle's place, since I had no classes, and gazed at the inkstains on her desk. There were other girls working in the clear morning light. When I put my hand up against my heart, the white envelope was quivering there, with Isabelle's writing shimmering on its surface. I postponed reading it, I read my physics book, I sat working inside my usual shell of idleness. The sun was tempting me, its honeyed reflection was tinting my wrists; the professorial voices of the masters had lost their winter resonance now that all the classroom windows were open. Seasons, lend us your tattered dresses. Let us be wandering gypsies with your hair lacquered to our heads by the rain. Will you come with me, Isabelle, will you set up house with me on some roadside bank? We'll crunch up our dry crusts with lions' jaws, we'll find our spices in the storm, we'll have a house, with lace curtains at the windows as the caravans roll by and disappear towards the frontiers. I'll undress you in the growing wheat, I'll find lodgings in the hearts of hay-stacks, I'll cover you in the water under low, overhanging branches, I'll nurse you on a mossbank in the forest, I'll make love to you in the fields of lucerne, I'll haul you up into the haycarts, my Boadicea. I escaped from the study hall and read her letter in the lavatories. 'Recover your strength, sleep wherever you can, fortify yourself for the night ahead, think of our future together this evening.' I wound the lavatory chain around my neck, I kissed one of Isabelle's vertebrae on each link, I tore up the orders she had sent me and threw the pieces into the lavatory bowl. Quarter past nine. The clock in the main quadrangle was marking an Olympian scale of time far above the petty time divisions of the classrooms. My physics book lost its paper cover, my lead pencil rolled under the radiator: my possessions were running away from me because I had abandoned them. There were some day girls waiting outside in the corridor for their two o'clock class, wandering to and fro beyond the glass door. They weren't in love: I felt oppressed by their easy, careless manner. 'The teacher is speaking to you,' a fellow student told me. I had fallen asleep during our cosmography class. 'She's been unwell,' the girl said. 'She fainted in assembly hall. We don't know what's wrong with her.' I went back to sleep. After the cosmography lesson came a morals lesson, and I dozed my way through that too. Eleven twenty-five, eleven thirty, eleven thirty-five. I could see our moment of reunion in the generous angle of the hands as they stood at eleven thirty-five. I shook myself awake like a sentry who has been sleeping at his post. I powdered my face under cover of my desk, exploring its features in my little mirror to see what Isabelle would like and what she wouldn't. The bell rang, there were yelling girls all around me, I had a plan. 'Yes, two roses... Go to the very best florist...' 'How big?' the day girl asked. 'Whichever are the most beautiful. Yes, if you like: for one of the teachers. Smell them before you buy them. Pink ones preferably!' 'You'd better go back now,' the day girl said. 'You can count on me.' The other day girls were flicking at my face with their scarves, their berets, their gloves; they were pushing and dragging me towards the forbidden gate. I turned back: I had someone. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="4">
                <p>The music room, up under the eaves, was still filled with the animal heat given off by the hundred or so girls who had been do-re-mi-ing up there during successive morning classes. I went in. I sank down on a desk. I heard a drop of water drip into a washbasin and waited intently for a second to follow it. I was loving Isabelle as I sat, but she didn't know where. I willed her to come: it did not occur to me that she might lack second sight. Twenty to twelve... I counted up to six between two drips of water. Her step. She was trampling on my heart, on my belly, on my fore-head, even before she came in. A city of light was coming towards me. I would be crushed beneath its blazing wonders. I could sense through the glass door that she was searching for me as I watched her in the blackness behind my lowered eyelids. I didn't raise my head, I stayed hidden in the folds of my widow's weeds. Ravens spread over the sky, hoarfrost whitened the hazel bushes. She was coming, she was breathing with my lungs. 'I've been looking for you everywhere,' Isabelle said. She collapsed against my back, sobbing with happiness. She sat down on the desk seat. We were loving one another and holding one another back: we were keeping ourselves balanced on a wild rose petal. She examined my lips, touching them roughly with one hand. 'Is it you, is it really you?' The hand was begging for certainties against my eyelids. Her face dived downwards, her face was lower than my breasts. 'Your face is too far away,' I said. 'I've torn your dress,' Isabelle said. She took out a pin to mend my dress, and while she did the repairs I sat breathing in the scent of memories from her hair. 'Someone's coming!' We sprang apart and hid, each in her own corner. One of the music mistresses turned the key of her room. She passed the door and walked away down the corridor, placid and monumental. 'The house mistress says I must take you to the doctor at four this afternoon,' Isabelle said. I ran into her arms as she ran into mine. 'A quarter to twelve!' Isabelle said. 'Come, come...' We fell onto the steps of the dais. 'A quarter to twelve, Thérèse!' I hesitated because of the inkstains on my fingers. 'Don't stop me!' I said out of shyness. I was afraid of degrading her by lifting her skirt. 'Almost ten to twelve, Isabelle!' 'If you don't talk more quietly, we shall be caught,' Isabelle said. I lifted her skirt: Isabelle quivered against my temple. I ventured onward, beneath the pleated skirt: her underclothes made me afraid. She was too indecent underneath , her dress. My hand advanced between skin and fabric. 'Let me do it. Don't look if it shocks you,' Isabelle said. I looked. She arched herself up from the step and gave me back my hand, 'These knickers are impossible!' she said. It was the hand of a sleepwalker that pulled them off, that stuffed them into her pinafore pocket. Isabelle offered herself up to me on the steps. . 'You were being squeezed, my little golden lamb. You're all crushed. Can you feel my cheek against you, my little squirrel? I'm combing you, I'm making you tidy, I'm coaxing you, my little gilded bunny... You're shining, Isabelle, you're shining...' I stood up and gazed down at her. 'Come back... Don't leave me.' 'You want me to?' I was being sadistic. Waiting and making the other wait is a delicious agony. 'What if we were caught,' I mused out loud. 'I can't wait any longer,' Isabelle moaned. Her hands were writhing over her face. I fell on my knees in front of the golden medallion, I gazed down at that radiant thicket. I ventured forward like a smuggler, my face first. Isabelle gripped me with a scissor movement of her legs. 'I'm looking, I'm trapped,' I said. We waited. Her sex was going to our heads. An incalculable number of hearts were beating there inside her, against my forehead. 'Yes, yes... Not so quickly. Not so quickly, I said... Higher. No... Lower. Almost... You're almost there... Yes... Yes... that's almost it... Quicker, quicker, quicker,' she said. My tongue went searching through a salty blackness, through clinging darkness, over the most delicate of meat. The more I applied myself, the more mysterious my efforts became. I hesitated around the pearl. 'Don't stop. That's it, that's it.' I lost it, then found it again. 'Yes, yes,' Isabelle moaned. 'You've found it, you've found it,' she sighed in ecstasy. 'Go on. Please, please... There... yes, there... exactly there.' Her anguish, her authority, her orders and her counter-orders bewildered me. 'You're not trying to guide me,' I said, separated from that fantastic universe. My complaint was made between the lips of her sex. 'I'm trying to do nothing else,' she said. 'You're not thinking what you're doing.' 'I'm thinking about it too much,' I said. The golden hair around her sex was wet with my tears of sweat. 'Teach me... Teach me...' 'Take away your face and watch.' Still lying on the dais steps, Isabelle searched within herself and found what she wanted. 'Come closer. Look, look. That's it. When you lose it, you must find it again, Oh, oh... No. Not now. You, you!' I looked down at the golden hair peeping between her spread fingers, I quivered with the quivering muscles in her hand. The finger was turning. Soon I would be vomiting out the sweets of her orgasm. Her neck stretched backward, her face was moving out of sight. Her eyes opened: Isabelle was seeing her paradise. 'You. Not me,' she said. She took her hand away and closed it into a fist. 'A minute past twelve! They'll all be in the refectory. A minute past twelve... I'm afraid of doing it wrong.' 'Yes, yes... Go on... Until this evening if necessary,' she said. I applied myself to my task with such concentration that the flesh I was tasting became unreal. Too close to her sex as I was, I thought how much I wanted to give her what she desired. My mind was trapped in her flesh, my self-abnegation grew and grew. If I became short of saliva, I created more. I didn't know if this was a good thing or a bad thing from her point of view, but if the pearl slipped away from me, I found it again. 'It will be there, it will always be there,' Isabelle said. Nostalgia and beatitude were coalescing. 'You've found the way,' she said. Then she was silent, intent on her own sensations. I was receiving what she was receiving: I was Isabelle. My efforts, my sweat, my rhythm were exciting me too. The pearl wanted what I wanted. I was discovering the little male organ we all of us have. A eunuch taking heart again. 'I'm nearly there, my love. It's beautiful: I'm nearly there. It's too beautiful. Go on. Don't stop, don't stop. Go on, go on, go on...' I raised my head: I was expecting to see an oracle on the steps where we lay. 'Don't leave me, don't stop,' Isabelle cried in panic. 'Yes, but don't stop.' I persevered. 'It's begun. It's beginning. It's coming upwards. In my legs, in my legs... Yes, my love, yes. Go on... Don't stop... In my knees, in my knees...' She was watching her own sensation, she was calling for help. 'It's coming higher. Higher and higher.' She fell silent. I was submerged and swept away with her. I felt stigmata open in my entrails. We thanked one another with fragile smiles. 'This time someone really is coming. Hide. I'll go out and block the window in the door. Go up to the dormitory... We'll be going into town together at four,' Isabelle whispered. 'Your hair! Your hair!' She smoothed all the madness and disorder away into its coils, then left the room, mistress of herself. A girl ran up to her in the corridor. I listened from behind the door. 'You're out of your mind,' Renée said. 'Do you know what time it is? Twenty-five past twelve. I've been looking for you everywhere: in the classrooms, in the study hall, in the infirmary. The headmistress is furious.' 'Does she know?' Isabelle asked. 'She came into the refectory. She was scandalized when she saw your empty place. But what have you been doing?' 'I was in the chemistry lab. I was working. I must go and explain to the headmistress,' Isabelle said. 'Thérèse has vanished too. Everyone thought she was sick and had gone up to the dormitory. I took her lunch up to her. 'No one there. You two are quite incredible,' Renée said. They moved away, The tray was there in my cubicle with its remains of meat, its lentils, and two little green apples. Eat. Eat so that you'll have plenty of energy at four o'clock this afternoon, I said to myself before swallowing down my dismal cold repast. 'Quite better now?' asked an assistant I had bumped into with my tray at the bottom of the stairs. 'I shall be going to the doctor at four o'clock,' I said com-placently. I ran out into the recreation yard to see her again. 'Isabelle has been in trouble. Isabelle is working,' Renée told me. 'In the future you will ask my permission before going up to the dormitory, even if you do feel unwell,' the new assistant told me. It was time to line up and file into the study hall. We sat and listened, we students, to the bells of the streetcars outside, then the protesting screech against the rails as each one moved off again. The noises and scents of the town were no longer a means of escape for me: the school was my love nest now, the school was my bracelet and my neck-lace. Isabelle was studying. I opened a book and listened. 'Faster, not so fast, go on, go on, it's begun, it's beginning, higher up, lower down, don't leave me, don't stop, go on, go on... I'm nearly there. It's beautiful. I'm nearly there. It's too beautiful... Go on, go on... It's there, it will always be there.' I listened to her voice till study period was over. 'A dozen roses! What were you thinking of!' I said to the day girl. 'I told you two, not twelve. And a shoe box into the bargain. Now what am I to do!' 'I scarcely had time to eat any lunch because of you. I had to look for the box up in the attic. That was all I could find to hide them in, and now you complain! Just two roses looked so stingy. You can pay me when you've got it.' 'I'll pay you for them right away; but you'll have to take them back home with you. I can't have them left on my hands. I'll take two and you can give the others to your father and mother.' 'They were for one of the assistants!' 'No, they weren't... But you've given me an idea.' 'We'll talk about it later. I love big bunches of flowers,' the day girl said. She vanished, and so did I - up to the dormitory with my flowers. 'What are you doing here?' the new assistant demanded. 'You can't go on being unwell forever!' A dingy smell of shampoo blanketed my roses as she half opened her curtain. 'I was looking for you. I wanted to give you these flowers...' 'Where did they come from?' 'I broke a rule. One of the other girls brought them in for me. They're from the florist.' 'Well, I'll close my eyes this time. But don't do it again.' She was exultant. 'I don't dare,' she said. 'I really don't dare. Come in. Let's see what it is you've brought me.' Her room was crammed with doilies, with cambrics, with lawns, with veils over every little aperture, with ribbons, with embroidered cushions, till you felt yourself sweating with sheer femininity. She cut the string around the cardboard box with her embroidery scissors. She lifted the paper: her long hands were all covetousness. 'Roses...' I leaned over the flowers I had sacrificed to her. She hadn't the courage to awaken them. 'It's too much. I ought to scold you. Really, it's too much.' Silly goose, I thought. She made as if to shake my hand. I went to sleep as usual during the afternoon classes, recharging my energies with refreshing naps in the back row. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="5">
                <p>At four o'clock, Isabelle was waiting for me at the classroom door. 'I'm taking you to see the doctor,' she said. 'We've been so happy here,' I said through the surrounding din. 'It's an order,' Isabelle said. 'I'm going up to the dormitory to get dressed, and you would do well to come too.' The bonds between us were loosening; the strength had all drained from my heart. The idea of going out into the town with her was inconceivable. I found her again up in the dormitory. Isabelle had emerged from her cubicle with her hair un-pinned, hiding her shoulders like an Arab horseman's cape. Isabelle was reassuring me by appearing exactly as she had during our first moments together: she was stroking the handle of her hairbrush. 'We're going out. Remember that we're going out,' she said. 'Don't go back into your cubicle. Let me go on seeing you forever,' I said. The hand holding the brush fell to her side. The light died in her hair. I ran towards her. 'Go into your cubicle then. Be beautiful without my seeing you,' I said. Isabelle threw down her brush in the aisle. She wound her scarf of hair around my neck. 'I want to strangle you. I really do,' she said. But she didn't pull the hair any tighter. This intimacy in the dormitory aisle made me feel lost. I led Isabelle by the hand and showed her the bunch of roses. 'I gave them to her at half past one. You're not angry, are you?' 'Angry! They're only flowers,' she said without turning around. The veil hanging down her shoulders lifted with each step, her hair was more moving than the roses. I went into my cubicle. 'This visit is worrying me sick.' 'Not me. I want very much to go out for a walk with you, and that's what we shall do. We'll say that the doctor was called out on an emergency. I'll take care of all that.' Isabelle came back. She lifted my cubicle curtain. 'Aren't you getting dressed? Do you want me to help you?' 'I can't get used to the idea. I'm a little afraid.' She seized hold of my wrist. 'Afraid! Can't you sense that I'm ready to give up everything?' 'Even your studies?' 'Especially my studies, because that would be the hardest,' Isabelle said. 'I would never want you to. I never will want you to,' I said. We got ourselves ready. The shouts from the recreation yard no longer concerned us. 'I'm putting her in your charge,' the house mistress told Isabelle. 'You have the letter with the name of the street and the number. You'll find him at home. He's expecting you. Come back with good news for us.' 'Will you allow us to take a little walk around the town?' Isabelle asked. 'Provided you don't abuse the privilege. No running away now!' she cried after us. We crossed the main quadrangle very sedately, but the flowers, the lawn, and the trees all flew away. The porter touched his cap to us. We walked along under the wall of the school, we. heard the voice of one of the piano teachers as he beat time with the ebony ruler that was always lying on the upright piano. 'Aren't you pleased to be out?' 'It was so nice inside.' We passed under the walls of St. Nicolas's: there were priests teaching and boys going wild inside. 'Can I give you my arm?' 'We have to be careful,' Isabelle said. A tram, the tinkling bell that we listened to from the recreation yard, was climbing the hill to the school. Other girls would be hearing its low refrain. The sleeping houses gave way to little shops, the lament of the tram against its tracks faded away beyond the school: we were in the town. Isabelle stopped to examine the window of a glove and leather-goods shop. She wanted me to look at this graveyard of black kid objects with her. 'Do you care for that sort of thing?' 'I care for, I care for... You know what it is I care for,' Isabelle said. I was proud to feel myself one of a couple against the town. 'Will you forget me? I'll never forget you,' Isabelle said. She gazed down at a diamanté clasp. 'You will live inside me always. You'll die with me,' I said. I closed my eyes, I imagined her talking to me under her breath in the darkness of the dormitory. I slipped my arm under hers, I kneaded her gloved hand, I thrust my finger into the diamond-shaped opening and pressed it into her palm. The lady in the glove shop, having nothing else to do, was watching us. 'The headmistress would say that we're not behaving properly. Yes, give me your arm,' Isabelle said. We set off again, we leaped over the light above a steeple. The gentle tingling of an ambulance bell punctuated our ecstasies; the clangour of the milk cans jostling against one another on a cart, and the driver dozing, up on his seat, filled me with nostalgia for pools of buttercups. We ran so as to make our freedom pant for breath, we ran along by the cones of anthracite in the railway yard, we flashed by their dark blue glitter, we stopped and drew ourselves up tall beside those pyramids of pride. I remember a coal man with a battered old face who was intrigued by us as he walked past us into the yard; I remember his white eyes and the handcart he was pushing along with the tips of his fingers. 'What shall we do now?' Isabelle said. 'I don't know.' 'I know,' she said. 'Are we going for a walk? Are we going into the waiting room? Are we going to buy tickets to go on the platform? Are we going to have tea in a tearoom?' She brushed all my suggestions aside with a wave of her hand. 'I have an address,' Isabelle said. 'Say something. I have an address for the two of us. Doesn't that please you?' We were trotting along beside the flint-studded wall of a factory. A plank fell in the distance. 'We're going to a hotel,' Isabelle said. 'But not a hotel exactly. To a house.' I moved away from her. 'Don't you want to?' 'I don't know what it is.' 'It's a house with a lady who lets out rooms. She'll be nice to us.' 'How do you know?' 'It's a business. She has to be nice,' Isabelle said. We had come to a square with'a circle of trees in it all cut back to mere stumps. 'Have you made up your mind?' 'I don't dare,' I said. We were walking furiously around the mutilated trees. 'Well! Is it yes or no?' 'It was so nice back at school...' 'It will be better here than it was there,' Isabelle said. I took her purse, held it in one hand with my own wallet, and slipped my arm under hers: our intertwining fingers made love to one another. 'Aren't you hungry? There are teashops,' I said in the feeble hope of deflecting her from her path. 'I'm never hungry now. Not since I met you. Here it is. Yes, this is definitely it,' 'Algazine, Dresses and Coats: that's the address?' 'Ring the bell, for heaven's sake. Go on, it's on your side.' I couldn't bring myself to do it. 'Excuse me,' a man with a beard said, 'excuse me. Unless you've rung the bell already. In which case.' 'It's been rung,' Isabelle replied. The man raised his hat, the door opened on its own. 'Ladies first,' the man said. He stood aside, raising his hat again as he did so. Isabelle pushed me forward. I went in first. Hanging on a hall stand were several tattered raincoats that seemed to have been sheltering there from the rain for a very long time; below them, sticking out in every direction like the separate ears of a wheatsheaf, were a number of canes topped with gold knobs or animal heads carved in wood and silver. The man with the beard was wiping his feet. 'You know the way, of course,' he insinuated in a syrupy voice that was quite unlike the voice he had used outside. 'No!' Isabelle said. We stood back against the wall, feeling the damp from it strike into our backs as he went off down the corridor with his hat in his hand and his briefcase under one arm. He crooked his index finger, hesitated, then knocked twice on a glazed door camouflaged with imitation stained-glass paper. 'Come in, come in The voice seemed to emerge from a mountain of kindliness. He pulled at his beard, then opened the door. 'After you, after you...' He stared at the minimal cleavage of Isabelle's blouse. I was still expecting dressmaker's dummies, tumbling lengths of cloth and reels of cotton; but there was nothing to be seen except plants, bushes in pots, birds and cages. 'I'll go and look for her,' the man said. He walked through into a little courtyard delightfully crammed with begonias, with ivy, with ivy geraniums, with potted vines, with ferns, with watering cans, and with stands for the plants. 'Let's go now!' I said. 'Wait till she comes,' Isabelle said sharply. She was looking at a picture of orange rocks being washed by waves of blue jam. The birds singing in the cages were offering their comments on this picture. 'No, no, please don't get up,' the lady said. 'And do excuse me. I was attending to all my lovely ladies.' She gestured towards her plants with the long string of pearls that hung down from her neck to well below her waist. 'You mustn't make such a noise when I have company,' she said to the birds. The man with his briefcase under one arm and his hat in his hand bowed goodbye to us: then he was gone as suddenly as he had arrived. 'Mlle Paulette wasn't in. He's heartbroken,' said the woman. Her face looked as though someone had forgotten to finish carving it. Despite her great height, her age, and her weight, she jumped up and sat on the table. 'I'm at your disposal.' Isabelle stood up. 'We're here to take a room.' Mme Algazine played with her necklace and considered us. 'We want to rent it for about an hour,' Isabelle said. The cage hooked on to the ring of the ceiling light swayed to and fro; the bird twittered away beneath the porcelain dome. 'I see,' Mme Algazine said. She threw the string of pearls back over one shoulder. 'You're minors,' she said. She fled into the little courtyard. Isabelle ground her teeth. But Mme Algazine returned carrying a juicy lettuce leaf, which she pushed between the bars of the cage. Then she disappeared into the courtyard again with the same agility. I stood up, I called: 'Madame!' 'Right away, my little ones, right away,' she called back in a patronizing tone. 'Madame!' Isabelle said firmly. She reappeared again. 'I told you that we want to rent a room.' Mme Algazine opened her eyes wide. 'Why didn't you tell me that when you first came in, my little ones?' 'We did tell you.' The wings were battering, now and again, against the cage bars; the wound in our spirits was grey. 'Are you minors?... Yes, of course you are.' 'Yes,' we both answered in chorus. 'Are you boarders up at the school? ... You're wearing the school uniform.' 'We'll pay you. We have money,' Isabelle said. 'You can pay afterwards,' Mme Algazine said. Isabelle opened her jacket, but I moved in front of her. Mme Algazine was to see nothing of that throat but its shield. 'Would you like a little port to drink, a few cookies to eat, up in your room?' 'We'll eat and drink whatever you like,' Isabelle said. 'Show us where to go.' 'We are unsociable, aren't we?...' Mme Algazine opened the glazed door and gestured towards the staircase with her pearls, holding them as though they were a hosepipe. 'Electricity is very expensive, and kerosene, and oil, and matches. Everything is expensive,' Mme Algazine said, speaking with the voice of her true nature. The staircase was dark. On the landing, we made our way gingerly past dilapidated rooms and brass bedsteads with disemboweled mattresses, we bumped against packing cases full of crockery, lumps of fallen plaster, and tattered flags. Mme Algazine led the way, glancing at everything absentmindedly as she went. 'Yours will be the first door,' she said. 'Thank you, oh thank you,' Isabelle said. 'I'll bring you the port in a moment.' Mme Algazine disappeared once more, old and alone, down her dismal staircase. Isabelle removed the key from the lock and went in first. 'Two beds!' she said. She tried to close the door but couldn't manage it. She tossed the key on the mantel, but it fell to the floor. Then she hurled her schoolgirl's hat to the other end of the room and pushed the table in front of the door. 'Take it off,' she said, half reproachfully. 'We're not here on a formal visit.' She sent my hat flying against the wardrobe mirror and undid my hair. 'Lie down with me on the floor,' she said. My mouth met her mouth as a dead leaf does the earth. We bathed together in that long kiss, we recited our wordless litanies together, we were greedy of each other's bodies, we smeared our faces with the saliva we were exchanging, we gazed at one another without recognition. 'There's someone moving about in the next room,' I said. She sat up. It was agony for her when I made her wait. 'Me, Isabelle. Not you.' I crushed her beneath me as though she were fighting me. 'Someone really is moving about in the next room. Look Isabelle, look. There in the wall?' 'It's just a little round window,' she said. 'They can see us. I'm sure they're looking at us.' I stretched myself on top of her, hiding her from other eyes. 'Who are "they"?' Isabelle asked in suave tones. 'I don't know. The people in the room. Listen! The noise our bed makes in the dormitory.' Isabelle opened her eyes. She was surprised at the way I was behaving. 'Forget other people, for goodness' sake, and lie down here with me properly,' Isabelle said. She began clawing at me, or else scraping her nails against the tiled floor. 'Our bed at night... Please, Isabelle: listen.' There was a knock. 'Open the door,' Isabelle said. 'It's the port.' Someone was trying to push open the door. Then came a voice. 'What have you done here? Have you barricaded yourselves in?' I picked up the key and pulled at the table. Mme Algazine stretched her neck through the aperture I had made. 'You can come out and bring the tray in off the landing yourselves, since you've locked yourselves in.' Isabelle, still lying in the middle of the room crossed her arms over her face. I picked up the tray. I could hear the groans of the bed from the room next door. I went back into our room. 'Don't you want some port? Don't you want to get up?' 'I want you to come here,' Isabelle said. 'The noise our bed makes at night...' 'It's not the noise our bed makes at night,' Isabelle said. I listened harder. The regular rhythm next door wasn't at all like the broken rhythm in Isabelle's cubicle. 'Who is it?' 'A couple.' The bed was silent. I went on listening. 'Come here,' Isabelle said. 'Leave your clothes on.' I went to her: my sex was scorching her dress. 'Melt into me, melt into me all over,' Isabelle moaned. Her smile grew wider and wider as I possessed her all over through her dress: I was burying her beneath my arms and my legs. I buried myself in her neck. 'The noise is beginning again.' I couldn't tear myself away from that relentless cadence. 'Listen!' 'I don't hear anything,' Isabelle said. I was a prisoner of that rhythm, condemned to follow it, to desire it, to fear it, to move towards it. 'Let's drink our port,' Isabelle said. I was too intent on the sounds next door. 'Drink!' Isabelle commanded. I obeyed. I felt a golden warmth in my chest, the colour of wallflowers warmed by the sun. 'Listen! Someone cried out.' Isabelle shrugged her shoulders. 'I don't hear anything.' She wandered around the room. Someone was sighing, someone was moaning. Isabelle leaned over the iron bedstead: she felt about in her purse. 'Not so loud. Someone's moaning,' I said. There was someone imprisoned in that room next to ours, someone who was trying to escape and not succeeding. Isabelle was filing her nails. 'Stop me hearing it!' I said. 'Oh, you have a new nail file...' 'I have several,' Isabelle said. She went on filing her thumbnail. The final moan rose up till it touched the North Star. Isabelle's file went on nibbling into the silence. Isabelle replaced the nail file in her purse. 'We're wasting our time. Why did we rent this room?' 'I don't know any more,' I said. Isabelle slapped me. 'I don't know, I don't know any more...' She slapped me again. 'It's a couple. There's a couple making love next door,' I said. She seized the edge of a small table and pushed it so violently that it fell against the marble fireplace. Isabelle's fury held me spellbound. 'Undress me,' she said. I undressed her, hanging each garment over the bedstead rail as I took it off. She was naked, stern, very tall and straight in the middle of the room. I took her by the hand, I led her after me,-and with the other hand, as we passed it, I pulled the table upright again. I fell on Isabelle, I unclothed the shape of her legs and ankles while watching myself in the mirror. The room was old, the mirror gave me back reflections of the flanks and the caresses of other couples. I took her leg in my arms and stroked it with my chin, with my cheek, with my lips. I was a violinist caressing a bow, and the mirror let me watch what I was doing: the slaps Isabelle had given me were still exciting me. 'You're going away from me,' she said. In the mirror, I could see her hands clasped over her fleece, and I experienced a wave of solitary pleasure. 'Aren't you going to undress too?' Isabelle asked. I kissed her knee, I looked at myself in the mirror, and I loved myself as I looked. 'You're ignoring me,' Isabelle said. I tore myself away from the mirror, from that sex, that entrance to such sweet depths. But it continued to draw me towards it, to call me back for further solitary caresses. I stroked Isabelle's secret lips and hair with her finger. I felt the burden of pleasure lying heavy on the back of my neck. 'What are you doing?' 'Go to sleep for a moment.' 'I begin to wonder if you really love me,' Isabelle said. I didn't want to say I did. Isabelle sat up on the pillow and crossed her legs. Pressed together like that, their shape intimidated me. 'Look up! What is all this nonsense?' Isabelle said. Someone opened a door, then closed it. 'The couple next door!' Isabelle stifled a yawn. 'Yes, a couple who've made love.' She opened her thighs. 'If you don't want to, say so?' I plunged into her sex. I would have preferred it to be less complicated. I almost felt a desire to sew it up here and there. 'My lovely carp, my beautiful underwater mouth. I'm coming back. I'm back. The couple has gone... We're alone... There was my pink monster. I loved it as it devoured me. I worshipped it with wide-open eyes. 'You're biting. You're hurting me,' Isabelle said. 'Oh, that was wrong of me, my fragile little monster. It was wrong of me, my anemone, when you're so moist, so moist, so moist...' 'Yes... Like you did in the music room, like you did in the music room... Gently... gently... That's almost it. Almost, almost...' 'You're talking too much, Isabelle.' My face plunged once more into the holy image. I licked, then I stopped a while to rest, but resting was a sin. 'Is that it?' 'Yes, that's it.' I began once again where I had left off: I had a sun to light up. I could see what Isabelle was seeing and what Isabelle was hearing with the sight and the hearing of our sexes; I was expecting what she was expecting. 'Go on... go on...' A cat washing itself, a cat pressing down and rubbing blindly away with its tongue. 'Slowly, slowly,' Isabelle chanted as though she were in church. I kept going like a scratched record repeating itself. Her pleasure was beginning inside me, I came up for breath. 'Someone's listening, Isabelle!' She closed her legs. She contracted. 'Open the door and look,' Isabelle said. I waited there, on my knees, fully dressed. 'Open the door and come back quickly. I'm waiting for you,' Isabelle said. 'The door's too far away. You want me to go on!' I made myself into a snake charmer for her, I played seductive melodies inside the folds of her flesh with my finger, I caressed the sex that I was watching in the mirror. I was keeping a lookout. I saw the mist of someone's breath coming under the door, and I could see it in the mirror too. 'Come and lie down beside me,' Isabelle said. 'There's someone there. I saw him.' 'You're torturing me!' Isabelle said. She had turned over and was lying on her stomach. I stood up beside the bed. I couldn't bring myself to take my clothes ofi.. 'I ought to strangle you,' Isabelle said. She turned over on her back. 'Are we leaving? Shall I get dressed?' 'Don't take your hair away from me. Don't pin it up.' 'I must do my hair,' Isabelle said. 'You've had enough of me.' 'Oh, what have I done! There was someone there. I didn't dream it,' I said. 'You were daydreaming.' I collapsed on the bed. 'Don't stop me... Take away your hands and forgive me. I'll make love to you. You can teach me. Yes, I will lie down with you. You're beautiful. Your legs are beautiful too. I do want to. Guide my finger. I want to give and receive, give and receive.' I abandoned her once more. I ran to and fro across the room, then I snatched up her clothes and threw them over her, over the trail of saliva. 'Oh, you're being devilish. I shall end up cursing you,' Isabelle said, tensing all her muscles in fury. 'Someone can see us, someone's looking at us,' I whined. 'Where?' Isabelle had turned back on her stomach: she was shaking the bars of the bed. 'There's an eye there. I can see it.' 'Be quiet, be quiet, be quiet! Almost... Almost... It's beginning, it's beginning,' Isabelle said. She turned on her back, bending her knees and pulling them up against her stomach. She was devouring herself. 'It's my fault if you didn't have it,' I said: 'I didn't have it, and it's your fault,' Isabelle said. 'At the little window... The eye...' Isabelle had got up and was walking across the room with naked dignity. 'It's just hunger, just your tiredness, my poor Thérèse. I don't see anything. This window is covered with dust and spider's webs:' Isabelle lay down on the bed again and pulled the eiderdown over her. 'Don't you really want to get undressed? It's warm under here,' she said. She wriggled one foot seductively beneath the satinette. 'It's so nice under here... What are you doing standing up?' 'I'm afraid of the eye.' 'For goodness' sake, come over here!' She reached out from the bed and seized my hand. 'Let's go, Isabelle. Let's escape from this house. I'll help you to dress out on the landing,' I said tenderly. She let go of my hand. 'A moment ago you were frightened of the landing.' 'Now it's the little window,' I said. She shrugged her shoulders. 'You're afraid of everything.' I saw it, the eye.' Isabelle laughed. Do you mind if we go?' I said. She turned her back on me. I escaped out onto the landing. She came out after me, but she came naked. Her mons Veneris bulged beneath its hair. It was as though it might be containing a life of its own. 'I'm cold because of you,' Isabelle said. She led me back in by the hand. 'We'll do it together,' she said in what she tried to make enticing tones: 'I'm afraid of the room.' 'Together... at the same time... We'll cry out as much as we like. We'll cry out together.' We were back in the room. 'I'd rather leave now.' 'Yes, it would be better,' Isabelle said. She was dressing. I escaped out to the landing again, leaving her to the intimacy of her garter belt, to her regrets. But every particle of that house was a peeping tom. 'Your handkerchief, your hat... Where are you, little scary cat?' She was looking for me on the landing. Her hand brushed my hair, the mauve scent of her rice powder was breaking my arms and my legs. She held out her closed fist for me to lean on and pull myself up. We kissed 'Let's look just once more,' Isabelle said. The abandoned room had become virgin once again. We risked the blackness of the stairs, we avoided crushing the hundred tiny wings of our reconciliation, we led our spring-. time safely back to its source. 'You had a room with two beds... Is that right?' 'A single one and a double one,' Isabelle said. 'Do you have any money?' Isabelle produced hers and I produced mine. 'Which should I take?' 'Both.' 'Yes, both,' Isabelle said. 'Was the bed comfortable?' Mme Algazine looked at us. She was counting the bills we had handed her. 'Yes,' I said under my breath, 'it was comfortable.' Isabelle pushed her hat firmly down on her forehead. 'No. Your beds are not comfortable,' she said. Mme Algazine scratched at her chin with our bills. 'We're in a hurry. Would you open the door, please,' Isabelle said. Mme Algazine went on tickling her chin with the money. 'Was the port good?' 'Excellent, but we have to leave now,' Isabelle said. 'The door's open,' Mme Algazine said by way of farewell. 'We have a half hour left to buy things. We mustn't dawdle,' Isabelle said. 'What things?' 'You'll see,' Isabelle said. Her gloved hand seized hold of mine. 'Give me your purse... Let me carry it.' 'You like that? Carrying my purse?' she said. It was six o'clock in the evening: the light was becoming half-hearted and the houses looked bored. I stole a flower from a big privet bush on the street along by the coalyard. I put it in Isabelle's palm and closed her fingers over it as a sign of our betrothal. '... I was counting the nights we shall have together before the summer vacation,' she said. 'There are masses and masses.' She led me into the best teashop in the town. The little tables hadn't been cleared, the echoes of the gossip that had been exchanged over them still persisted, and the scent of Virginia tobacco was still mingling with the scents worn by the lady customers who had by now departed. 'Why have we come here? Are you hungry?' 'No,' Isabelle said. 'Neither am I.' 'Give me my purse all the same,' Isabelle said. I gave it to her and fled from the teashop. At last I could buy the two roses I had wanted for her. I caught sight of her again just as I was paying for them. Isabelle was looking for me and biting her lips. The love I felt for her was dispassionate, but it was love. I hid the flowers under my jacket. 'That wasn't very clever,' she said. 'Why did you run off?' We walked back up the street with the glove and leather-goods shop on it. 'Let's stop here a moment. Choose any purse you like and I'll buy it for you. I'll carry it for you when we're alone in the corridors back at school,' I said. 'Anyone would think you were offering me something to remember you by. As though you were about to say goodbye. 'I don't want you to buy me anything,' Isabelle said. The saleslady was replacing a round box-calf handbag in the corner of the window. 'Let's go back to school now. It's time we did,' Isabelle said. 'Yes, let's. Come on, why are you just standing there like that?' 'I'm afraid of the future,' Isabelle said. 'Afraid... you!' 'I'm unhappy, Thérèse.' The town split in two. 'If you're unhappy, I shall die.' 'Don't talk. Hold my arm tight and look at the window. We ought to go back to school now, and yet it seems to me that we ought not to. I'm afraid,' Isabelle said again. 'Let's run away from school. We won't die of hunger.' 'They'd catch us. We'd be parted right away. Make me warm,' Isabelle said. 'Don't be unhappy.' 'Be careful! Look, in the reflection... We've attracted their attention,' Isabelle said. It was raining admonitory fingers. But our self-assurance charmed the cobbles and won the day. The azure between the branches above ruffled our hair. 'Shall we run away?' 'Where would we go?' 'To Mme Algazine's.' 'Not a very good idea.' The school reappeared before us and we felt ourselves once more a part of that great anonymous family poring over its books in the study hall before dinner. I made a detour up to the dormitory to hide the roses in my dirty-linen bag. At seven o'clock, Isabelle walked into the refectory after everyone else. I threw my napkin under the table. I bent down for it so that I could whisper to myself that I would carry her purse for her, that I would carry the evening breeze too, if the breeze was too heavy for her. She was coming. I counted her steps along the middle aisle. Fifteen drumrolls went through my heart. Fifteen times I was executed before she reached her place. The same great city of love was coming towards me: my breast strained forward to meet her. Isabelle was looking at that patch of fervent blue: Isabelle was loving me as the sun set beyond the stained glass. The assistant in charge called out my name from the other end of the hall. 'You'd better wake up,' one of the girls said. Isabelle was calling me too: Isabelle was draining me of colour. 'Do you love me? Do you still love me?' I begged with my eyes. The assistant told me that I wasn't to do any private studying that evening, that I was to go up to the dormitory and rest, that it was an order from the house mistress. </p>
            </div>
            <div type="chapter" n="6">
                <p>The day was failing, my cubicle was wasting away, tiny feathers were flying up into the air from my absent beloved's lips. Night was taking over. Night: our swansdown covering. Night: our canopy of seagulls. I switched on my flashlight, trained it on the flowers I had bought, and savoured the festive atmosphere they created. Outside, the roses in the gardens were lapped in night. I embarked upon a long, bride-to-be's toilette, I hid sprigs of orange blossom in my armpits and between my legs as I rubbed the soapsuds there, I crossed my cubicle with my cool and scented train behind me, I walked up the aisle holding a sceptre of our future, I went into Isabelle's cubicle: her things were austere, her bed an orphan. I lost all notion of time. I waited for her there, my face hidden in my hands. The girls came rushing in like invaders, the assistant had switched on the lights. I could no longer escape, There were girls running along the aisle, shrieking and laughing. 'You! In my cubicle!' Arm outstretched, gripping the curtain she had just slid brutally along its rod, she stood in the opening offering me the wild, end-of-day disorder of her hair, her lost child's face, the alertness of her eyes. The cord of my robe fell on her bedside rug. Isabelle looked at my nightgown. 'Oh,' she exclaimed, 'how white it is...' She threw me down on her bed, she entered me, but withdrew again immediately. One of the little girls had pulled the curtain aside and was looking at us. She fled, screaming as she did so: 'Blood, I saw some blood.' 'Back to your cubicle!' Isabelle ordered. Isabelle was gazing at her three blood-covered fingers. I escaped. 'What's going on?' the assistant asked. She was coming out of her room. She was walking up the aisle. I slipped into bed and examined the red stain on my night-gown. 'Just a cut. It's all over now,' Isabelle said. 'Is it serious?' the assistant asked. There was an agonizing silence. 'I bleed very easily,' Isabelle said. I got out of bed and repaired the ravages inflicted on me by my Valkyrie. 'Isabelle...' The new assistant made the name she had stolen from me sound insipid on her tongue. 'Yes,' Isabelle replied very matter-of-factly, still cleaning her teeth. 'Was it really only a cut?' the assistant asked. 'It was nothing at all,' Isabelle said, her mouth full of foam. The other girls were chattering away beneath the energetic tang of eau de Cologne in the air; Isabelle got into bed, and the groan it gave didn't matter. The assistant began her rounds. 'Good night, mademoiselle,' I heard a girl murmur. The lights in the aisle were switched off. A girl on some rash quest of love brushed against my curtain, leaving a little of her secret in its folds. The whisperings sank at last into an abyss. The dormitory abandoned itself to sleep. I too was struck down by sleep. I dreamed: Isabelle was holding my wrist, stroking my hand and the two roses to and fro across my sex. I woke up panting with hunger and longing. I waited by my window with the roses, imagining Isabelle's arrival. The curtain was lifted aside just at the momerit when my mind's eye was seeing the self-same thing. Isabelle had come in, and centuries of love were set asighing. Isabelle in her nightclothes, with the Byron collar of her nightgown pulled out over the revers of her robe, Isabelle with the preoccupied face of a queen. 'Good evening.' 'Good evening.' I laid the roses down on the bed, let myself slide to the floor, and covered her feet with a layer of kisses. Isabelle was glad to let me worship her. The flowers fell to the floor, the rustling of their leaves made us afraid that the assistant might wake up; but then the darkness offered me the surprise of Isabelle's face close to mine. 'You put your little girl's nightgown on,' she said. She fingered its cool folds. Her cheek followed the slope that led from crotch to knee. The water lily was about to open deep inside me, the veil of the White Lady of Avenel was about to trail over my demesne. 'Come,' Isabelle said gallantly. We crossed the aisle and went into Isabelle's cubicle. The linen mat on the table looked like a cloud, the pillow was all innocence. She broke the stems of the roses. Where had my roses come from? When had she picked up the glass from her dressing table? When had she poured out the water? When had she leaned over the basin? I gazed at Isabelle in the darkness of every country in the world. 'Where are you?' she said. I shook the darkness from my shoulders as one shakes the snow from a cape; in those roses leaning over the edge of their glass I had the roses that suited me, roses for a girl at boarding school. 'Smell them,' Isabelle said. I was paralysed with wonder. 'Smell them!' She put the glass and the roses into my hands, she tossed back her hair, she let me see her Byron collar, she let me see her neck. My flashlight and the glass clinked together. I was drawing bronze garlands, I was trailing wrought-iron roses around her neck. 'We must begin, we must begin,' I said severely. Isabelle was protecting her neck. She stepped back. The storm was steadily rising, the whole sky was whirling inside me in a single cloud. We were calling to one another with the whites of our eyes. It was time either to die or to make a move. I went closer to her. 'Open your collar.' I closed my eyes, listening to hear if she was opening her nightgown collar or not. 'I'm waiting,' Isabelle said. The rose-coloured eye was watching me, the roses in the glass were leaning towards us. My arms fell to my sides; I was ready to be their martyr. They sent their beams of warmth washing over me, and already their silkiness was weighing down my empty hands. I set off towards them and found that, like fruit, they had ripened. They were swelling: they were to be our midnight sun. Isabelle, her back against the wall, was watching them just as I was watching them. 'Button your collar,' I said. The night was rejuvenated suddenly, as it had been on other evenings, by whispers from one of the other girls. Isabelle smiled down at her breasts. I know where I would make love to her if I still had her: I would make love to her under the bellies of a flock of sheep. Isabelle unbuttoned my nightgown, hesitantly, greedily. I didn't help her: I was taking pleasure in this greed for possession being displayed by a queen in disarray. A sigh dropped from the tree of silence, two breasts hurled themselves out into space, four sources of sweetness glowed with warmth. There was absinthe flowing through my veins. 'Better than that,' Isabelle begged. It did not leave my lips as we fell slowly down on the floor. I kept it fast in my hands, I held firm to its heavy weight of warmth, of pallor, of tenderness. My belly was crying out for invading warmth. 'Stroke it,' Isabelle said. 'No!' I opened my mouth and let the breast in. I was biting into those precious veins, remembering their blueness as it stifled me. My hand moved away like a curl of smoke, my hand fell away like a departing echo. Oh, what eyes, what peeping toms crowding there in the shadows above us!... 'You're looking down. What is there to be afraid of?' Isabelle said. I was possessed by a secret and frenzied longing for her neck. There were lodestones under Isabelle's chin that drew me up to them. My flashlight fell on the rug. 'You'll get us caught!' Isabelle said. 'Your neck...' She accepted my homage coolly. Without admitting it, I searched for the furrow between her breasts, and it was this hypocritical gaze of mine that caused her to fold in the revers of her robe. The portcullis between her eyes and mine was raised: we had recovered the power to love and look at one another freely. My gaze came flowing back to me like a wave that has bruised itself on the beach. I was subduing the mirrors in her eyes, and she was subduing the mirrors in mine. Isabelle sat on my knees. 'Say we've got lots of time. Say it.' I didn't answer. The darkness chilled our lips as we kissed. 'I'm counting the hours we still have ahead,' Isabelle said. Time was coming towards us and swirling past with its black crepe scarves. I wound Isabelle's long hair around her neck to protect her. 'Stay, stay awhile longer,' Isabelle said. We hugged one another as tightly as we could, but we could find no shelter from the great tide of time and its passing hours. The darkness in the main quadrangle, the darkness in the town broke over us. 'I'm cold,' Isabelle said. We heard the wind flapping in the shroud of a tree. 'I'm afraid of the time going by,' Isabelle said. I forced out a laugh. I switched on my flashlight. Isabelle looked at her watch. 'It's eleven, Thérèse. Switch it off now.' She stood up. My knees felt so light I was bewildered. I fell at her feet. I became the twine around a sheaf of wheat. 'My mouth wants you inside it,' Isabelle said. I heard the rustling of a mass of black crepe. It was Isabelle throwing back her hair. She rattled the battery inside the flashlight. 'I must put the watch forward,' I said. 'I must.' She handed me the watch. 'What have we gained by that?' 'We shall be keeping ahead of time,' I told her. How was I to soften up the limbs of this doe made of spun glass? My touch brought no response; but with my jeweller's tongue I dropped glistening gems into her mouth. She wiped her lips with my hand, feigning indifference. 'Don't go on.' She slipped out of my arms: I found myself alone and powerless against the waves of languor ravaging my belly. Isabelle hung herself around my neck. My lips returned to the place they had just left. Our mouths, as they met, opened into an accommodating dream. I tilted her backwards without relinquishing those lips, I held her head in my hands as I always did, as I would have held the weight of a head shorn from its body. I made my way inside. I encountered a faint taste of toothpaste, a memory of faded freshness. Our limbs were ripening, our corpses were deliquescing. Exquisite decay. I half opened my eyes: Isabelle was watching me. I had declared war inside her mouth, and I had been defeated. There was oriental music undulating through my bones, its singsong circling slowly through my elbows, through my knees. I had grace flowing in my blood, my death was yielding itself up to corruption. I was purifying her gums, I wanted to annihilate Isabelle even further with my kiss. I thanked her twice with two more busy kisses on her hands. Tiny heads turned to look: the sparrows of the night were watching us. We got into the bed and lay listening to the coolness of the sheets. The darkness was bending down and keeping watch over us, the darkness was whispering suggestions of a chaste finale in our ears. Isabelle took my hand and pressed it against her belly, against the golden hairs. 'Don't move,' she said. My hand willed itself as warm and moist as the air of a cowshed. Isabelle came towards me with her arm spread-eagled against mine, with her guileless hand, with a dream that alighted on my belly, on my secret hairs. 'Be quiet, be quiet!' Isabelle was talking to our two lordly hands, each spread-eagled across its own demesne. I felt my calves turning to soft lint. I was a pear tree agains a wall, weighed down by summer's heat. The baying hounds... have mercy... that I could no longer hold in check. I waited intently, longingly, for a movement from that delicate hand. My heart was beating beneath my eyelids, in my throat. 'I can't stand it any more!' I shattered everything: our hands, our arms, the golden hairs, the silence, the night. We moved apart, we waitied for one another, we sensed the crevasse of terror that lay between us. It the thread of that wait were to snap, we would both hurtle down into the depths of the earth. I turned over on my stomach and hid away inside myself with my fever. Isabelle dragged me into the centre of the bed, straddled across me, then pulled me up towards her so that I could feel the cold air under my arms. You were mounting me, Isabelle: there was nothing new in that. I was carrying a burden of memories on my back. In meeting you I found a meaning to my nothingness. Isabelle was sawing my shoulders, arching herself against me, climbing me, opening herself, thrusting herself against me, breathing me in, rocking, and rocking me with her. The little lamps were beginning to glow again, the sea monster inside me was coiling its tentacles around my entrails once more. 'Don't leave me now,' I said. Night, womb of silence. Isabelle pulled herself up, slowly, slowly, till I felt her secret lips close against my buttock. Isabelle toppled on to the bed. I felt for her hand, I put it against my back, I guided it down beyond the end of my spine, I left it pressed against the edge of my anus. 'Yes,' Isabelle said. I waited patiently, letting calm seep into me. 'It's something new,' Isabelle said. The timid finger entered me. Isabelle spoke. 'My finger is warm, my finger is happy.' But it was too timid to venture farther. We listened to it inside me, savouring the pleasure it gave us. The finger would always be an intruder in that miserly scabbard. I contracted my muscles so as to encourage it, I tightened my muscles so as to imprison it. 'Farther in, I want to be farther in,' Isabelle moaned with her mouth crushed against the back of my neck. She thrust against the impossible. There was still the knuckle, still the prison outside from which she couldn't escape. We were at the mercy of the finger's inadequacy. The weight on my back signified that the finger had not given up. Furiously, it struck and struck again. I had a maddened eel battering itself to death against my inner walls. My eyes heard, my ears saw: Isabelle was injecting me with her own brutality. Let the finger arrow through the town, let the finger pierce the slaughter yards. The rubbing was burning and painful; our limitations were even more painful still. But the stubborn finger awakened my flesh, each of its blows made my pleasure sharper than before. I felt the intoxication seeping deep into my inside, I was filled with spices and birdsong, I was stretched open as wide as my thighs. 'The bed's moving about too much,' Isabelle said. The dilated flesh gave thanks, the sharp pleasure to come was being created in its petals. Drops of sweat dripped from Isabelle's forehead on to my back. 'Don't move. Let me stay in you,' Isabelle said. We hibernated for a while. Then I contracted my muscles to bring the spring. 'Oh yes!' Isabelle said. I drew it into myself, I forced it out again, I transformed it into the sex of a dog, red and naked. It mounted inside me till it was almost in my throat. I listened to Isabelle making herself light, following its ascent, enjoying this reflected pleasure. The finger emerged from a cloud, then sank into another. My ardour had sparked an answering flame in Isabelle, there was a maddened sun whirling through my flesh. Isabelle's body laboured up a solitary Calvary on my back. I was hung all over with grey. My legs weakened in their paradise. My calves were ripening, now that they had drunk their fill. I was wholly softened into ineffable decay. There was no end to it as I crumbled from bliss into bliss until I was all dust. Isabelle's finger methodically withdrew, but my knees still swam in pools of pleasure. It had left me. Its departure was a slow barge laden with harmonies. We listened to the final chord fading away. 'You didn't have yours.' 'I didn't have mine?' Isabelle said, stifling her laughter against my neck, her face aglow with tropical madness. 'Didn't have it!!' She pressed my hand between her lips, then my mouth avoided hers. We didn't mix the different moments. 'Suffocate me,' Isabelle said. She rested while I suffocated her, while I tried to flatten her into a beauty spot on my left breast. I crushed her to me, quivering like the tips of brittle grass in winter. 'Yes, you do love me,' Isabelle said. I pushed myself up, I could feel the diamonds of the cold against my shoulders. I was remembering, I was seeing myself again under the apple tree: my mother used to take me out into a meadow for a very personal celebration, when the winter wind was still buffeting at April, when the summer breeze was still holding November in a trance. We used to settle ourselves down twice a year under the same apple tree, and there we unpacked our little feast while the wind blew into our mouths and whistled through our hair. We would spread our foie gras on ordinary slices of bread, drink our champagne out of the same beer glass, smoke a Camel, and watch the youthful quivering of the sprouting wheat or the quivering old age of the thatch on the roofs. The wind, the sparrow hawks' round-about, used to circle overhead, over our love and over our little feast. I clothed Isabelle's name in velvet before pronouncing it, I listened in my mind to the intonation of what I was about to say to her. 'Wouldn't you like to turn over and face me?' I said. She turned over. I hurled myself into the Vale of Roses. The tiny lights in my skin were greedy for the tiny lights in Isabelle's skin, and the air became rarefied around us. We could do nothing without the meteors that would drag us after them into their orbits, that would hurl us one into the other. We were dependent on irresistible forces. We sank into unconsciousness, but we remained a single bloc opposed to the darkness around us in the dormitory. Death brought us back to life: we sailed into several ports. I was not seeing, not hearing, and yet I still experienced the world with a visionary's senses. We were intertwined: a miracle was flickering out instead of flaming. 'Together, together...' She stroked her breast with my hand. 'Lean over. Together, together... No, no... Not right away?' She fell back. 'Your hand, your hand,' Isabelle moaned. We did it from memory, as though we had caressed one another before we were born, as though we were replacing a link. Isabelle's hand, sending tremors down my thigh, was my hand; my hand as it rested on Isabelle's flank was hers. She was reflecting me, I was reflecting her: two mirrors making love. Our exploration in unison was not affected when she pushed back her hair, or when I pushed down the sheet. I listened with her fingers to the song my fingers were singing to her. We learned, we were remembering that the skin of thighs is as sensitive as mimosa. Our hands were so light that I could follow the curve of Isabelle's down along my arm, the curve of mine down along her arm. We trailed the backs of our fingernails down the furrow between one another's closed thighs, then trailed them up again, stimu-lating, then suppressing little quivers. Our skin was exercising our hands and their doubles. We led velvet rains and floods of frothing muslin down from our groins to our ankles, then made our way back, prolonging an underground rumbling of sweetness from shoulder down to heel. We stopped. 'I'm waiting for you,' Isabelle said. Her flesh seemed to be made entirely of pearls to me. 'I shall never find it,' I said. Her arm lying beneath mine lifted mine as it lifted itself. Isabelle was examining herself. She replaced my hand, began the movement with her hand over mine, then left me to my own rhythm. 'Concentrate on it,' Isabelle said. The air was heavy, the air was barbaric. I rocked her, I sharpened her, I drew her out from among the folds of her collapse, I restored her confidence. I wouldn't remember her as I do if I hadn't given her my life and my soul. The pearl refined the finger and the finger became flesh of our flesh: the rhythm of my movements was in our heads as well. The fiesh was polishing my finger and my finger was polishing Isabelle's flesh. The movement continued without us: our fingers were lost in a dream. I rubbed the dying fingers to soften them, I anointed myself as deep as my bones with pagan oils. Isabelle raised herself a little and nibbled at a lock of my hair. 'Together,' she said. Seeping streams of languor, cracks of sweating sweetness, marshes of secret delight... Lilac leaves were unfolding their sweetness, spring was putting me to the torture, the dust of the dead was dancing in my beams. At last I was myself in ceasing to be myself - at last. The visit to my paradise was not far off. 'Tell me when.' 'Yes, I'll tell you.' I detached myself from my skeleton and floated away on my dust. The pleasure was rigid at first and difficult to sustain. The visit began in one foot, pursuing its course through flesh now candid once again. We had forgotten our fingers back in the old world, we were gaping with light, invaded by a rending bliss. Our legs were mangled with delight, our entrails flooded with illumination. 'It's coming, it's coming...' 'Keep on, keep on.' The vell brushed at the sole of my foot, the finger turned in thick white sun, a velvet flame writhed in my legs. Having come from so far, the veil receded even farther than it had come. Walking on the water... I knew what that meant as my thighs flowed in that great river. I had been brushed by the scarf of madness that has no end, I had been caressed, yet also milled to dust, by a cramp of pleasure. 'Together.' 'It was together...' Rest, a divine curfew. The same death in body and soul. Yes, but death with a zither in one's head. Our silence: the periwinkle blue of celestial charts. Our stars beneath our eyelids: tiny crosses. 'Do you have to be so quiet?' Isabelle said. 'I'm not being quiet. I'm carrying you.' I was carrying the child most like herself that she was able to give me: I was carrying the child of her presence. She stroked my neck with her hair, with her little cold nose. 'One word...' 'I can't. I have you here inside.' I guided her hand. 'I have you there, and there...' I led her hand across my belly. 'Bend your arm,' she said. 'Bend your arm as though we were out walking together.' She gave me her arm and we went out walking together between the Great Bear and the Pleiades. My blood ran towards her in jubilation. I switched on the flashlight. Her fleece was no longer shining: it had faded into a pensive mood. I embalmed Isabelle with my lips, with my hands. The wan sleepers in their cubicles were breathing all around her, the shadows hungry for pallor were circling above her. I opened her lips and plunged to my death before looking. My face brushed against her sex, my face was wetting it. I began to make love to it with simple friendship. 'More than that.' I hadn't the strength to do anything more. Isabelle pushed my face against her. 'Talk,' she said. 'Tell me about it.' There were clouds buffeting one another inside. me. My brain was crazed with the greed of desire. 'You're beautiful...' I was imagining her. I wasn't lying. Two petals were trying to engulf me. The eye could see better because it was seeing me first. 'Talk,' Isabelle begged. 'I'm all alone.' 'You're beautiful... It's so strange... I don't dare look any more.' That language all made up of yawns, the monster making its demands, then the replies, all were terrifying to me. 'Make me warm,' I said. I felt chilled by the shadows rustling around us at three in the morning. 'Sleep for a while,' she said. 'I'll keep watch.' 'Have I disappointed you?' 'That can be looked at too, just like the rest,' Isabelle said. The night would go away, the night would soon be leaving us with nothing but our tears. I switched on the flashlight and refused to be afraid of my open eyes. 'I can see the world. It is coming out of you.' 'Be quiet.' Dawn with its shrouds. Isabelle was combing her hair in a country of her own, a country where her hair was always un-done. 'I don't want day to come,' Isabelle said. It was coming. It would come. Day was preparing to shatter the darkness along an aqueduct. 'I'm afraid of being parted from you,' Isabelle said. A tear fell into my garden at half past three in the morning. I refused to let myself think even the tiniest thought, so that she too could fall asleep inside my empty head. The day was taking the night, the day was erasing our couplings with its own, and Isabelle was falling asleep. 'Sleep,' I said, near to the glimmering hawthorns that had waited for this dawn all night. I slipped from the bed like a betrayer and went over to the window. High in the sky there had been a battle that was now losing its heat. The mists were flying in defeat, though a greyish darkness was still holding out here and there. The universal dawn was out there alone, with no one to usher her 'Were you leaving?' Isabelle said. 'Sleep.' 'Come back. My arm's cold.' 'Listen... One of the girls is working.' 'That's what I used to do before I knew you,' Isabelle said. Already there were birds clustering in a tree and pecking at the first glimmers of day 'I'll do whatever you want,' I said. I licked. Isabelle, kneeling on the pillow, quivered as I was quivering. How far away my burning face, how far away my mouth was from her face, from her mouth! My sweat, my saliva, the lack of space, my galley-slave existence, condemned to ceaseless pleasure since I had come to love her, all these held me in a magic spell. I quenched my thirst with her brine, I sated my hunger with her hair. I saw the half morning of the dawning day, I saw the tatters of the night, and smiled at them. I smiled at Isabelle, and then, forehead against forehead like fighting rams, we joined in a playful contest to help us forget what was dying. The lyric strains of a songbird forcing the beauty of the morning into bloom drained us of life: perfection is not of this world, even when we meet it here. 'The assistant is up!' Isabelle said. The sound of the water running into her basin aged us suddenly. 'You must go,' Isabelle said. Leaving her like a pariah, leaving her furtively like that added to my sadness. There were balls and chains around my feet. I sat down on her bed. Isabelle offered me her desolate face. I made love to Isabelle without gestures, without violence: I offered her my life without a sign. Isabelle sat up and took me in her arms. 'Will you come every evening?' 'Every evening.' 'We won't leave one another?' 'We won't leave one another.' My mother took me out of the school a month later. I never saw Isabelle again.</p>
            </div>
        </div>
    </body>
</text>
</TEI>