<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">The Childlike Life of the Black Tarantula</title>
            <title type="subtitle">i move to san francisco. i begin to copy my favorite pornography books and become the main person in each of them.</title>
            <author>
                <persName>
                    <forename>Kathy</forename>
                    <surname>Acker</surname>
                </persName>
                <persName type="pseudo">The Black Tarantula</persName>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
                <resp>Encoded in TEI All by</resp>
                <name xml:id="MD">Miki Derdun</name>
            </respStmt>
        </titleStmt>
        <editionStmt>
            <edition n="0.5">Non-public release for research purposes. Basic annotation with minimal enrichment.</edition>
        </editionStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
            <p />
        </publicationStmt>
        <seriesStmt>
            <title>The Childlike Life of the Black Tarantula</title>
            <biblScope unit="issue">#3</biblScope>
        </seriesStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
                <titleStmt>
                    <title>Portrait of an Eye</title>
                    <author>Kathy Acker</author>
                    <respStmt>
                        <resp>Edited for XML and encoded by</resp>
                        <name>Miki Derdun</name>
                    </respStmt>
                </titleStmt>
                <editionStmt>
                    <edition n="0.5">An early release. Some encoding choices remain to be refined or
                        extended.</edition>
                </editionStmt>
                <publicationStmt>
                    <publisher>Grove Press</publisher>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>841 Broadway</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>New York, NY 10003</addrLine>
                    </address>
                    <date>1998</date>
                </publicationStmt>
            </biblFull>
        </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
    <projectDesc>
        <p>This version of The Childlike Life of the Black Tarantula uses TEI All to encode Acker's texts and sources. The primary research aim at this stage is to understand Acker's textual reuse habits and interrogate their uses in the formation of narrative identities on the level of varying personas.</p>
    </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="text">
                <p>I'm two people and the two people are making love to each other. </p>
                <p>In my girls' school, I watch the green metal door rise up and down; I can't decide whether I'm a woman giving birth to a brat or a five-year-old girl. I have to piss so I won't piss in my pants. Older girls are talking to each other. It's so hard to shit I think I'll dig it out with my fingers. Do you want to help me? I'll cut off your cunt hair. Uh ugh ugh. O.K. I'm coming in to help you. I flush the toilet. I'm madly in love with the older girls and scared of them.</p>
                <p>As Jean opens the heavy brown door to the bathroom, she sees one of the stall doors open; a small white face appears long brown ponytail which is always falling apart white middy blouse and navy wool jumper like hers. She looks into her lover's face and smiles.</p>
                <p>"Jean, quick, come in here." I grab her thin long arm, drag her back into the metal stall. She slyly lets her hand brush against my hand I move slower toward her; she shows her teeth puts both her hands on my shoulders yanks my body toward her tall thin body. We look up at each other and our lips begin to touch. Thin layers of skin against thin layers of skin, fluids swirling through, until we don't know whose skin's whose. Tiny fingers curl around the sides of my body. I don't understand what I'm doing. I hold on to Jean harder and harder. I want to enter into her body rise up through the metal ceiling blow the select girls' school into tiny bits. Are they going to catch us?</p>
                <p>(I begin to copy Therese and Isabelle):</p>
                <p>I push Jean's body against the metal door, I surround her with my hands my legs, my teeth bore into her neck. "That's not enough." I throw the weight of my body against hers, my heavy ulcer stomach; I whisper something to her. Her body wrenches away from me she wants to get away. Her thin white hands lie in my hands, her tall body droops over me so that her lips rest above mine.</p>
                <p>(Start again: I'm a lesbian):</p>
                <p>"Hug me harder." I tighten my hands around her chest, my knees imprison her knees. "We have to scram." "I hate you. I want to punch you out first for going with Linda yesterday. You have no right to be in that gang."" A small girl walks into the bathroom just to annoy us. "Get out of here crud. Who do you think you are?" " I'm going to stick a knife in you."</p>
                <p>"Jean, when can we meet again secretly? I have to be with you." "Tonight, when it's dark." I place three kisses on her right shoulder. "That will be the bond between us until then." "Jean, I'm scared: I'm not going to see you again." My stronger self laughs at me, turns away, content to move down the long hall, alone, a gallant knight lost in this stupid school I have to attend.</p>
                <p>I hate this school. I hate to wear a white blouse, navy blue jumper, navy blue knee socks, curtsy, no underwear, I'm a freak, no makeup; no men are allowed inside the school buildings except on Parents' Day and a few repairmen. I keep a bottle of Scotch in my locker so I don't get too bored and think only about Jean. I decide I'm never again going to take a job "job" means my dealing with straights and pretend freaks I'll prostitute if I have to hopefully I can get away with modeling. There's the world of jobs and the world of freaks. The school, the headmistress wants to expel me because I wear black nail polish on my fingers and I'm a Jew. I take another drink of whiskey. I want Jean. I want Jean.</p>
                <p>At night I read the Marquis de Sade, Artaud's poems, and my algebra book. I'm dead unless I'm in love, most of the times I've been in love nothing's happened no I dream I'm never going to see Jean again: I follow Jean everywhere, I lay in my white cubicle, Jeans walks off with another teacher ignores me, I hide in a black corner, I'm invisible; I see Jean put her arms around another person and kiss him. She lays her head on his shoulder. I'm not sure whether I'm a male or a female. I withdraw into a tiny ball, black. My mother pretends she's my sister: we throw snowballs at each other how old's your younger sister? She promises me presents and forgets to give me anything, she remembers to forget she plans to forget; she gives birth to me because she can't get an abortion. This is what she tells me: she gets appendicitis her mother tells me she loves me madly I can't climb into her bed because my sister climbs into her bed every night, she puts her arms around me tells me she loves me, she takes away my home. Mother I'm dying there are free clinics in the city will you help me you better find someone to pay for your grave you're giving your father a heart attack. I think of Jean. Piss on the teachers if they find us; they don't even fuck.</p>
                <p>I hate men because I've had to be a semi-prostitute; an ocean rolls over me I don't want men touching me if I have to semi-prostitute again for money I will because getting a straight job would lobotomize me a wall breaks down I'm a single animal fending for myself I'm clever and relentless.</p>
                <p>I hear from X gallery D wants to give a show with me does D know who I really am? I write back immediately after I send the letter the phone rings. D. Do you know who I am? Yes. I'm not sure what that means (my unconscious fantasy).</p>
                <p>How heavy can I get. Pornography's more fun and interesting. I have a child I hate children I don't have a child Jean says she'll scream. I'm scared we'll be expelled. Jean and I lie in Jean's cubicle, midnight, Jean tells me that she's going to make me a house, set me in the house among thick velvets silks yellow brocades and yellow suns, she's going to leave me: I'll be out on the streets alone where men go looking for starving young girls they can make into prostitutes I grab on to Jean my hands circle around her arm "I'll scream" "I don't care if you scream, I can take anything" she placing my hand on the hair between her legs. I'm scared, I don't move so that I won't increase my fear, I gradually fall asleep I'm scared no one will respect me. Everyone will know about me.</p>
                <p>"Move your hand lower. Press down. Do you feel my lips. Insert your finger slightly between my lips below my clit toward the top, lightly run your finger over the inside in lighter circles." I feels Jean's hand on my cunt. "Slowly increase the speed. Touch the skin more firmly as it becomes wetter dart press your finger down on my clit faster put your fingers together, thrust them into me two fingers right above the edge of the opening; I feel your fingers move into my belly, press against the muscle walls touch my clit again." In every other bed a girl has her lover. One girl lies still; only her hand exists. The other girl is coming, you're coming. "You'll have to do it right, faster..." I'm coming; I feel Jean coming I'm able to make Jean come. "Rest." She draws my head against her chest; I let my lips fall against her flat nipple. I'm always thinking about the tasks I have yet to do.</p>
                <p>"I think Miss St. Pierre's a lesbian" Jean whispers. I can't tell Jean about everything, who I like and hate, she'd reach too far inside me rub against the open veins. I hate the Mueller twins because they're the only people who are as intelligent and beautiful as I am; the head of the school encourages the Mueller twins and I to fight so we can raise the intellectual standards of the school. We use each other's last names; we have no sex. "Do you like being in school?" I ask Jean. "No, I want to do whatever I want to do fuck everyone I don't want to listen to anyone. I want to blow my identity outward, away, until I'm always running in a black ocean under a black sky and I can control my emotions." I don't see Jean in classes: I'm in section A and she's in section B. They stick the rich kids in section A and the poor ones in B, they want us to learn that poor means stupid. We hate them but what the hell. I'm like Nixon: when I lived in New York I was so paranoid I couldn't see that I was acting totally from an unnecessary paranoia. Blow up the school.</p>
                <p>This is a list of what's necessary: I'm scared Jean's falling asleep, I'm scared I'll have to leave Jean, I'm scared someone's coming; I listen carefully "No one's coming stupid; you're stupid." Jean carefully licks my ear, blows into my ear; I trust her she'll never leave me, her hand lies on my belly; I love her because she's beautiful, I love her because she's tall and skinny has short black curly hair, she's more historical than I am; her hand enters me her three magic fingers, I love her, we pretend we're communists we announce the meeting of the next communist club in our ritzy girls' school, are you a virgin, no what does it feel like at first it hurts then some feeling I can't describe; it grows I claw at his back I usually rip open his skin, it's terrific. I tell Jean this, she puts her hand over my mouth; we look into each other's eyes
                <lb />(more programmatic):</p>
                <p>The big toe of my left foot is making love to the toe of my right foot. The toes become two people. In my head I'm telling someone about me the two voices become voices outside my head I almost hear, not quite, I feel I'm closest to people in loony bins I see myself acting superior I'm going to get a job emptying toilets in a loony bin because I subconsciously know that I'm crazy. This is how I'm sneakily helping myself: I ask L about B's work say I think B's work is important because I'm still secretly and madly in love with B; secret sexual intentions determine my actions. The black water and black sky become menacing, I see them as menacing because I'm becoming used enough to them; I'm projecting. A semicircle of people stand around Jean's cubicle, stare at our forms through the thin white curtains. Everyone knows about me. I love you.</p>
                <lb />
                <p>The fuck with this shit I'm going to be as direct with you as possible. The first time I fuck a chick, sorry, a woman, I'm scared as hell I mean I'm really scared, I'm not sure my dong belongs on me but I have to do it anyway I want to. A few inches from my body I create a wall of bricks white concrete that exactly mimics the contours of my body I'm as tough as possible, and I've got a dong! I wongle it a few times I figure I'm pretty big, not all that big, but when we, the guys, measured at camp I came in second. I've got a good body good strong muscles. I can feel myself bulging, right there. A cock feels like, it feels like me, I can sense it hang outward from my body sort of down, I don't really feel anything though I know it's there, I feel proud: a piece of flesh. When I have to piss or when I get hot, I can feel it more, I can feel the skin or the muscle gather, begin to tense, create a different world. Especially the tip of my prick, the blood flows to and from it, faster I want to touch its tip lightly, constantly; I can feel the spot burn; the burning causes the muscles next to the spot then the next set of muscles onward large vibrations. The first time the woman runs her hand down the hair on my stomach up my prick I can't feel her touch, she puts her hands on my waist motions for me to roll over on top of her, I'm scared out of my mind I have to appear sure of myself controlling the events; I control the events, I put my hand on my prick touch the tip to her lips I feel something wet suddenly I feel wet walls close around my prick I feel wonderful I can feel my balls swell I still don't feel any strong sensations. When I come the burning at the tip of my prick increases with the swirling flow of the blood increases the tension, about to break open, I'm a volcano. When I wear tight pants, I watch my cock rise and fall it looks like a small animal only I know it's me; I stand straight over the toilet, now my back's extremely straight, I look at the wall and hold my cock in my right hand, I feel faint vibrations in the upper half of my cock as the liquid shoots through it. I rub my cock up and down especially at the rim of the head and underside of the head where there's a slight white streak between the pink skin, my piss-hole's about as large as three needle points, when I rub my cock quickly in these areas with my right hand some cream the burning extends from the tip to the bottom of the head, and then outward; I bring the tension to a pitch, back down, to a pitch back down, etc. until I feel like the sperm's boiling and rising no matter what I do, until the slightest touch of my finger on my cock is enough to make me come. I usually jerk off into the toilet bowl or in my bed alone late at night.</p>
                <p>A woman with blonde almost orange hair and large light brown eyes, cross between Spitz and the dog Cluckle Clark, looks up at me, her face is diagonal to mine, I see her large eyes and I see her smile; she takes my hand in her left hand brings my hand between her legs so that I feel her cunt hair and the wet lips of her cunt. I press my hand against her cunt I try to bring the palm of my hand up above her bone so that I can excite her, I feel her excitement she begins to whisper to me. "I want you to do what you're doing; I want you to tease me ha ha." She sticks her tongue out of her mouth. I stick the third finger of my right hand forward, gently draw my finger inside against her outer lips, barely touching her inner red lips. She lays down on me her buttocks over my crossed legs so that I can touch her as freely as possible. Her right hand presses against my cock I want her to love it. (me.)</p>
                <lb />
                <p>The Black Tarantula moves to San Francisco. The windows are two huge eyes staring at me, any person can become part of these composite insect eyes, I sit against the white walls of the enclosed room and gibber. The walls are all white. The walls of an asylum. The walls of a hospital. The walls are going to close around me, are closing around me: crush me. I start to scream. The walls are the legs of a huge spider. I walk into the room, a woman flips up to me, do I want to be in her poetry class I'm new here she'll help me. I tell her to go to hell. P runs up to me, hugs me, loves me, arranges everything. I'm famous (I see A who's with a blonde small girl friend, he looks exactly like me and has the opposite name so we have to become good friends I don't care who he fucks I don't care about sex and heterosexual sex always fucks up friendships, I'm scared it will fuck up this one; T platonically falls in love with me, I see D and sleep with him everything happens perfectly. Someone even offers me a job.</p>
                <p>(I'm scared to go outside alone, I'm scared everyone will hate me, everyone's watching me everyone doesn't know me.)</p>
                <p>I tell Jean I want my belongings back. "I want my belongings back." "I agree with you completely." I have to ignore everyone, I turn my face to the side, I can't look at her. "I'm placing them on your body, each piece of clothing, each feather, each scarf." Jean's not me, I can tell now she's not me I want to touch her. No. "Place that feather in my hair." "Is it too tight?" Softly people are watching us, the people outside the window.</p>
                <p>"How do you know?" "I have to do everything for you, you're stupid." "I'm too scared to write, I'm too scared to walk on the street, I don't know anyone in this town, I'm too scared to call anyone I know." "I've moved too frequently from city to city in the past year, I can't deal with anyone any more, I lie I don't care, they can believe what they want to believe, but when I find out their fantasies about me I have to work make them like me." "If I call up P he'll be cold, I'm obviously bothering him O we'll have to have dinner together uh sometime. I'm paranoid and don't know the truth. If I call up P he might be happy to see me again. I'll have to pretend I admire him be bored shitless." "If I call up anyone either I'll be bored shitless or they won't like me. " "You're losing your mind. " "What'd you say Jean?" "I don't have any mind." One of the people comes by. "You're making too much noise. Stupid." "I have to piss." Jean and I giggle, I press my head into her belly. "You're not allowed to do that." "I can do what I want." "You're a creep you're stupid you're making too much noise. They'll come in here, kick us out of the world." "I hate their guts." Jean opens the cubicle window. "Have you thrown your nail file out?" I'm thinking about Latin. I'm going to become a Latin scholar because I love my teacher my parents tormented me when I was a child tried to make me kill myself because I hated myself so much. Hate them. I show Jean the razor marks on my wrist. Am I offending you? Jean and I standing in a sunblazed square low white walls around us; a camel lowers its head, we laugh, start racing down a slope to the next place. We laugh and laugh, "Jean, did anyone see you come to me?" I touch my cunt with my hand. "Who knows you're with me?" Jean brushes my shoulders with my thick brown hair, she covers her eyes with my hair, "they're coming," she enters into me, she disappears in me, "no one's here," I hear steps, I'm scared. Jean leaves me.</p>
                <p>A teacher pokes her ugly nose in my cubicle. "Who was with you? Are you a lesbian?" "Go to hell creep." "Jean was here, she was helping me because I'm crazy the other teachers know that: what's the matter with you? I hate you." A and T both come over, fuck with me, we enjoy ourselves, discuss sexism and get rid of that problem. I talk to P on the phone: he doesn't get upset. "You're astonishing me. Hurry up and get to class. You don't want to get more demerits." I'm alone again. (p. 32)</p>
                <lb />
                <p>I don't have an image of myself I'm moving too quickly to a strange city. I'm a young lesbian in a French boarding school who's growing up too quickly to have a childhood. I read Sartre De Sade Laing Esterson and Leduc. I'm scared I don't have my own space. I have a slight urine infection so I piss too much. You don't want to get more demerits. I'm alone again.</p>
                <lb />
                <p>I decide I have to hide from my public, rest; for two weeks I think I'll blank out, black. The bottom half of my leg is slim, pink, sticks pointed upward in the air. I'll live alone, quietly, Peter will tell my friends I've disappeared: wait for further communications. I wrap my silver gold lame dress and cape closer and closer around my huddling body. I'm Silver Gold Lame.</p>
                <lb />
                <p>Linda arrives with lice in her hair. She lives in the snow in the winter. The teacher tells her to get the lice out. I imprison her hand, imprison her so I can become her.</p>
                <p>"Is it cold outside? In the country" I explain. "I froze my toes off."</p>
                <p>"Is your father preparing for spring?" We don't believe any of this nonsense. We spend all our time gossiping about our friends, our fellow students, and our teachers: who's going with whom, who's outcast whom, who's most popular, who's tough, who's smart. I secretly know that the richer parents force their kids to be best friends with the girls of the richest parents. I want to puke. I sense I'm an outcast, so's Linda; we make friends with the children of the poorer parents. "Did you hear they've got a male in the school?" "What for?" "He's a religion teacher, everyone's falling in love with him." We part.</p>
                <p>In the distance I see Jean looking at a younger girl's photographs. "Renee's been showing me some photographs. What do you think of this one?" Jean says to me in the assembly hall as we wait to go into breakfast.</p>
                <p>"It's a landscape. It's good."</p>
                <p>I faint. I pretend to faint. I pretend I'm dead, I'm most scared of being dead after starving, being alone on the streets, I think I'm going to die my consciousness will go; I won't be anything any more (conscious) I fight, all the time I fight. I see myself: I'm a leopard. I get up. A teacher tells me to go to my bed. Jean says she'll accompany me. (p. 36)</p>
                <p>As I return to study hall, I find an envelope in my locker, I think of Isabelle, no Jean, I shouldn't think of Jean, I give way to Isabelle. There it is.</p>
                <p>"It's true," says Isabelle, "I'm upsetting you." She opens her eyes, I watch her opening her eyes, we both begin to moan.</p>
                <p>"Someone's coming. Wipe away the saliva."</p>
                <p>I don't want to hide. I want to hide.</p>
                <lb />
                <p>I come square against the fear. My fear. Until here I avoid, here I begin to merge, I hit the old fear. I'm Jean. I'm trying to make someone else's fantasy, fantasy caused by fears, my reality so I can deal with my fear. I can do it but I don't want to. Can I do it?</p>
                <lb />
                <p>"The teacher's here, you have to get away." Jean looks at me.</p>
                <p>The sound of running water frightens us.</p>
                <p>Leaving Jean like a criminal, leaving her like a thief, adds to my fear. The bars close around me.</p>
                <p>I sit down on Jean's bed, look at her horse's face.</p>
                <p>"I don't want you to go. Go. It's dangerous." This is how I am. This is how I will be. I begin to make love with Jean.</p>
                <p>In San Francisco Jean and I pretend we're in disguise; I wear red lipstick, my violet diamond butterfly coat, huge shoes, mirrors all over me; she wears all black because she's a cat burglar, she's he, we walk into this room with T.V. mirrors, I hide behind Jean I say hello to someone I want to avoid, then turn away he doesn't recognize me other people recognize me. I have to say hello to the guy I want to avoid, we begin kissing.</p>
                <p>I love lonely criminals and thieves.</p>
            </div>
            <postscript>
                <p>All events are taken from Therese and Isabelle by V. Leduc, my past, and my fantasies.</p>
            </postscript>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>