<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
    <fileDesc>
        <titleStmt>
            <title type="main">The Childlike Life of the Black Tarantula</title>
            <title type="subtitle">i become helen seferis, and then, alexander trocchi</title>
            <author>
                <persName>
                    <forename>Kathy</forename>
                    <surname>Acker</surname>
                </persName>
                <persName type="pseudo">The Black Tarantula</persName>
            </author>
            <respStmt>
                <resp>Encoded in TEI All by</resp>
                <name xml:id="MD">Miki Derdun</name>
            </respStmt>
        </titleStmt>
        <editionStmt>
            <edition n="0.5">Non-public release for research purposes. Basic annotation with minimal enrichment.</edition>
        </editionStmt>
        <publicationStmt>
            <p />
        </publicationStmt>
        <seriesStmt>
            <title>The Childlike Life of the Black Tarantula</title>
            <biblScope unit="issue" n="4">#4</biblScope>
        </seriesStmt>
        <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
                <titleStmt>
                    <title>Portrait of an Eye</title>
                    <author>Kathy Acker</author>
                    <respStmt>
                        <resp>Edited for XML and encoded by</resp>
                        <name>Miki Derdun</name>
                    </respStmt>
                </titleStmt>
                <editionStmt>
                    <edition n="0.5">An early release. Some encoding choices remain to be refined or
                        extended.</edition>
                </editionStmt>
                <publicationStmt>
                    <publisher>Grove Press</publisher>
                    <address>
                        <addrLine>841 Broadway</addrLine>
                        <addrLine>New York, NY 10003</addrLine>
                    </address>
                    <date>1998</date>
                </publicationStmt>
            </biblFull>
        </sourceDesc>
    </fileDesc>
    <encodingDesc>
    <projectDesc>
        <p>This version of The Childlike Life of the Black Tarantula uses TEI All to encode Acker's texts and sources. The primary research aim at this stage is to understand Acker's textual reuse habits and interrogate their uses in the formation of narrative identities on the level of varying personas.</p>
    </projectDesc>
    </encodingDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div type="text">
                <p>I'm lying in the dark, in a tent, my thighs wrapped in the thick skins of sheep. The dark lies around me, murderers thieves who have taken me stand around, I can smell them I hate their guts; they'll need food when we get to the city, I'll take my revenge. Right now I'm impotent.</p>
                <p>My lover Y sold me to them the man I had allowed to touch me: I'll kill him. Why do I still fuck?</p>
                <p>All I have left is my writing. That's the only stability I know have ever known. Y wanted to kill me because he was scared I might kill him. Now I want to kill him. He's not so fucking powerful, he can sell me, I'll get my revenge. Part of me, a box, hates men, despises them, I can usually see that box and forget it; now it's exploded. I like to fuck.</p>
                <p>I don't understand why I think so much about sex. I'm scared to death to call up someone, ask him/her to fuck me, go out on the street, let a stranger touch me (fantasy): my desire usuall overcomes my fears. I do what I fantasize doing. Right now, I'm nowhere. I'm touching my thigh my hand is someone else's hand, an inch toward the inner thigh the low wind of the skin curving toward my cunt hair; I touch myself again alone I know who I am; I experience strength pulse the muscles between the arms of my back a young virulent athlete. I feel alone and strong.</p>
                <p>The beginning:</p>
                <p>I climb alone down the rocks of the cove. The coral reefs stretching into the sea look like mirrors of my cunt, my inner womb; then look utterly strange: black sea monsters skimming the surfaces of each other's bodies for their communication. I imagine I'm a mermaid. At night I see the sea, the ocean black against black against black, long thick lines of white appearing moving inward at my image. Because my father's chief I'm always alone and can do whatever I want. At night I run into the black ocean: a wave which I can't see lifts me up in the blackness larger unseen waves lift me breaks over my head, white, the ocean lights up! The waves grow larger I always swim alone.</p>
                <p>I'm fifteen years old; I hate everyone. I don't hate everyone (that's stupid).</p>
                <p>All I do is fantasize about sex. Someone being nice to me. I close my eyes, begin to space out: feel I'm rolling down then out my legs straight out on a pillow, my head falls backwards I begin to fantasize: I move like a sleepwalker among deeper sleepwalkers in this beach I remember. (Memory makes everything romantic.) I open my legs, the water feels coldest around my ankles as it rises around my legs the shock disappears the foam springs around me wets my cunt, I begin to swim naked the long muscles runn ing around my ass down the backs of my long legs relax, my body opens at my cunt, I'm alone I laugh talk to the ocean my pickle paul lizzy dizzy fizzy cluckle clark, I float in it and leap over it, when I leave it I'm gleaming I see blood blood floating around me everywhere. I want to fuck impersonally passionately so that I feel completely free, two twin streams of blood run down the inside of my legs, I draw my knees apart, gently, and let the blood dry.</p>
                <p>My father wants to fuck me, fears his desire which is the only honest part of him, and fears me. I scare everyone away. I look like a rat. My father's partly conditioned me: made me scared of everyone in the village, especially men. I hide from people; I despise people because they accept the shit they live in and get, limits limits no complete absorption into anyone/anything I can feel my fear. My father tried to fuck me and doesn't succeed. I vow to sleep alone. I wait for the day my father'll die: I can do whatever I want.</p>
                <p>Tomorrow I'll get mail. I look at the ocean, I slowly take my clothes off feel the material leaving each inch of the body, I look at the dark ocean I run into the ocean expect the physical shock to break apart the wall of my fantasies relieve me, nothing happens, I'm constantly horny untouched, I throw myself on the sand, the pointed shells. I see a half-rotten log, fat, in the sand as I know what I'm about to do my legs feel like they' re opening without opening the muscles in the center of my belly extend like fingers toward my throbbing clit I watch my cunt approach the log I'm on the log I'm a man my hands shake then my whole body, as I collapse on the log my whole weight thrown on my clit against the wood as I sink the log falls on top of me scrapes the delicate skins of my breasts, the thick layer of fat soft skin across my navel. The shells beneath my buttocks cut into my buttocks, sharp points drive into the lips of my ass so that nerves spasm sharply in arrows from my ass upward, down to my cunt. I press the log more tightly with my legs. I</p>
                <p>I press the rough sharp wood against my clit an inch below my clit then rhythmically increasing speed touching my clit.</p>
                <p>I look up at the black air behind the black air I fantasize. If I could see people I like I could get out of the fantasy, there would just be fewer fantasies. I'm covered with blood I'm hurt which makes me scared a few green streaks cover my body.</p>
                <p>(For the last time I walk into the ocean. Now I'm stuck in San Francisco. I moved here for good reasons: I leave all my friends. I go to a party, I know everyone, everyone loves me. Do you want to go? Anywhere. On Mission and 18th Street three guys rape me. I hear laughter. Once I open up to the possibility of sex, I can fuck anyone I want to feel my strength there. My sex is myself my strength. Was someone watching me? Is a man going to rape me? Elemental signs of conditioning.)</p>
                <p>"Let me go... no... no... I'll kill you."</p>
                <p>Her fear rouses my fear and the excitement that I feel with fear. I scale the rocks, immediately see one of the village girls I know, she was in my school class I thought her stupid, a man on top of her, his hands clenched around her arms. The girl throws him off, runs away. For the first time I'm no longer scared because I have a cunt. "Do you have a cunt?" I walk across the sand to the man whom I recognize. We're both dressed.</p>
                <p>I can see his dark body clearly beneath his clothes. "I'd leave this village again," he tells me, "if I could get the money."</p>
                <p>I watch his eyes fall against the cloth of my skirt which is pressing against my mound. "If you like, I could get the money."</p>
                <p>"You mean together?"</p>
                <p>"I was watching you make love to P." He lays one of his hands on the thick skin of my thigh, I lean back into space; I open my eyes.</p>
                <p>(Pure pornography.) I scarcely feel his fingers edging through the layers of my musk into the sex of the body, the twin mouth, strange sensations like waves rip through my body, I only feel relief as his fingers penetrate, move freely inside me, the outside becomes my inside, then I feel nothing. He slowly removes his fingers, licks them, as I feel his lips rub against my wet lips, his double cock quickly tears through my knotted hairs into the long spiraling muscles of my cunt a knife toward my womb I feel nothing I arch my back so that the top of his cock presses against the upper part of my cunt, the delicate opening of the skin below the cunt hairs, I'm scared I move back and forth quickly abandon myself to his rhythm as his legs tense, my tensed muscles the muscles around my clit shooting outward disintegrate I lose my sex by coming.</p>
                <p>He opens my blouse his head mouth falls on my left nipple. Hard. A thin line of desire, electric nerves, moves from my nipple straight down over to my sensitive clit my right hand presses his head against my breast the muscles around my clit begin to quiver I run my hand down in the sweat down to caress his thick hairs, he simultaneously slides his hand under my buttocks his middle fingers into the more delicate opening between my buttocks. I'm doing what I've dreamed of doing wanted to do for years. Never again. I sit alone in the house I don't talk to anyone. I masturbate. I dream of ass. Cunt against the plate behind the cock, rapidly, our juices mingle, the juices of my 18-years-starved body. Cats howl at each other and screech. I contain the strange liquid in me. I have no definite feelings.</p>
                <p>We make our plans: "We'll go to Charleston first, then we'll go south from there."</p>
                <p>"How soon?"</p>
                <p>"I'll steal my father's money tonight." I remember I need someone to protect me. "We'll get married there."</p>
                <p>I have no intention of getting married: I'll stay with this guy as long as he can help me, then find another guy. All that matters is my own sexuality.</p>
                <lb />
                <p>[7/18]</p>
                <p>I persuade myself I can't call up A because I'll ruin any chance of a friendship between us for a quick fuck I call him up decadence wins ah I'll call back I persuade myself</p>
                <p>Now I touch my cunt I can work. I hide my writing my self fear someone will steal me a man enters a shadow. I lie in the tent of falling sheepskins. As I see his eyes fall down on me his finger point the muscles below and beneath my belly begin to quiver I watch my self falling into my cunt: I take off the rough robe they've put on me I dig my heels into the blankets my legs feel heavy thick I spread them outward first the muscles at from the center of my groin my knees flexed like a dancer's my ankles twisted I slowly raise the altar of my body the thick outer lips open my whole body opening up toward the black air heavy and dangerous then toward the man. He thrusts his bearded mouth against my cunt.</p>
                <p>Again I feel the complete joy of giving myself, myself fully since I don't know this man, to another person and having the person equally, for both our pleasure and pain, give himself to me. A person who I will never see again, not recognize, so no ties can interfere with our delight. As I come again and again, his lips working softly against my clit, I again rejoice that I have no personal friendships, I dream, fantasize, awake briefly to meet someone and come, to worship my own coming. I'm almost asleep. I want to make myself become/put down everything before they try to destroy an anomaly such as me. I hate the robot society I know.</p>
                <p>I arrived with A in Charleston early on the morning of my 19th birthday. I gave A a quarter of my money, pretended I didn't have any more. I don't want to depend on any man. A slowly touches my cunt under the table, moves his hand under my velvet dress lightly up the waving hairs of my leg until the tip of his fingers scrape the beginning of the opening of my sex. I want to come but am too anxious, too scared. "We have to get to Charleston." "I want to marry you," A says, "settle down take over your father's lucrative fishing business."</p>
                <p>A's a death person despite his body, his cock. I don't let my feelings show. Now that I've gotten away from my parents, I have to steer free of every one, those who want to entrap me; I have to get every thing where on my own. I see policemen in the streets waiting for us with guns.</p>
                <p>"A, I need some of my money. I have to buy clothes."</p>
                <p>I take my money, 40 pounds, split. Split. Into the toilet, out the side door, around the policemen. I'm very smart and clever.</p>
                <p>I look up at a man who, I realize, is attracted to me. I want to fuck him. I watch him watching me until I can't stand the agony the vibrations of the huge metal wheels under the slimy flesh around my clit, and fur, a yowling cat, I rise leave the train car, a few minutes later, I find the stranger standing behind me. I slide my hand below the low tight belt of my jeans lower along the skin made thick from milk, I can feel the lips of my cunt separate, the outer ones, the inner ones moving slightly against my clit, the muscles behind the mouth tense until my fingers ease over to them, to my clit. Tough wait touch lightly wait the third finger clit-centered wait "trains are always boring" at the rim of the walls I lose myself touch again "are you coming?" "am I coming?" the skins fold into around each other I feel them too close touch lighten then insistently the rhythm rub my clit slowly. The wave centers begin everywhere.</p>
                <p>I look up at him my desire obvious. His lips touch the lips of my cunt my erosion as my muscles tense. Upward begin to break my nipples open I feel his lips then tongue my seed flows and at the peak, like a male, I begin to moan, repeat my desire, I rise, and snap. I feel his lips inside me</p>
                <p>I slowly fall asleep. End of minimal pornography.</p>
                <lb />
                <p>I don't see anything any more. White beating down white glimpses of white the edge of my shoulder. Am I breaking out, or enclosing myself further? I'm no longer interested in my memories, only in my continuing escalating feelings.</p>
                <p>After we leave the porno shop walk A home I sit down onthe corner of Market and 9th fold my cape over my face. I don't want to see or hear anymore. Stasis before the danger occurs: my space disappears. I do this over I sit down on the corner of Market and 9th. Can I steal your money? Can I take your black leather jacket lined with black fur? If I hate you will you love me more? They put a black tent over me as I sit on one of the camels. No other men can see me because if they see me they'll fuck me. I can smell the sex everywhere: I reach down along my neck kiss the skin of my right breast. I smell at the brown pit of my arms. I have more power than most people which I don't use am scared of if I turn on the power I attract everyone. Men aren't attracted to me but I can charm them by being forceful if I want, otherwise I can vanish. I'm so horny I'll sleep with anyone. The dark men gather around me, stare at me, I can't recognize who I've slept with I'm unsure I say hello to the junky he doesn't say hello: goodlooking long black hair, sharp yellow features, brilliant B touches me because he wants to fuck me I can touch his extending cock. I see my cunt ahead of me the pear lips pulsing and the thin inner folds. But I can never be certain.</p>
                <p>I don't want to escape now. My revolt against the death society collides with my desire to be touched I have no identity I can feel the hand softly running up down my leg inside the leg against the sand softly spreading my legs my buttocks against the burning sand the sand rises into my ass tiny diamonds every touch causes all people think about when they meet me is sex ripples of flesh to collide against the returning ripples as they enlarge into waves I give myself entirely to each desire because there's nothing else to give myself to nothing else exists I have to hide my work am I scared? His hands grasp my thighs pulling him upward over me. My, Silver Gold Lame's, first vision of San Francisco: nothing, delight, hey stop yeah ah, what, you're under arrest, I see some black junky, I'm Vice Squad and I'm arresting you, I start to cross the street, you can't move I've got a gun, he reaches in a plastic portfolio he's carrying, I'm still alive, his hands fold around my cheeks he turns his head bend down on top of my mouth to kiss me saliva flows into me I'm burning saliva and mucus flesh until I can't tell object from object, my feeling rushes to my center I don't want to sleep with you my feeling rushes to my center I rise there against the new lover there is only this and my account of this I immediately begin to come, I see a frame around me: my space. The rest is blackness, money-deathnecessity coming to destroy my gropings toward, sex-money looming over me destroy my tentative beginning human sex, I rub my body against P. I become a parrot. O.K.</p>
                <p>I do only one thing. I touch my self or I feel a hand a leg touch me a mouth enters me I can feel its wet softness against my skin I expect nothing and quickly I begin to quiver my hands contact the strange flesh my delight begins I thrust my hands under the shoulders the body over me burning flesh sliding on my burning flesh the strange object slides into my body within the secret walls of my cunt wet hairs pierce my clit until I'm about to break my clit swollen with blood until I'm at the final edge</p>
                <p>for hours I come and come until there's no difference between coming and reality. I have to be careful for they may visit me at any moment, and take away my writing; I'm still me, I'm still scared by my passion and sex. Reporting involves memories involves identity: I have my identity and I have my sex: I'm not new yet. I have to be careful for I may be visited at any moment.</p>
                <lb />
                <p>[7/20/73]</p>
                <p>I became a man and a woman:</p>
                <p>The ground pulls out from under my body I feel the anxieties I felt as a kid because my parents hate me or the anxieties I feel on acid I stay with the anxiety to find out what's happening I forget who I am I don't know who I am I see a huge soft black widow no identity a large tarantula I have no feelings I begin to float. I'm Helen I know who I am, then my work means nothing to me my work means less to me than my sexuality. I'm a failure. This is a failure all I'm causing is my own disintegration. What'm I trying to do? My work and my sexuality combine: here the complete sexuality occurs within, is not expressed by, the writing. I feel anxious. Last night no one comes in. I hear footsteps muffled voices talking about me describing my real being, bricks being thrown on the ground, large black woman jiving, I hear two tough guys on telephone wires one tells the other I love you, cat begins to yowl. Nothing stops my writing finally I'm alone I use my writing to get rid of all feelings of identity that aren't my sexuality. I have to exist only when someone seeks to touch me or I touch myself. Fuck this. I feel hot and sweaty. It's hot and sweaty, early, the heat of the day focused in the grey-black evening air. The endless sand still burning. Men mutter and cry around me, stare at me uneasily, and talk. I eat a few dates, cheese, bread, and wine. No one touches me; I'm constantly horny; I think only about sex. I don't like sexual explosions getting mixed up with hampering my work. I'll do anything to fuck.</p>
                <p>Last night no one comes in. I tried to remember the last time a stranger more than one of them touched me I wet my finger slid it up the tight writhing hole between his buttocks the strangely smooth skin welcome me a thin cord of skin spiraling around my finger a vein throbbing and helping my finger climb upward tightened around me pulsating as my finger pressed inward toward his belly. My other hand slid between our wet flesh around the head of his cock pressing the white cord under his cock I remember the two men staring at me, huge rectangle eyes the eyes of spider, as I sit flat against the white walls the sand I have no protection the sand is a hospital and a loony bin I go off. Fuck people, by the time anyone's 26 years old he/she's crazy unable any longer to communicate with more than 1% efficiency genitals meet but no info gets across so I act romantic I'd rather make love with parrots and cats I like and bite them they lick and bite me. My dears, we're all very sophisticated, but it's a drag; I sleep with few people. As one man lays his cock in my mouth, the other spreads my legs with his hand already the nerves at the ends of my cunt like tiny paws stroke the inside of my flesh. I can't handle my horniness. We're, I think, moving into a city.</p>
                <lb />
                <p>My sex fucking is impersonal. My sexuality's impersonal. I'm rapidly losing my identity, the last part of my boredom. I caress the heavy thighs that turn outwards from my center, like a spider, sink into the rough clothes in the minaret, the thin muscles twirl around my calves to turn the feet outward like a golden dancer, leap through the hot air, the hairs of my cunt brush against wet the rough hair on your head, I can feel the liquid drip down the fat inner bulges of the legs near my cunt. Veins stick out from my wrists. I rub my flesh against my flesh, my skin against my skin, my skins against my skins, my torso begins to rise I'm always at the beginning of desire I can hardly tell when my orgasms rise and fall as if I'm almost unable to come and don't care, or am continuously slowly coming, I rub my back like a cat does against the rough wool, spread my heavy brown legs so that my buttocks open, the red flesh against the black wool, I pretend it's the hair of another person: there are mirrors making my hands into another person's hands, people all around me watch me. I watch the thin hands hold my arms, move slowly living bracelets around my arms on to the heavy flesh of my aching breasts.</p>
                <p>The liquid begins to rise, and my orgasm, I can no longer keep enticing myself (with the future), my orgasms, begin: the thighs spread apart at my ovaries, two central nerves parallel 5 inches apart from each other passing past my navel to my clit begin to burn, my cunt is my center my cunt is my center my cunt is my center, the hand reaches into my cunt my womb like a strange cock back and forth the thumb presses against my clit lightly then harder I imagine whips slashing into my ass just where the buttocks begin to spread I imagine tongues licking the round opening of my ass quickly lighting me until a dome begins to rise in my cunt, a growing sphere that wants to conquer me I touch myself faster</p>
                <p>I have to wait till people physically want me and I can be. But I'm no longer and I have my fantasy of my outcome, scared.</p>
                <lb />
                <p>[7/21]</p>
                <p>No one comes near me.</p>
                <lb />
                <p>[7/22]</p>
                <p>A tall man comes up to me and looks at my standing naked body. He turns my body around; with his thumb and third long finger opens my mouth sticks his tongue in my mouth, around my gums, to my inner throat. His hands touch the beginning of the outward curves of my upper buttocks the thick layer of fat developing over my ass and around my stomach. After stroking me, so I feel l ike a cat, his hand moves to the hair over my cunt, down to the lips of my cunt, softly; his eyes carefully note every expression on my face. I understand they are trying to sell me. How do I feel?</p>
                <p>The man leads me to a tent, motions for me to lie down. I expect him to kick me or hurt me. I'm slightly scared and also hot. I'm not supposed to look at him. He lays his left hand flat on my shoulder, looks at my eyes. I start to lift his robe. He stops me, lifts my heavy breasts with his right hand, draws two fingers around the purple nipples. As I look up at him, he turns his back to me, and leaves the tent. Again I'm alone.</p>
                <p>I no longer care about being safe, I don't care about the men because they'll make me feel safe; I know now they see me as an animal, I have only these wide arms, these breasts, eyelids shut over my eyes, and the heavy flesh of my legs shoving out of my cunt. If they sell me, they treat me badly it's because they think I don't matter. I matter when someone touches me, when I touch someone; the touch matters; so in this way I no longer exist, nor do the men. My body matters to me: the heart next to the lungs, the stomach pressing on the lungs, the lungs thoughtlessly drawing the air in and out, the oxygen out of the air. I'm no longer as scared as I was in the world because I no longer care. My only fear now is that no one will touch my body. I don't know yet how I'll get rid of this fear.</p>
                <p>Days pass by, moment like moment, the light becomes yellower and yellower, my fantasies more constant and thicker, like orange cloth on blue silk, on yellow sun; so that I'm always at a slow rolling edge. If my hand brushes across the flesh of my leg, the nerves begin to quiver, to stimulate other nerves further away from and closer to my clit, the desire rolling like soft dangerous animals an inch below my skin is everpresent, increases until I'm incapable of satisfying myself, I'm forced to wait; I'm forced to enter the worst of my childhood nightmares, the world of lobotomy: the person or people I depend on will stick their fingers into my brain, take away my brain, my driving will-power, I'll have nothing left, I won't be able to manage for myself. In the midst of this level anxiety, I'm constantly at rest. I wanted to control all environments and actions surrounding and of me; I was scared they would take control of me. Me. How strange now as I lay here waiting for another person, in the desert a man, I don't know who for what purpose, waiting so long that I can no longer perceive. I play with myself, smell the sweat at the pit of my arms, is it sweat, how can I tell what sweat is? I perceive yellow, yellow all around me, faint misty outlines of a body, everyone I know's crazy, I believe everyone's in her/his own way crazy, the edges shifting of the body look white I close my eyes I don't. I feel a limb thrust against the outjutti ng bone right above my clit, not a limb but a head, if I see an arm intersect my arm, I think my arm's been cut in half, the lips and beard rub against the fragile lace of my inner legs and the skins beneath the wettened hai rs. Li ps twi ne i nside me slowly ki ss the inner walls of my body until every inch of my body in shuddering my feeling becomes present to me. I can perceive everything. I'm a child; I sense through touch. Every inch over and over first with: the soft lips thick lips then the needle at the end of the tongue, my wetnesses begin to mingle, I open myself, I have no more will, so that anything can touch me, can enter me, I'm any thing/one more sensation at the bottom and top levels of my flesh, licking me I begin as I'm doing, orgasm, orgasm upon orgasm, open OPEN the nerves roll in cycles in preconceived courses through my body faster and faster in huger and huger rolls until my flesh di sintegrates and turns on itself. Like a devouring spider. I begin to clean myself and laugh.</p>
                <p>I lose my memory. Days after days pass blackness I am blackness. I'm alive.</p>
                <lb />
                <p>[7/25]</p>
                <p>We climb down the rocks and sliding sand Devil's Slide to the beach, tiny cove surrounded by boulders crash the huge waves against the rocks. B, V, and I take off our clothes. I lie in the hot sand. V starts drinking, people recognize her she tries to harden her nipple by rubbing it with wet finger. I lightly rub my tongue around the center of her nipple and press my lips against it as it grows. We separate, she looks around, waves to the people on the beach who are watching us. A stupid macho creep walks by. V scratches the back of my neck. We begin to kiss, gently, the slow liquids drawn by her lips to the insi de curves of my skin, I begin to shudder, I surprisingly yield to her, the kiss continues, at the edge of each inch of skin, feelings in my lips and skin of swirling lines nerves lines of nerves, everything opens, the kiss continues I draw my body over the blanket against hers some relief I get hotter. Now I'm drawn in, I need her, I can't escape orgasm, escape desiring V; my hand touches her heavy triangular breasts which scrape the skin above my stomach simultaneously I draw myself under her so that she can do whatever she wants with me and so I can hold her head like a cat's against me and protect her. How many people are watching? We look up; try to separate. V spreads her legs at people, laughs at them, passes her book around Female Orgasm. Three Spanish kids are staring entranced at us; one straight couple behind us and two bisexual couples in front of us are obviously turned on. I feel weird. I'm weird. I have to orgasm blank everyone out. I thrust my legs up huge pyramids her wet hairs press painfully against my clit this won't work. She looks at me. I have to come. We continue to kiss still lightly as if each inch of skin contains snakes she's a he this is a lie, "Can I wipe the sand out of your hairs; can I put my tongue in you?" I'm too far gone to hear anything she tongues me too hard I thrust her away she's hurt the situation's too weird I beg her to climax me. She tongues me a woman's touching me a woman's touching me as I rub as hard as I can my open outer lips against his hairs I can hardly feel his cock his hands begin to beat my ass I feel strange I don't feel anything how am I supposed to feel his hands begin to slap my buttocks harder and faster as I rise I begin to orgasm the pain finally surprises me and pleases me I completely relax her tongue directs each nerve within my lips and clit each center and line of nerves I'm completely dependent on her tongue I blank out every thing/one else I hold on to her as I begin to rise, easily, I can partially control the strong orgasm, increase its length</p>
                <p>I see two blonde women in front of us kissing each other</p>
                <p>My world is the four walls ceiling and floor in which I live hot they have shuttered the windows I do not think about them the other person who lives in the room with me a young girl whose flesh is now thick and soft like the legs of a spider is my life.</p>
                <p>I realize nothing else so that I will completely please whoever comes to me, whoever could be the only person who could give me pleasure. The oil runs from the pores of my skin, greases the skin of my beloved, the only person I now see, so that at night we slide over each other animals who live at the bottom of the deepest parts of the ocean.</p>
                <p>I don't know when I started living here at first the young girl stared at me and drew away from me. At first the young girl stares at me and draws away from me. I'm completely alone, I'm bored with touching my own flesh, I hide myself with heavy light brown blankets, and, like the strange creature I am, I sit and wait. I no longer care what happens so I no longer remember. I cast away my memory so I'm always at the edge of multiple orgasms. I sit and wait. As if I'm laying my heavy older hand on her child's thigh and doing nothing else. I stop approaching her because I'm continually at ecstasy.</p>
                <p>The third day she smiles at me, then runs away. I smile back, once. I won't let anyone have complete control of me my body ever again. I have to keep returning showing that I'm willing to touch enter her I'll never rape her. I live in this world: have to take pleasure opening myself where and when I can, most of the time I'm alone. She's younger and on the fifth night as I rub my flesh against the rough wool bored of touching myself by now so open to myself that I can't tell whether I'm touching myself or not, I feel two hands at the pit of my body a spider circling I throw my arm slowly into the dark circling around nothing, then the smooth skin lying over the sharp bones of a shoulder, I draw her to me until she's lying quietly in my arms. Inside me, I begin to shiver. I am her. I'm her child and her mother so that I'm completely safe I'm inviolable and there're no men around. My blackness cuts off all extra perceptions. Our mouths meet as my mouth has never been met in a thickness of feelings physical and mental that have a complexity that leads me to orgasm. I kiss her for hours and hours. At some point without knowing how I get here I have to complete my orgasm I mount her our cunts meet and fit surprisingly for me and easily and I ride her as love is our only way until we begin to peak and need more, and turn around</p>
                <p>I can do what I want. I can write more freely make my break to get rid of my damaged mind my lover silently aids me and watches out for them, the servants who bring us the rich boring food we eat, who licks the tips of my ears then quickly thrusts her tongue into their quivering centers into the center of my brain. Do I give a shit about her? I want to become as stupid and mindless as her and yield to the hard thighs of my next faceless lover. I want control over my environment. Like a fat spider I sit and wait. I float. Night after night we fold our limbs around each other and come and come we exist only for each other, then only for ourselves until there is no difference.</p>
                <lb />
                <p>I think a week has passed. I'm not sure of the time anymore, in this room where the light is always grey and I'm always hot. I love you. I realize my roommate's not me, another person; she's left me, already, in what remains of her memory, believes she's about to meet someone besides the servants who give us food. I'm tired of her. I like to look at her as I sit back in myself, her skin's now thick and fat, like the oil we continuously ingest, the hairs swirling dark in the middle of her flesh. I no longer care about her.</p>
                <p>I look at my body as if it were a web, solely a way of asking people to touch me. My body doesn't exist. I watch myself: I'm now heavy and even more beautiful: huge curves of thighs zooming into the valleys around my belly I begin to love myself as if I'm someone else no I realize my attractiveness coldly, I basically couldn't care how I look; I can see anything in a set of shifting frameworks. I'm interested solely in getting into someone else. I find the heavy flesh sensual, as if it were permanent. I'm not sure if I think of myself as a person.</p>
                <p>Enough mind remains in me to want this prison to disappear. The awareness of time (prison). I find myself more interesting than my companion, my former beloved; I'm no longer interested in such paltry pleasures in which I have to exert myself, I have to command and control an orgasm; the more I feel my self and my strength, the more I desire complete passivity. Blackness and minimal stuff I have to sense. My breasts are bright red.</p>
                <p>I'm sick of this society. "Earn a living" as if I'm not yet living; lobotomized and robotized from birth, they tell me I can't do anything I want to do in the subtlest and sneakiest ways possible. They want to erase all possible hints that I've been born. I have two centers: love and my desire to sleep. I want only the moving toward exaltation, opening toward and becoming other people; the exaltation, then nothing, until it starts again. People are unused to love because they don't go far enough. As far as possible, and farther, into their intuited desires. And complete love, apart by nature from "time," does not meet complete love where, given consent, anything can happen and there's no such thing as strength or weakness except as masks to be acted out. All forms of love are drag. How little do I have to do to survive except for passion, my desire to open and exist as I can only depend for existence on my surroundings, and if I have to do more, if I again have to prostitute by becoming straight, is life-fakery of living-that necessary to me? As if in that case, that deadness without love, there would be any me.</p>
                <p>I find my being dependent on love. Physical passion for others and thus myself. Fuck the shits who think otherwise.</p>
                <p>A calls me up do I want to meet him at The Stud midnight I've got to work I tell him V ate me in the middle of a public beach terrific are you upset about something? I love you</p>
                <lb />
                <p>[7/27]</p>
                <p>They wrap a thin white veil around my body, lead me out of the room, across a square of dirt, a courtyard, to a place where there are loud noises, animals and men. The cries of whipped beasts are my subterranean cries. I begin, in my bodymind my mind gone, to descend. Slabs of wood, a long heavy knife, and the shadows, the shadows help me undress. I can again see and hear; roofs, pipe and zither music, the evening prayers, the blackness of the evening air. I haven't gone as far as I thought I had: I'm still part of the daily death-goal world.</p>
                <p>Now there's only my large bed.</p>
                <p>A large heavy woman enters, hands me a sweet sticky mixture she motions me to eat. I like her; she smiles at me. My will-power is either totally reflexive or gone. Gone. I slowly eat the glue, sandy glue, which is too sweet for me to eat fast, her food, so that I'll do what she wants. No. I simply don't care: at this point it's easier not to make a fuss. I don't know what would help me and I'm too far gone to do more than act through my delirium. I'm completely involved in delirium.</p>
                <p>A hand inside my stomach begins to trace light circles on the inside of my skin the skins of my belly my limbs fall outward. Do they disappear? The spirals rise to a peak down below my breasts; I not only feel the various liquids in my body, but I can control the pulsing rhythms of their flow, I can move the muscles which form a cylinder around my clit tense and loose so that the walls and canals of nerves through my body vibrate under my command. Drugged, I can completely control myself.</p>
                <p>The drug aids my passivity and thus my strength. Living has become pure pleasure. I can hardly tell the difference between my coming and not coming: if I concentrate on the air that my lungs draw into themselves, I can feel the nerves around my breasts move and shift in complex patterns. I feel more clearly than I've ever felt now that all of me, my mind being every pore of my body, my whole body quivering to open from clit outward, is connected. I begin to play with the spirals within me, my flames, brush my fingers over my tender skin red from the suns, my sensations rise toward my coming, am I about to come? I play with my disbelief, feelingless, until I'm almost insane. I can feel nothing, and have no mind. I can do nothing for myself, nor do I know what I need done. From nowhere needles start rising in me and outside of me through my skin; I have no idea what comes from inside and what comes from outside; I descend into the mental and physical blackness. I see a frame: inside the frame, I'm suspended from a piece of wood by a string tied around my clit; the muscles upward from my clit tighten, and I cry out loudly. My eyelids are sewn to the skin below my eyes. I'm an opening in the earth, moving and crying through the rain. Somehow I awake enough to sense an animal standing over me.</p>
                <p>As the man's cock enters me, every muscle of me begins to shake, every nerve begins to burn and quiver. I'm both liquid and solid. I'm completely pleasure. At this moment. (1) I'm opening enough to contain all identities, things, change everything to energy, a volcano. (2) I'm constant energy and I can never be anything else. (3) I have no emotions; I sense textures of everything against textures; I'm completely part of and aware of the object world. I don't exist. My nerves so quiver, quiver burning, up and down the secret inflamed passages of my skin, the nerves tensing my muscles so that my blood zooms to the edge of my body, swells and inflames me, and unable to burst, I begin to come. These sensations-I do not know how to describe them-last for hours. I come again and again and again I now equal to everything and nothing am completely dependent on the pleasure this stranger is giving me.</p>
                <p>As I begin to swoon, my body covered with films of cooling sweat, I find myself alone again. Another man enters, sinks into me, leaves, and then another; I count six men in the blackness who wake me out of my semi-orgasmic sleep. I have no idea what this means.</p>
                <p>I'm going to finish this logically: I eat the sweet sandy mixture every night, stewed lamb and eggplants drenched in oils, thick honey pastries. I don't have to earn my living any more. I think of the mixture (the drug) and the sex, but mostly I feel the pleasure of the masochism which occurs only when I give my consent. If I consent, now, I can do anything.</p>
                <p>I find this harder and harder to write lest I be ripped off. I</p>
                <lb />
                <p>I'm speaking to you directly. Complete disorder exists. I spend most of my time, alone, in the monastery; I bend slowly to my knees, and I pray. I am very poor, but whenever I can I stay alone and pray. Think. Sometimes I go crazy I go pick up a man. "Do you want to fuck?" we go off fuck in every way possible until he can no longer stand the passion, I never see him again. At times I fuck women. I believe in explaining everything about my sexual life as fully as possible. If I have to, I use people to get where I want. I am most scared of dying: I think I will do anything to stay alive. I think I would rather die than submit become a robot let them lobotomize me. Each time I'm about to fuck suck tease a man I think I'll get what I want I vomit have to get out. I fuck only the men I'm madly in love with (for that time).</p>
                <p>I would have slept with my brother, after my mother died, but he chases me away. I now have to be alone I've been seeing too many people who I don't know well I have to consider everything within myself. If I feel I don't have any space left, I start going crazy. Soon everyone will go crazy if things don't change. My closest friend, Madame Lydia Paschkoff, tells me I need a lot of money. She is crazy and loving, the Virgin Mary of the spirits; I adore her. She tells me how to get money, but I can't do it. Some people think I'm mad. Some people forget me. I use psilocybin, mescaline, pure acid; occasionally hash as an aphrodisiac. I eat as little food as possible to save money.</p>
                <p>Of course, I disguise myself as a man. I'm 26 years old. I am exceedingly lazy. Lydia is furious with me because I sleep with men, and refuses to see me again. Now there is no one. The senses and the spirit are independent manifestations of each other; sexual ecstasies become mystic communion. Human communion. There's nothing else I want.</p>
            </div>
            <postscript>
                <p>All the above events are taken from Helen and Desire by A. Trocchi, The Wilder Shores of Love by L. Blanch, and myself.</p>
            </postscript>
        </body>
    </text>
    </TEI>